<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Legal News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/legal/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/legal/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Legal News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/legal/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Missouri Senate introduces bill to disqualify CBDCs as legal tender</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Missouri Senate introduced SB 194 on Dec. 1, proposing to ban central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) as legal tender within the state. The bill seeks to prohibit public entities from accepting or using CBDCs and modifies the definition of &#8220;money&#8221; under the Uniform Commercial Code to exclude these digital currencies. Sponsored by Senator Brattin, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/">Missouri Senate introduces bill to disqualify CBDCs as legal tender</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Missouri Senate <a href="https://trackbill.com/bill/missouri-senate-bill-194-creates-and-modifies-provisions-relating-to-legal-tender/2573895/">introduced</a> SB 194 on Dec. 1, proposing to ban central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) as legal tender within the state. The bill seeks to prohibit public entities from accepting or using CBDCs and modifies the definition of &#8220;money&#8221; under the Uniform Commercial Code to exclude these digital currencies.</p>
<p>Sponsored by Senator Brattin, SB 194 outlines several provisions affecting Missouri&#8217;s financial policies, including the requirement for the State Treasurer to hold gold and silver reserves equal to at least 1% of all state funds. Further, it also reduces tax liability for gold and silver as it</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;exempts from state income tax the portion of capital gain on the sale or exchange of gold and silver that are otherwise included in the taxpayer&#8217;s federal adjusted gross income.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In addition to addressing precious metals, the bill explicitly prohibits public entities from participating in any tests or pilot programs related to CBDCs conducted by the Federal Reserve or other federal agencies. This stance reflects growing concerns among some state legislators about the implications of CBDCs on financial privacy, monetary policy, and state sovereignty.</p>
<p>The modification of the Uniform Commercial Code&#8217;s definition of &#8220;money&#8221; to exclude CBDCs is a notable legal shift. This change could have significant implications for commercial transactions, contracts, and financial instruments within Missouri, effectively limiting the legal recognition and enforceability of CBDC-based transactions.</p>
<p>Earlier in 2024, Missouri&#8217;s legislature considered related <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-passes-crypto-mining-protection-law/">measures</a> regarding digital currencies. House Bill 2780, introduced in February, sought to prevent public entities from accepting or using CBDCs and passed the House in April with substantial support. The Senate also reviewed companion legislation, such as SB 1352, indicating a sustained legislative focus on regulating digital currencies at the state level.</p>
<p>Missouri&#8217;s legislative actions occur amid broader national and global discussions on the adoption and regulation of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-carolina-stands-firm-against-cbdcs-overrides-governors-veto/">CBDCs</a>. While some view CBDCs as an evolution in digital payment systems with the potential to enhance efficiency and financial inclusion, others express concerns over centralized control, privacy issues, and impacts on traditional banking systems.</p>
<p>By introducing SB 194, Missouri positions itself among states actively scrutinizing the role of government-issued digital currencies in their economies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/">Missouri Senate introduces bill to disqualify CBDCs as legal tender</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/missouri-cbdc.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/missouri-cbdc.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Celsius CEO Alex Mashinsky pleads guilty, agrees to 30 years in prison</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/former-celsius-ceo-alex-mashinsky-pleads-guilty-agrees-to-30-years-in-prison/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/former-celsius-ceo-alex-mashinsky-pleads-guilty-agrees-to-30-years-in-prison/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 21:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Alex Mashinsky, the former CEO of crypto lender Celsius, has pleaded guilty to two charges related to fraud and market manipulation, agreeing to a sentencing guideline of 30 years in prison.  Mashinsky was indicted in July 2023 on seven counts, including fraud, conspiracy, and manipulation of the market for Celsius&#8217; token, CEL. Under the terms [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/former-celsius-ceo-alex-mashinsky-pleads-guilty-agrees-to-30-years-in-prison/">Former Celsius CEO Alex Mashinsky pleads guilty, agrees to 30 years in prison</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/alex-mashinsky/">Alex Mashinsky</a>, the former CEO of crypto lender <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/celsius-network/">Celsius</a>, has pleaded guilty to two charges related to fraud and market manipulation, agreeing to a sentencing guideline of 30 years in prison. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mashinsky was indicted in July 2023 on seven counts, including fraud, conspiracy, and manipulation of the market for Celsius&#8217; token, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/celsius/">CEL</a>. Under the terms of the agreement, Mashinsky has waived his right to appeal any sentence below 360 months in prison.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">During a Dec. 3 hearing before US District Judge John Koeltl in Manhattan, Mashinsky acknowledged his role in misleading Celsius customers to invest in the platform and artificially inflating the value of CEL to benefit personally and bolster the company&#8217;s financial standing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Federal prosecutors accused Mashinsky of using deceptive tactics to lure investors to Celsius, promising high returns on deposits while secretly manipulating the value of its native token. Additionally, they estimate he profited $42 million from sales of his holdings in the asset.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mashinsky&#8217;s guilty plea follows that of Roni Cohen-Pavon, Celsius&#8217; former chief revenue officer, who pleaded guilty in September 2023 and agreed to cooperate with the ongoing investigation. Cohen-Pavon&#8217;s cooperation could provide further details about Celsius&#8217;s inner workings and leadership, potentially leading to more charges.</span></p>
<h2><strong>The collapse</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mashinsky&#8217;s case is part of a broader wave of regulatory and legal action in the wake of the 2022 collapse of several major crypto firms, most notably the implosion of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> exchange. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Celsius, once one of the leading crypto lenders, filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in July 2022 after a sharp decline in crypto asset prices prompted a rush of customer withdrawal requests. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The company struggled to meet its obligations, and many clients found themselves locked out of their funds for months as the firm sought to restructure. Celsius officially exited bankruptcy in January 2023 and shifted its business focus toward <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> mining.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mashinsky&#8217;s legal troubles follow several other high-profile figures accused of criminal wrongdoing. In November 2023, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-bankman-fried/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a>, the founder of FTX, was convicted of stealing roughly $8 billion from the exchange&#8217;s customers and sentenced to 25 years in prison in March 2024.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/former-celsius-ceo-alex-mashinsky-pleads-guilty-agrees-to-30-years-in-prison/">Former Celsius CEO Alex Mashinsky pleads guilty, agrees to 30 years in prison</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/former-celsius-ceo-alex-mashinsky-pleads-guilty-agrees-to-30-years-in-prison/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celsius-creditors.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celsius-creditors.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean politicians agree to implement 2-year moratorium on crypto taxation</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-politicians-agree-to-implement-2-year-moratorium-on-crypto-taxation/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-politicians-agree-to-implement-2-year-moratorium-on-crypto-taxation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>South Korea&#8217;s Democratic Party agreed to delay the implementation of crypto taxation laws, signaling a temporary truce in the heated debate over digital asset regulation in the country, the Korean Herald reported on Dec. 2. Democratic Party floor leader Rep. Park Chan-dae announced the agreement to postpone the taxation of crypto profits by two years. Park [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-politicians-agree-to-implement-2-year-moratorium-on-crypto-taxation/">South Korean politicians agree to implement 2-year moratorium on crypto taxation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea&#8217;s Democratic Party agreed to delay the implementation of crypto taxation laws, signaling a temporary truce in the heated debate over digital asset regulation in the country, the Korean Herald reported on Dec. 2.</p>
<p>Democratic Party floor leader Rep. Park Chan-dae announced the agreement to postpone the taxation of crypto profits by two years. Park said during a press conference:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We have decided to agree to a two-year moratorium on the implementation of the cryptocurrency taxation proposed by the government and ruling party.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>As of 2024, approximately 20% of South Korea&#8217;s population — nearly 10 million people — engaged in crypto trading or investment. However, despite this high level of adoption, the country has adopted a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptoquant-ceo-compares-south-koreas-hostile-bitcoin-stance-to-gary-gensler-situation/">cautious stance</a> toward the industry.</p>
<p>The nation&#8217;s average daily crypto trading volume is estimated at 11.3 trillion won ($8.4 billion), often exceeding that of its stock exchange, the Korea Composite Stock Price Index (KOSPI).</p>
<h2>Political agreement</h2>
<p>The law imposes a tax on digital asset income and was initially set to take effect in January. The delay aligns closely with a government proposal, though the ruling People Power Party sought a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-moves-to-delay-crypto-tax-until-2028-amid-market-concerns/">three-year moratorium</a>.</p>
<p>Park&#8217;s opposition party has agreed to a short two-year delay but vowed to block new tax cuts for inheritances and gifts, which it claims disproportionately benefit the wealthy.</p>
<p>The agreement marks a shift in the Democratic Party&#8217;s position. The party previously advocated raising the threshold for crypto-related tax deductions from 2.5 million won ($1,790) to 50 million won ($35,800) rather than delaying the law altogether.</p>
<p>Despite the concession on crypto taxation, Park emphasized his party&#8217;s opposition to proposed reforms to inheritance and gift taxes. The government and ruling party plan to lower the top inheritance tax rate from 50% to 40% and dramatically increase the deduction threshold for assets passed from parents to children.</p>
<h2>Debate around fiscal policy</h2>
<p>The tax debates come amid broader discussions on South Korea&#8217;s fiscal policies.</p>
<p>Last month, Democratic Party leader Rep. Lee Jae-Myung reversed course on a proposed tax on financial investment income, opting instead to support its repeal. The move was aimed at revitalizing the country&#8217;s lagging stock market and appeasing millions of investors.</p>
<p>Lee said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I could not ignore the voices of 15 million financial stock investors who might be affected by structural vulnerability.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The crypto tax delay provides temporary relief to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/financial-watchdog-clarifies-role-amid-south-koreas-new-crypto-compliance-crackdown/">digital asset traders</a> but raises questions about the government&#8217;s ability to balance competing fiscal priorities.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-politicians-agree-to-implement-2-year-moratorium-on-crypto-taxation/">South Korean politicians agree to implement 2-year moratorium on crypto taxation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-politicians-agree-to-implement-2-year-moratorium-on-crypto-taxation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How the Tornado Cash ruling is a victory for crypto</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/how-the-tornado-cash-ruling-is-a-victory-for-crypto/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/how-the-tornado-cash-ruling-is-a-victory-for-crypto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Matthew Niemerg]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455242</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest article from Matthew Niemerg, co-founder of Aleph Zero. The Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals handed down a landmark ruling yesterday that could fundamentally reshape how cryptocurrency protocols are regulated. In Van Loon v. Department of Treasury, the court found that the Treasury Department&#8217;s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) exceeded [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/how-the-tornado-cash-ruling-is-a-victory-for-crypto/">How the Tornado Cash ruling is a victory for crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest article from Matthew Niemerg, co-founder of Aleph Zero.<br />
</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Fifth Circuit Court of Appeals handed down a landmark ruling yesterday that could fundamentally reshape how cryptocurrency protocols are regulated. In </span><strong><a href="https://assets.bwbx.io/documents/users/iqjWHBFdfxIU/rWi4YTmtAT5I/v0">Van Loon v. Department of Treasury</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the court found that the Treasury Department&#8217;s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) exceeded its authority when it sanctioned <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tornado-cash/">Tornado Cash&#8217;</a>s immutable smart contracts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ruling hinges on a deceptively simple question: can computer code that cannot be modified or controlled be considered &#8220;property&#8221;? The appellate court&#8217;s answer was an emphatic no.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tornado Cash is a cryptocurrency anonymizing service that helps preserve privacy by pooling users&#8217; digital assets together, making transactions harder to trace. In 2022, OFAC </span><strong><a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0916">sanctioned</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> it after North Korean hackers allegedly used it to launder over $455 million in stolen funds. But the court found that since Tornado Cash&#8217;s core protocols are &#8220;immutable&#8221; &#8211; meaning they cannot be changed or controlled by anyone &#8211; they don&#8217;t qualify as property that can be sanctioned under existing law.</span></p>
<h2><b>A Watershed Moment for Crypto</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Because these immutable smart contracts are unchangeable and unremovable, they remain available for anyone to use,&#8221; wrote Judge Don Willett, noting that even under sanctions, &#8220;the targeted North Korean wrongdoers are not actually blocked from retrieving their assets.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This represents a watershed moment for the cryptocurrency industry. For the first time, a federal appeals court has acknowledged that certain decentralized protocols operate entirely as something completely different from traditional property or businesses. Since no one &#8220;owns&#8221; the protocols underlying email or the web, these autonomous smart contracts exist independent of any controlling entity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The implications are significant. The ruling effectively creates a safe harbor for truly decentralized protocols that cannot be modified or controlled. While OFAC can still sanction individuals and companies, it cannot sanction the underlying code itself &#8211; at least under current law.</span></p>
<h2><b>Balancing Privacy and Security</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the court explicitly left the door open for Congress to update the 1977 International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA) to address modern technologies. &#8220;Perhaps Congress will update IEEPA, enacted during the Carter Administration, to target modern technologies like crypto-mixing software,&#8221; the ruling noted. &#8220;Until then, we hold that Tornado Cash&#8217;s immutable smart contracts&#8230;cannot be blocked under IEEPA.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This highlights the broader challenge of regulating privacy-preserving technologies that can be used for both legitimate and illegitimate purposes. As the court record shows, Tornado Cash was used by individuals seeking to protect their privacy when donating to Ukrainian war efforts and avoid harassment. But it was also exploited by bad actors for money laundering.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The crypto industry still has work to do in preventing illicit use while preserving privacy rights. Some proposed approaches include allowing users to voluntarily prove the legitimacy of their funds, or implementing &#8220;anonymity revoking&#8221; systems that could unmask users only under specific circumstances with proper oversight.</span></p>
<h2><b>The Path Forward</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Judge Willett acknowledged the government&#8217;s concerns about illicit finance as &#8220;undeniably legitimate.&#8221; But he emphasized that courts must apply the law as written, not &#8220;tinker with it.&#8221; The ruling concludes: </span></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;Mending a statute&#8217;s blind spots or smoothing its disruptive effects falls outside our lane.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This balanced approach &#8211; recognizing both the importance of preventing criminal activity and the need to protect privacy-enhancing innovation &#8211; points the way forward. Rather than trying to force new technologies into old regulatory frameworks, legislators need to craft updated laws that understand the unique nature of decentralized systems while addressing legitimate security concerns.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For now though, this ruling represents a victory for technological innovation and a recognition that not everything in the digital age fits neatly into traditional legal categories of property and ownership. The challenge ahead is building a regulatory framework as sophisticated as the technology it aims to govern.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/how-the-tornado-cash-ruling-is-a-victory-for-crypto/">How the Tornado Cash ruling is a victory for crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/how-the-tornado-cash-ruling-is-a-victory-for-crypto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/tornado-cash-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/tornado-cash-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Canadian media giants sue OpenAI over ChatGPT&#8217;s alleged copyright violations</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/canadian-media-giants-sue-openai-over-chatgpts-alleged-copyright-violations/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/canadian-media-giants-sue-openai-over-chatgpts-alleged-copyright-violations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 01:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A coalition of Canadian media organizations has launched a lawsuit against OpenAI, claiming the company&#8217;s ChatGPT product infringed copyrights by utilizing their journalism without authorization, according to a Nov. 29 court filing. The plaintiffs include prominent outlets such as CBC/Radio-Canada, The Toronto Star, and The Globe and Mail. They are seeking damages and an injunction [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/canadian-media-giants-sue-openai-over-chatgpts-alleged-copyright-violations/">Canadian media giants sue OpenAI over ChatGPT&#8217;s alleged copyright violations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A coalition of Canadian media organizations has launched a lawsuit against <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/openai/">OpenAI</a>, claiming the company&#8217;s ChatGPT product i<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/authors-guild-claims-openai-used-pirated-ebooks-to-train-chatgpt-on-copyrighted-material/">nfringed copyrights</a> by utilizing their journalism without authorization, according to a Nov. 29 court <a href="https://litigate.com/assets/uploads/Canadian-News-Media-Companies-v-OpenAI.pdf">filing</a>.</p>
<p>The plaintiffs include prominent outlets such as CBC/Radio-Canada, The Toronto Star, and The Globe and Mail. They are seeking damages and an injunction to prevent OpenAI from continuing to use their content.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, filed in the Ontario Superior Court of Justice, accuses OpenAI of extracting and profiting from Canadian news content without permission.</p>
<p>The group alleged:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;OpenAI is capitalizing on the use of our content, disregarding copyright laws and online terms of use.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>OpenAI defended its practices, stating that its AI models are trained on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/openai-announces-time-partnership-amid-new-lawsuit-over-copyright-violations/">publicly available information</a> under the principles of fair use and related copyright laws. The company also highlighted its partnerships with news organizations and its opt-out options for publishers.</p>
<p>An OpenAI spokesperson told reporters:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;ChatGPT is used by millions worldwide to enhance creativity and solve complex problems. We collaborate with publishers to ensure attribution and offer tools for them to control how their content is engaged with on our platform.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>However, the plaintiffs argue that OpenAI&#8217;s activities undermine the value of journalism by repurposing it for commercial gain. They also challenged OpenAI&#8217;s reliance on fair use, emphasizing that their journalism is intended to serve the public interest and should not be exploited for profit.</p>
<p>This case joins a growing number of lawsuits against OpenAI and other AI companies over the use of copyrighted materials for model training. Earlier this year, OpenAI acknowledged to a UK committee that training its current AI systems without incorporating copyrighted materials would not be feasible.</p>
<p>The company has also faced scrutiny for missteps, including a recent admission that engineers inadvertently erased critical evidence related to AI training data. The outcome of this case could have significant implications for copyright law in the AI era as courts grapple with the balance between innovation and intellectual property rights.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/canadian-media-giants-sue-openai-over-chatgpts-alleged-copyright-violations/">Canadian media giants sue OpenAI over ChatGPT&#8217;s alleged copyright violations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/canadian-media-giants-sue-openai-over-chatgpts-alleged-copyright-violations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/openai-revenue-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/openai-revenue-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-Binance executive alleges retaliatory firing over bribery whistleblowing</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A former senior executive at Binance has accused the company of retaliatory dismissal after she raised concerns about an alleged bribery scheme involving a colleague, Bloomberg News reported on Nov. 28. Amrita Srivastava, a London-based executive who worked remotely on Binance&#8217;s Link platform, testified that she was dismissed after reporting that a colleague solicited a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/">Ex-Binance executive alleges retaliatory firing over bribery whistleblowing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A former senior executive at <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> has accused the company of retaliatory dismissal after she raised concerns about an alleged bribery scheme involving a colleague, Bloomberg News </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-28/ex-binance-executive-brings-whistleblower-claim-alleging-bribery">reported</a> on Nov. 28.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amrita Srivastava, a London-based executive who worked remotely on Binance&#8217;s Link platform, testified that she was dismissed after reporting that a colleague solicited a bribe from a customer in exchange for expedited integration services. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The alleged payments were disguised as &#8220;consultative services&#8221; and executed while the colleague purportedly distanced himself from his formal ties to Binance. The colleague in question has since left the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Srivastava joined Binance in April 2022 after a role at Mastercard, where she managed fintech coverage for Western Europe. She told the tribunal that she initially believed in the company&#8217;s commitment to improving compliance, especially given the global regulatory pressure it faced. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, she described a &#8220;chaotic&#8221; work culture and said her unit faced mounting pressure to close deals, particularly after losing significant revenue streams tied to a client with alleged links to Iran.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Binance response</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former executive claims she reported the bribery incident to her managers in April 2023 but was terminated a month later for what Binance claims was &#8220;poor performance.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a statement, Binance&#8217;s lawyer maintained that the decision to end Srivastava&#8217;s employment predated her whistleblowing, adding that the alleged bribery was already known and under internal review.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, Srivastava asserts that her dismissal was linked directly to her decision to report the alleged misconduct. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under UK law, whistleblowing awards in employment tribunals are uncapped, potentially exposing Binance to significant financial liabilities if the court upholds Srivastava&#8217;s claims. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She has alleged that her experience at Binance caused severe damage to her career and reputation, which she anticipates will take years to repair. Srivastava concluded:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;My experience at Binance has been personally damaging to my career, an impact I will continue to have to undo over the next few years.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/">Ex-Binance executive alleges retaliatory firing over bribery whistleblowing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/binance-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/binance-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia formalizes taxation framework for crypto, mining</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/russia-formalizes-taxation-framework-for-crypto-mining/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/russia-formalizes-taxation-framework-for-crypto-mining/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 18:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Russia&#8217;s Federation Council has approved sweeping amendments to the nation&#8217;s Tax Code, formalizing the taxation framework for digital currencies like Bitcoin (BTC). The legislation, adopted on Nov. 27, represents a critical step toward regulating the rapidly growing crypto sector while ensuring compliance with tax laws. Comprehensive tax laws The new law, titled &#8220;On Amendments to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/russia-formalizes-taxation-framework-for-crypto-mining/">Russia formalizes taxation framework for crypto, mining</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Russia&#8217;s Federation Council has approved sweeping <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/russia-approves-tax-on-crypto-mining-and-transactions/">amendments</a> to the nation&#8217;s Tax Code, formalizing the taxation framework for digital currencies like Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>).</p>
<p>The legislation, adopted on Nov. 27, represents a critical step toward regulating the rapidly growing crypto sector while ensuring compliance with tax laws.</p>
<h2>Comprehensive tax laws</h2>
<p>The new law, titled &#8220;On Amendments to Parts One and Two of the Tax Code of the Russian Federation and Certain Legislative Acts of the Russian Federation,&#8221; was introduced by Alexander Shenderiuk-Zhidkov, Deputy Chairman of the Federation Council&#8217;s Committee on Budget and Financial Markets.</p>
<p>The amendments define digital currency as property for tax purposes, providing legal clarity that aligns with Russia&#8217;s broader regulatory goals. Under the updated Tax Code, income derived from crypto transactions will be taxed under a progressive personal income tax system.</p>
<p>Earnings up to a specified threshold will incur a tax rate of 13%, while higher income brackets will face a 15% rate. This structure aims to balance government revenue generation with fairness for individuals and businesses involved in digital asset trading.</p>
<p>Additionally, mining operators must report detailed information about their activities to local tax authorities, a move that aims to enhance transparency and address potential regulatory loopholes in the mining sector.</p>
<p>This includes disclosures about mining activities conducted on behalf of clients and addressing long-standing concerns about regulatory gaps and potential tax evasion in the sector.</p>
<h2>Exemptions for mining</h2>
<p>The legislation exempts certain crypto activities from value-added tax (VAT), including transactions related to the mining and sale of digital currencies, distinguishing them from other taxable economic activities. This provision is seen as a significant incentive for miners and crypto enterprises operating in Russia.</p>
<p>The legislative effort comes as Russia ramps up its oversight of digital currencies amid global debates about their regulation. The government has also introduced measures to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/russia-halts-crypto-mining-in-energy-strapped-territories/">restrict crypto mining</a> in energy-deficient regions, ensuring that mining activities do not strain the country&#8217;s power grid.</p>
<p>Analysts estimate that the new tax framework could generate up to 200 billion rubles (approximately $2 billion) annually in state revenue, bolstering public finances while supporting the digital economy.</p>
<p>Critics of the legislation have raised concerns about potential enforcement challenges, particularly in monitoring decentralized financial activities. However, proponents argue that the law strikes a necessary balance between fostering innovation and maintaining fiscal responsibility.</p>
<p>The amendments are part of a broader strategy to integrate digital currencies into Russia&#8217;s financial system while addressing risks associated with unregulated markets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/russia-formalizes-taxation-framework-for-crypto-mining/">Russia formalizes taxation framework for crypto, mining</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/russia-formalizes-taxation-framework-for-crypto-mining/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/russia-crypto-tax-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/russia-crypto-tax-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tornado Cash token surges to 2-year high after US court rules Treasury sanctions unlawful</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-token-surges-to-2-year-high-after-us-court-rules-treasury-sanctions-unlawful/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-token-surges-to-2-year-high-after-us-court-rules-treasury-sanctions-unlawful/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 11:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TORN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornado cash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us treasury]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The price of Tornado Cash&#8217;s TORN token skyrocketed to a two-year high after a US federal appeals court ruled that the US Treasury Department&#8217;s sanctions on the platform were unlawful. Tornado Cash is an on-chain privacy tool that uses immutable smart contracts to enable anonymous crypto transactions. The platform was sanctioned in 2022 by the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-token-surges-to-2-year-high-after-us-court-rules-treasury-sanctions-unlawful/">Tornado Cash token surges to 2-year high after US court rules Treasury sanctions unlawful</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The price of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tornado-cash/">Tornado Cash&#8217;s TORN</a> token skyrocketed to a two-year high after a US federal appeals court ruled that the US Treasury Department&#8217;s sanctions on the platform were unlawful.</p>
<p>Tornado Cash is an on-chain privacy tool that uses immutable smart contracts to enable anonymous crypto transactions.</p>
<p>The platform was sanctioned in 2022 by the US Treasury&#8217;s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC). It alleged that it aided the laundering of over $7 billion in crypto, including stolen funds, by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hackers-like-lazarus-continue-to-use-tornado-cash-despite-us-sanctions/">hacking groups linked with North Korea.</a></p>
<h2>The judgement</h2>
<p>On Nov. 26, the US Court of Appeals determined that the Treasury exceeded its authority by sanctioning Tornado Cash&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-judge-rules-software-code-does-not-qualify-as-free-speech-in-tornado-cash-case/">immutable smart contracts</a>. As open-source software, these contracts do not belong to any person or foreign entity and, therefore, cannot be subjected to sanctions.</p>
<p>The court highlighted a critical 2020 event called the &#8220;trusted setup ceremony,&#8221; where over 1,000 participants contributed cryptographic data to finalize Tornado Cash&#8217;s parameters. This process rendered the smart contracts immutable, eliminating any form of updates or administrative control. Governance was later handed to the Tornado Cash community through the TORN token.</p>
<p>The judges ruled that these contracts operate autonomously and do not meet the legal definition of property or services under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA). They also pointed out that the smart contracts have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wazirx-hacker-launders-10-million-through-tornado-cash/">continued to operate</a> despite the OFAC&#8217;s sanction.</p>
<p>Consequently, OFAC cannot sanction them unless Congress updates the law to account for technologies like crypto-mixing tools.</p>
<p>The Judges <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/c5bd0wqjc7v0/70EasapqSxH1kLInf3IQrd/1a1ce21cdc6bc903921f45018cce3821/Tornado_Cash.pdf">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<span class="s5">We hold that Tornado Cash’s immutable smart contracts (the lines of privacy-enabling software code) are not the &#8216;property&#8217; of a foreign national or entity, meaning they cannot be blocked under IEEPA, and OFAC overstepped its congressionally defined authority.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Following the ruling, data from <em>CryptoSlate</em> shows that TORN surged to a two-year high of $40 before falling back to around $18, marking a 400% increase within 24 hours. Despite this rally, the token remains 96% below its all-time high of $436 recorded in February 2021.</p>
<h2>Crypto community celebrates</h2>
<p>The decision was widely celebrated within the crypto community., with industry leaders calling it a landmark victory for decentralized technologies and privacy rights.</p>
<p>Coinbase&#8217;s Chief Legal Officer, Paul Grewal, emphasized that this ruling protects open-source software from unjust sanctions. He noted that while addressing illicit activities is essential, targeting decentralized protocols with blanket restrictions oversteps legal boundaries.</p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/iampaulgrewal/status/1861549058797772874">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;No one wants criminals to use crypto protocols, but blocking open source technology entirely because a small portion of users are bad actors is not what Congress authorized. These sanctions stretched Treasury’s authority beyond recognition, and the Fifth Circuit agreed.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Bill Hughes, Consensys&#8217; senior counsel and director of global regulatory matters, explained that the judgment does not mean that the rest of Tornado Cash is also out of bounds for Treasury/OFAC. However, the issue was about smart contracts with no admin key.</p>
<p>Hughes <a href="https://x.com/BillHughesDC/status/1861545321450336342">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[This is] a good win. One which the Supreme Court would be unlikely to reverse. Another case where <span class="r-36ujnk">Loper Bright</span> helped because the court wasn&#8217;t required to defer to a permissible reading by the agency.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-token-surges-to-2-year-high-after-us-court-rules-treasury-sanctions-unlawful/">Tornado Cash token surges to 2-year high after US court rules Treasury sanctions unlawful</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-token-surges-to-2-year-high-after-us-court-rules-treasury-sanctions-unlawful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/tornado-cash.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/tornado-cash.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FCA to wait till 2026 to launch official crypto policy with 12% of UK owning digital assets</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/fca-to-wait-till-2016-to-launch-official-crypto-policy-with-12-of-uk-owning-digital-assets/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/fca-to-wait-till-2016-to-launch-official-crypto-policy-with-12-of-uk-owning-digital-assets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 13:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454713</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crypto ownership in the UK has increased to 12% of adults, up from 10%, according to the Financial Conduct Authority&#8217;s (FCA) latest research published on Nov. 26. Awareness of cryptocurrencies also grew, reaching 93% of the adult population. The FCA&#8217;s study revealed that the average value of crypto holdings per person rose from £1,595 to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fca-to-wait-till-2016-to-launch-official-crypto-policy-with-12-of-uk-owning-digital-assets/">FCA to wait till 2026 to launch official crypto policy with 12% of UK owning digital assets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Crypto ownership in the UK has <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/publications/research/research-note-cryptoassets-consumer-research-2024">increased</a> to 12% of adults, up from 10%, according to the Financial Conduct Authority&#8217;s (FCA) latest research published on Nov. 26. Awareness of cryptocurrencies also grew, reaching 93% of the adult population.</p>
<p class="p1">The FCA&#8217;s study <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/news/press-releases/fca-finds-crypto-ownership-continues-rise-it-delivers-plans-regulate-crypto">revealed</a> that the average value of crypto holdings per person rose from £1,595 to £1,842. Family and friends emerged as the most common source of information for those who have never purchased digital assets, while only one in ten buyers admitted to doing no research before investing.</p>
<p class="p1">Approximately a third of respondents believed they could file a complaint with the FCA in case of issues, seeking recourse or financial protection. However, digital assets remain largely unregulated in the UK and are considered high-risk; investors are cautioned that they could lose all their money without any regulatory safeguards.</p>
<h2>FCA crypto approach hampering progress</h2>
<p class="p1">The FCA has begun outlining its approach to regulating digital assets, publishing an indicative roadmap of key dates for the development and introduction of the UK&#8217;s crypto regulatory regime. The roadmap details a series of focused consultations aimed at fostering transparency and engagement in policy development.</p>
<p>Arun Srivastava, fintech and regulation partner at Paul Hastings, told <em>CryptoSlate</em></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The UK was in danger of becoming an outlier, with the EU&#8217;s MiCA regulation coming into full force at the end of this year and the change in the US Administration in the US heralding a fresh and crypto-friendly approach in the US.</p>
<p>The new rules will materially change the current regulatory framework in the UK, which operates under anti-money laundering legislation focused on financial crime.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p class="p1">The research also indicated shifts in consumer behavior. More individuals are considering crypto as part of a broader investment portfolio, with influence from friends and family cited as a primary reason for purchase by 20% of participants. The use of long-term savings to buy crypto increased from 19% in 2022 to 26% in 2024, while purchasing with credit cards or overdrafts rose from 6% to 14% over the same period.</p>
<p class="p1">The FCA&#8217;s analysis suggests that recent events have affected consumer demand for digital assets, including the crypto market crash in 2022, the cost-of-living crisis, criminal charges against CEOs of major exchanges, and rising crypto valuations since the end of 2023.</p>
<p class="p1">Notably, 26% of non-crypto users indicated they would be more likely to invest if the market and activities were regulated. The FCA acknowledges that regulation can influence consumer behavior and is considering how to mitigate risks associated with digital assets through its policy work.</p>
<h2>FCA crypto roadmap by 2026</h2>
<p class="p1">Per the FCA&#8217;s roadmap, the planned regulatory framework for digital assets includes multiple phases spanning from 2023 to 2026. Key milestones involve implementing financial promotion rules, regulating stablecoin issuance and custody, introducing prudential standards, and establishing comprehensive rules for trading platforms, intermediation, lending, and staking.</p>
<p class="p1">Matthew Long, director of payments and digital assets at the FCA, stated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">“Our research results highlight the need for clear regulation that supports a safe, competitive, and sustainable crypto sector in the UK. We want to develop a sector that embraces innovation and is underpinned by market integrity and consumer trust.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<figure id="attachment_454723" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454723" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-454723 size-large" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-26-at-12.59.34-1024x718.png" alt="FCA crypto roadmap (Source: FCA)" width="1024" height="718" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-26-at-12.59.34-1024x718.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-26-at-12.59.34-300x210.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-26-at-12.59.34-768x538.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-26-at-12.59.34-1536x1077.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-26-at-12.59.34-2048x1436.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454723" class="wp-caption-text">FCA crypto roadmap (Source: FCA)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">Following legislative changes, the FCA has been responsible for regulating digital asset promotions since October 2023. In the first year under this regime, the FCA has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/uk-fca-defends-tough-crypto-rules-to-prevent-money-laundering-and-maintain-market-integrity/">issued</a> 1,702 alerts, taken down over 900 scam crypto websites, and removed more than 50 apps to combat illegal promotions targeting UK consumers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fca-to-wait-till-2016-to-launch-official-crypto-policy-with-12-of-uk-owning-digital-assets/">FCA to wait till 2026 to launch official crypto policy with 12% of UK owning digital assets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/fca-to-wait-till-2016-to-launch-official-crypto-policy-with-12-of-uk-owning-digital-assets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/fca-uk-bitcoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/fca-uk-bitcoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US court strikes down controversial SEC &#8216;dealer&#8217; rule</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/us-court-strikes-down-controversial-sec-dealer-rule/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/us-court-strikes-down-controversial-sec-dealer-rule/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A federal court has struck down the Securities and Exchange Commission&#8217;s (SEC) controversial dealer rule, delivering a major setback to the agency&#8217;s regulatory efforts in the crypto sector. The US District Court for the Northern District of Texas ruled on Nov. 21 that the SEC exceeded its statutory authority, invalidating the rule as a violation [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-court-strikes-down-controversial-sec-dealer-rule/">US court strikes down controversial SEC &#8216;dealer&#8217; rule</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A federal court has struck down the Securities and Exchange Commission&#8217;s (SEC) <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-groups-sue-sec-claiming-overreach-in-new-dealer-rule-definition/">controversial dealer rule</a>, delivering a major setback to the agency&#8217;s regulatory efforts in the crypto sector.</p>
<p>The US District Court for the Northern District of Texas ruled on Nov. 21 that the SEC exceeded its statutory authority, invalidating the rule as a violation of the Exchange Act.</p>
<p>The decision came after the Blockchain Association and the Crypto Freedom Alliance of Texas (CFAT) challenged the rule in court, arguing it unlawfully expanded the SEC&#8217;s jurisdiction and created uncertainty for digital asset innovators. The court agreed, describing the SEC&#8217;s definition of &#8220;dealer&#8221; as &#8220;untethered from the text, history, and structure&#8221; of the law.</p>
<p>Blockchain Association CEO Kristen Smith <a href="https://t.co/w2j8GmQf4C">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This ruling is a victory for the entire digital asset industry. The dealer rule was an attempt to unlawfully expand the SEC&#8217;s authority and stifle crypto innovation. Today&#8217;s decision curtails that overreach and safeguards the future of our industry.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The SEC&#8217;s dealer rule, introduced earlier this year, sought to broaden the regulatory scope for market participants dealing in securities. Critics argued the rule would impose onerous compliance burdens on blockchain developers and small businesses, stifling innovation in the rapidly growing sector.</p>
<p>CFAT, a Texas-based trade group, joined the legal battle, calling the SEC&#8217;s actions a clear case of regulatory overreach.</p>
<p>Marisa Coppel, head of legal at the Blockchain Association, said:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Litigation is never our first choice, but it is sometimes necessary to defend the industry from overzealous regulation. The court&#8217;s decision underscores the importance of adhering to the boundaries of statutory authority.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The lawsuit, filed in April, marked a significant pushback against what many in the digital asset community see as the SEC&#8217;s aggressive regulatory agenda. Industry leaders have repeatedly criticized the agency&#8217;s approach, accusing it of using enforcement actions and ambiguous rules to curtail innovation.</p>
<p>The court&#8217;s ruling is expected to have far-reaching implications for digital asset regulation, signaling that judicial scrutiny of the SEC&#8217;s policies may intensify. Advocates hope the decision will prompt lawmakers and regulators to pursue clearer and more balanced policies for the sector.</p>
<p>The Blockchain Association represents a coalition of crypto companies, investors, and projects advocating for innovation-friendly regulations. CFAT promotes digital asset policy in Texas, emphasizing the economic and technological benefits of blockchain development.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-court-strikes-down-controversial-sec-dealer-rule/">US court strikes down controversial SEC &#8216;dealer&#8217; rule</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/us-court-strikes-down-controversial-sec-dealer-rule/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/us-courtroom.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/us-courtroom.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
