<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Crime News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/crime/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crime/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:46:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Crime News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crime/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Australia intensifies crypto ATM oversight to curb money laundering risks</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto ATMs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Transaction Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC) has intensified efforts to enforce Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing (AML/CTF) regulations among crypto ATM providers. On Dec. 6, the watchdog said that crypto ATMs are increasingly used for money laundering and other illicit activities. Despite the country having around 400 registered crypto exchanges, only a small portion [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/">Australia intensifies crypto ATM oversight to curb money laundering risks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Transaction Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC) has intensified efforts to enforce Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing (AML/CTF) regulations among crypto ATM providers.</p>
<p>On Dec. 6, the watchdog said that crypto ATMs are increasingly used for money laundering and other illicit activities. Despite the country having around 400 registered crypto exchanges, only a small portion operate crypto ATMs. This gap leaves a significant share of Australia&#8217;s 1,200 crypto ATMs potentially non-compliant.</p>
<p>AUSTRAC CEO Brendan Thomas highlighted the risks posed by crypto ATMs, emphasizing their appeal to criminals due to their accessibility and capability for near-instant, irreversible transactions.</p>
<p>He stated:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;We’re seeing too many Australians falling victim to scams carried out through cryptocurrency, and we’ve heard of some victims losing their life savings, which is just heart breaking. As the use of cryptocurrency increases, so too will criminal exploitation, which is why this taskforce will work to eliminate non-compliant high risk operations.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>AUSTRAC has launched a task force to ensure compliance among digital currency exchanges (DCEs) operating <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/california-to-limit-bitcoin-atm-transactions-to-1000-per-day-to-combat-fraud/">crypto ATMs</a> in order to tackle this issue. The initiative focuses on enforcing minimum compliance standards and implementing stronger safeguards to detect and prevent fraud and scams.</p>
<p>Crypto ATM operators in Australia are required to adhere to strict AML/CTF obligations. These include registering with AUSTRAC, conducting Know Your Customer (KYC) checks, monitoring transactions, and reporting cash transactions exceeding AUD 10,000 (approximately USD 6,430). Non-compliance risks significant financial penalties and swift action from the regulator.</p>
<p>Thomas warned:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Cryptocurrency ATM providers need to ensure they are complying with their money laundering obligations and are reducing the risks of crime. If they’re ignoring those obligations they risk being subject to significant financial penalties and AUSTRAC won’t hesitate in taking action.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The move aligns with a broader global trend of increased scrutiny <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">of crypto ATMs. German authorities recently <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/germany-seizes-28-million-in-raid-on-unlicensed-crypto-atms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seized 13 crypto ATMs</a> and €50,000 in cash due to non-compliant operations</span>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/">Australia intensifies crypto ATM oversight to curb money laundering risks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/australia-crypto-atm.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/australia-crypto-atm.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North Korean hackers impersonate tech professionals to steal billions in crypto</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/north-korean-hackers-impersonate-tech-professionals-to-steal-billions-in-crypto/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/north-korean-hackers-impersonate-tech-professionals-to-steal-billions-in-crypto/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 20:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hacks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>North Korean hackers have stolen billions in cryptocurrency and sensitive corporate data by impersonating venture capitalists, recruiters, and remote IT workers. Researchers made the revelations during Cyberwarcon, an annual cybersecurity conference, on Nov. 29. According to Microsoft security researcher James Elliott, North Korean operatives have infiltrated hundreds of global organizations by creating false identities. Using [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-korean-hackers-impersonate-tech-professionals-to-steal-billions-in-crypto/">North Korean hackers impersonate tech professionals to steal billions in crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>North Korean hackers have stolen billions in cryptocurrency and sensitive corporate data by impersonating venture capitalists, recruiters, and remote IT workers.</p>
<p>Researchers made the revelations during Cyberwarcon, an annual cybersecurity conference, on Nov. 29.</p>
<p>According to Microsoft security researcher James Elliott, North Korean operatives have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-korea-links-suspected-in-5-million-breach-of-tapioca-dao/">infiltrated hundreds</a> of global organizations by creating false identities.</p>
<p>Using tactics ranging from sophisticated AI-generated profiles to malware-laden recruitment campaigns, these hackers have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-links-major-crypto-heist-to-north-korea-recovers-bitcoin/">funneled stolen assets</a> to the regime&#8217;s nuclear weapons program, circumventing international sanctions.</p>
<p>According to Elliott:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;North Korean IT workers represent a triple threat.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>He emphasized their ability to earn a legitimate income, steal corporate secrets, and extort companies by threatening to expose stolen data in the modern world of remote work.</p>
<h2>Evolving cyber tactics</h2>
<p>The hackers employ a range of schemes to target companies. One group, dubbed &#8220;Ruby Sleet&#8221; by Microsoft, focuses on aerospace and defense firms stealing information to advance North Korea&#8217;s weapons technology.</p>
<p>Another, &#8220;Sapphire Sleet,&#8221; poses as recruiters and venture capitalists, tricking victims into downloading malware disguised as tools or assessments.</p>
<p>In one campaign, hackers stole $10 million in cryptocurrency over six months by targeting individuals and companies with fake virtual meeting setups. Hackers staged technical issues during the meetings to coerce victims into installing malware.</p>
<p>The most persistent threat stems from North Korean operatives posing as remote workers. These bad actors establish convincing online personas using LinkedIn profiles, GitHub repositories, and AI-generated deepfakes to take advantage of the global shift to remote work.</p>
<p>Once hired, these operatives direct company-issued laptops to US-based facilitators, who set up farms of devices preloaded with remote access software. This allows North Korean agents to operate from locations such as Russia and China.</p>
<p>Elliott revealed that Microsoft uncovered detailed operational plans, including fake resumes and identity dossiers, from a misconfigured repository belonging to a North Korean operative.</p>
<p>Elliott said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It was the entire playbook.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Calls for heightened vigilance</h2>
<p>While sanctions and public warnings have been issued, North Korean hacking groups continue to evade consequences.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, US prosecutors charged individuals connected to laptop farming, and the FBI <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fbi-warns-of-north-korean-threat-to-crypto-cautions-against-potential-etf-related-attacks/">cautioned companies</a> about using AI-generated deepfakes in employment scams.</p>
<p>Researchers emphasized the need for stricter employee verification processes. Elliott pointed to common red flags, including linguistic errors and inconsistencies in geographic data, that could help companies identify suspicious applicants.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This is not a fleeting issue. North Korea&#8217;s cyber campaigns are a long-term threat that demands constant vigilance.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>With cyber deception evolving rapidly, the global business community is under mounting pressure to adapt and strengthen its defenses against these sophisticated threats.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-korean-hackers-impersonate-tech-professionals-to-steal-billions-in-crypto/">North Korean hackers impersonate tech professionals to steal billions in crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/north-korean-hackers-impersonate-tech-professionals-to-steal-billions-in-crypto/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/north-korea-hacker.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/north-korea-hacker.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto losses hit second-lowest level of $71 million in November 2024</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-losses-hit-second-lowest-level-of-71-million-in-november-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-losses-hit-second-lowest-level-of-71-million-in-november-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto hacks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The crypto industry experienced its second-lowest monthly losses this month, November 2024, with $71 million lost across 26 incidents, according to blockchain security firm Immunefi. This marked a significant improvement compared to November 2023, which recorded $343 million in losses, representing a 79% year-over-year drop and a 4% decrease month-over-month. Year-to-date (YTD) figures show the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-losses-hit-second-lowest-level-of-71-million-in-november-2024/">Crypto losses hit second-lowest level of $71 million in November 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The crypto industry experienced its second-lowest monthly losses this month, November 2024, with $71 million lost across 26 incidents, according to blockchain security firm Immunefi.</p>
<p>This marked a significant improvement compared to November 2023, which recorded $343 million in losses, representing a 79% year-over-year drop and a 4% decrease month-over-month.</p>
<p>Year-to-date (YTD) figures show the industry lost $1.48 billion in 2024 due to hacks and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/glossary/rug-pull/">rug pulls</a> in 209 incidents. This represents a 15% decline compared to the $1.7 billion lost during the same period in 2023.</p>
<h2>November hacks</h2>
<p>According to Immunefi, two incidents accounted for most of November&#8217;s losses. DeFi project Thala Labs lost $25.5 million, while the memecoins trading terminal DEXX suffered a $21 million loss.</p>
<p>The firm noted that all reported cases for the month involved DeFi platforms, which surpassed centralized finance (CeFi) as the primary target. DeFi incidents accounted for 100% of the lost funds.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455233" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455233" style="width: 634px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455233" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-29-100640.jpg" alt="Top 10 November 2024 Hacks" width="634" height="612" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-29-100640.jpg 634w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-29-100640-300x290.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 634px) 100vw, 634px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455233" class="wp-caption-text">Top 10 November 2024 Hacks (Source: Immunefi)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, hacks remained the leading cause of losses, with $70.99 million lost across 24 hacking incidents. Rug pulls contributed a smaller amount, with $25,300 lost in two cases.</p>
<p>Across chains, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a>-backed BNB Chain was the most targeted blockchain, responsible for nearly 47% of the total losses across all chains. It added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> experienced 9 incidents, representing 30% of the total. Solana, Polygon, Fantom, Avalanche, Arbitrum, and Aptos each experienced one incident, accounting for 3.3%, respectively.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>CEXs dominate 50% of 2024 crypto losses</h2>
<p>Centralized exchanges (CEXs) have emerged as a significant target in 2024, accounting for almost 50% of total crypto-related losses year-to-date. Immunefi <a href="https://x.com/immunefi/status/1862136361148621295">reported</a> that CEX-related losses totaled $724 million, marking the highest share of attacks on centralized platforms since 2021.</p>
<p>The resurgence in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-korea-linked-hack-costs-crypto-exchange-bingx-52-million-in-crypto-assets/">CEX vulnerabilities</a> became particularly evident during the third quarter of the year when 72% of crypto losses stemmed from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/uaes-m2-crypto-exchange-hacked-for-13-7m-assures-full-fund-recovery/">CeFi hacks</a>. For context, a single attack on Indian exchange WazirX in July resulted in a<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hacker-nearly-completes-laundering-230-million-stolen-from-wazirx/"> $235 million loss</a>.</p>
<p>Immunefi highlighted that CeFi&#8217;s vulnerabilities often stem from compromised hot wallets, allowing attackers to drain substantial funds. The $724 million lost by CEXs in 2024 came from just nine incidents, whereas a similar amount in DeFi was spread across 200 attacks.</p>
<p>The security firm pointed out that blackhat hackers have adopted innovative methods to exploit centralized platforms.</p>
<p>These techniques include impersonating recruiters or securing fake job placements to infiltrate internal teams and infrastructure. Such threats often go undetected until significant damage occurs, underscoring their growing sophistication.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-losses-hit-second-lowest-level-of-71-million-in-november-2024/">Crypto losses hit second-lowest level of $71 million in November 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-losses-hit-second-lowest-level-of-71-million-in-november-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/hack-rug-pull.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/hack-rug-pull.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XT Exchange assures users after $1.7 million asset theft disrupts services</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/xt-exchange-assures-users-after-1-7-million-asset-theft-disrupts-services/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/xt-exchange-assures-users-after-1-7-million-asset-theft-disrupts-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455058</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>XT Exchange has suspended all coin withdrawals after it confirmed the &#8220;abnormal transfer of assets&#8221; from its platform. In a Nov. 28 announcement, the firm revealed that about $1 million worth of assets in 12 different currencies was affected. It stated: &#8220;[We] identified an abnormal transfer of assets from the platform wallet with the on-chain [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xt-exchange-assures-users-after-1-7-million-asset-theft-disrupts-services/">XT Exchange assures users after $1.7 million asset theft disrupts services</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>XT Exchange has suspended all coin withdrawals after it confirmed the &#8220;abnormal transfer of assets&#8221; from its platform.</p>
<p>In a Nov. 28 announcement, the firm revealed that about $1 million worth of assets in 12 different currencies was affected. It <a href="https://xtsupport.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/40528847749657-XT-COM-Statement-on-Abnormal-Transfer-of-Platform-Wallet-Assets">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[We] identified an abnormal transfer of assets from the platform wallet with the on-chain address 0xdb3ded7731c781224ec292e2163d9554c094fd7c. Our technical team is currently conducting an urgent investigation. The amount involved in this incident is approximately 1 million USDT across 12 different currencies.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Blockchain security platform Peckshield first <a href="https://x.com/PeckShieldAlert/status/1862059885174874355">reported</a> the incident. The security firm reported that XT suffered a $1.7 million exploit, and the attacker has allegedly swapped the stolen assets for 461.58 <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">ETH</a>, valued at approximately $1.66 million at current rates.</p>
<p>XT is a Seychelles-based crypto trading platform with approximately $147 million in reserves and has reported a 24-hour trading volume of $3.1 billion, according to CoinMarketCap <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/exchanges/xt/">data</a>.</p>
<h2>XT response</h2>
<p>XT claimed that the impacted funds involved in the breach belonged to it and assured users their assets were unaffected.</p>
<p>It <a href="https://xtsupport.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/40522692897561-XT-has-suspended-all-coin-withdrawals">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Since inception, XT.COM has always upheld a user-centric approach, maintaining strict and standardized platform fund management while prioritizing the security of user assets. We have established asset reserve funds 1.5 times greater than those of users on the exchange.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The firm plans to launch the Merkel Tree Asset Proof System in mid-December to enhance transparency and security.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, XT suspended all coin withdrawals, citing wallet upgrades and maintenance. The firm did not provide a clear timeline for when withdrawals would be reactivated.</p>
<h2>Increasing CEXs hack</h2>
<p>This incident adds to a growing list of centralized exchange (CEX) hacks in 2024.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, UAE-based exchange M2 lost $13.7 million in a breach. Other recent attacks include a $305 million exploit <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">of<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-exchange-suspends-withdrawals-after-305-million-bitcoin-theft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> Japan&#8217;s</a></span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-exchange-suspends-withdrawals-after-305-million-bitcoin-theft/"> DMM Bitcoin</a> platform, a $235 million hack <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">on<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indian-exchange-wazirx-hit-by-235-million-hack-north-korea-link-suspected/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> India&#8217;s</a></span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indian-exchange-wazirx-hit-by-235-million-hack-north-korea-link-suspected/"> WazirX in July</a>, and a $20 million <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indodax-hit-by-20-5m-exploit-north-korea-link-suspected/">breach of Indonesia&#8217;s Indodax exchange.</a></p>
<p>The rise in CEX hacks illustrates the ongoing need for more robust security measures within the crypto industry.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xt-exchange-assures-users-after-1-7-million-asset-theft-disrupts-services/">XT Exchange assures users after $1.7 million asset theft disrupts services</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/xt-exchange-assures-users-after-1-7-million-asset-theft-disrupts-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/xt-usdt.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/xt-usdt.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain security firm warns of AI code poisoning risk after OpenAI&#8217;s ChatGPT recommends scam API</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-security-firm-warns-of-ai-code-poisoning-risk-after-openais-chatgpt-recommends-scam-api/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-security-firm-warns-of-ai-code-poisoning-risk-after-openais-chatgpt-recommends-scam-api/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 12:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChatGPT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Yu Xian, founder of the blockchain security firm Slowmist, has raised alarms about a rising threat known as AI code poisoning. This attack type involves injecting harmful code into the training data of AI models, which can pose risks for users who depend on these tools for technical tasks. The incident The issue gained attention [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-security-firm-warns-of-ai-code-poisoning-risk-after-openais-chatgpt-recommends-scam-api/">Blockchain security firm warns of AI code poisoning risk after OpenAI&#8217;s ChatGPT recommends scam API</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yu Xian, founder of the blockchain security firm Slowmist, has <a href="https://x.com/evilcos/status/1859818700389732513">raised alarms</a> about a rising threat known as AI code poisoning.</p>
<p>This attack type involves injecting harmful code into the training data of AI models, which can pose risks for users who depend on these tools for technical tasks.</p>
<h2>The incident</h2>
<p>The issue gained attention after a troubling incident involving OpenAI&#8217;s ChatGPT. On Nov. 21, a crypto trader named &#8220;r_cky0&#8221; <a href="https://x.com/r_cky0/status/1859656430888026524">reported</a> losing $2,500 in digital assets after seeking ChatGPT&#8217;s help to create a bot for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a>-based memecoin generator Pump.fun.</p>
<p>However, the chatbot recommended a fraudulent Solana API website, which led to the theft of the user&#8217;s private keys. The victim noted that within 30 minutes of using the malicious API, all assets were drained to a wallet linked to the scam.</p>
<p><em>[Editor&#8217;s Note: ChatGPT appears to have recommended the API after running a search using the new SearchGPT as a &#8216;sources&#8217; section can be seen in the screenshot. Therefore, it does not seem to be a case of AI poisoning but a failure of the AI to recognize scam links in search results.]</em></p>
<figure style="width: 1418px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Gc7SoMDWYAAvsS6?format=jpg&amp;name=large" alt="AI scam link API (Source: X)" width="1418" height="958" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">AI scam link API (Source: X)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Further investigation revealed this address consistently receives stolen tokens, reinforcing suspicions that it belongs to a fraudster.</p>
<p>The Slowmist founder noted that the fraudulent API&#8217;s domain name was registered two months ago, suggesting the attack was premeditated. Xian furthered that the website lacked detailed content, consisting only of documents and code repositories.</p>
<p><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">While the poisoning appears deliberate, no evidence suggests <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/openai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">OpenAI</a> intentionally integrated the malicious data into ChatGPT&#8217;s training, with the result likely coming from SearchGPT.</span></p>
<h2>Implications</h2>
<p>Blockchain security firm Scam Sniffer <a href="https://x.com/realScamSniffer/status/1859765453536756130">noted</a> that this incident illustrates how scammers pollute AI training data with harmful crypto code. The firm said that a GitHub user, &#8220;solanaapisdev,&#8221; has recently created multiple repositories to manipulate AI models to generate fraudulent outputs in recent months.</p>
<p>AI tools like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chatgpt-drives-openai-toward-1b-revenue-goal-after-losing-540m-in-2022/">ChatGPT</a>, now used by hundreds of millions, face increasing challenges as attackers find new ways to exploit them.</p>
<p>Xian cautioned crypto users about the risks tied to large language models (LLMs) like GPT. He emphasized that once a theoretical risk, AI poisoning has now materialized into a real threat. So, without more robust defenses, incidents like this could undermine trust in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-launches-new-tool-to-help-users-build-ai-agents-in-minutes/">AI-driven tools</a> and expose users to further financial losses.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-security-firm-warns-of-ai-code-poisoning-risk-after-openais-chatgpt-recommends-scam-api/">Blockchain security firm warns of AI code poisoning risk after OpenAI&#8217;s ChatGPT recommends scam API</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-security-firm-warns-of-ai-code-poisoning-risk-after-openais-chatgpt-recommends-scam-api/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ai-poisoning-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ai-poisoning-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korea links major crypto heist to North Korea, recovers Bitcoin</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-links-major-crypto-heist-to-north-korea-recovers-bitcoin/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-links-major-crypto-heist-to-north-korea-recovers-bitcoin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 13:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UPbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>South Korean authorities have successfully recovered 4.8 Bitcoin (BTC), which was linked to the 2019 hack of the Upbit exchange, local media outlet Yonhap News reported on Nov. 21. The incident, in which North Korean hackers stole 342,000 Ethereum (ETH), was among the most significant cyberattacks targeting a cryptocurrency platform. The stolen Ethereum, valued at [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-links-major-crypto-heist-to-north-korea-recovers-bitcoin/">South Korea links major crypto heist to North Korea, recovers Bitcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korean authorities have successfully recovered 4.8 Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>), which was linked to the 2019 hack of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/upbit/">Upbit</a> exchange, local media outlet Yonhap News <a href="https://en.yna.co.kr/view/AEN20241121005600315?section=nk/nk">reported</a> on Nov. 21.</p>
<p>The incident, in which North Korean hackers stole 342,000 <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> (ETH), was among the most significant cyberattacks targeting a cryptocurrency platform. The stolen Ethereum, valued at $41.4 million in 2019, is now worth over $1 billion at current prices.</p>
<h2>The investigation</h2>
<p>South Korea&#8217;s National Police Agency&#8217;s investigation confirmed the involvement of North Korean hacker groups <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chinese-otc-trader-linked-to-laundering-millions-for-north-korean-hackers/">Lazarus</a> and Andariel in the Upbit 2019 hack. These groups are notorious for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-koreas-lazarus-group-tied-to-305m-crypto-breach-of-japans-dmm-exchange/">large-scale cybercrime</a> and have stolen more than $3 billion in cryptocurrency from 2017 to 2023.</p>
<p>The confirmation marks the first time South Korean police have officially tied a significant hack to North Korean operatives.</p>
<p>Police explained that the hackers laundered 57% of the stolen ETH by converting it into Bitcoin. The funds flowed through three North Korea-linked exchanges and 51 global platforms.</p>
<p>After years of tracing blockchain activity and analyzing North Korean IP addresses, investigators identified patterns, including unique North Korean language usage. Support from the US Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) also contributed to uncovering the hackers&#8217; operations.</p>
<p>The recovered Bitcoin, which was traced to a Swiss exchange, has been returned to Upbit.</p>
<h2>Upbit scrutiny</h2>
<p>This development arrives as Upbit is under scrutiny from South Korea&#8217;s Financial Intelligence Unit (FIU) over <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-investigates-upbits-kyc-violations-amid-market-dominance-concerns/">KYC-related violations</a>. The FIU reports that the exchange could be implicated in as many as 600,000 compliance breaches.</p>
<p>South Korea&#8217;s Financial Services Commission (FSC) has also flagged <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-investigates-upbit-over-market-dominance-concerns/">concerns over Upbit&#8217;s market dominance</a>. The exchange accounts for nearly 20% of the 22 trillion won deposited in K Bank, raising questions about potential risks to the financial system.</p>
<p>According to CoinMarketCap <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/exchanges/upbit/">data</a>, Upbit is the largest South Korean crypto trading platform, with a trading volume of around $6 billion.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-links-major-crypto-heist-to-north-korea-recovers-bitcoin/">South Korea links major crypto heist to North Korea, recovers Bitcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-links-major-crypto-heist-to-north-korea-recovers-bitcoin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/korean-police.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/korean-police.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX co-founder Gary Wang sentenced to &#8216;time served&#8217; as FTX criminal cases end</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-co-founder-gary-wang-sentenced-to-time-served-as-ftx-criminal-cases-end/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-co-founder-gary-wang-sentenced-to-time-served-as-ftx-criminal-cases-end/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 16:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gary Wang, co-founder and former chief technology officer of crypto exchange FTX, was sentenced to time served with no additional jail time after providing extensive cooperation to U.S. prosecutors in one of the largest financial fraud cases in history, as reported by Inner City Press. Inner City Press shared live updates from the court via [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-co-founder-gary-wang-sentenced-to-time-served-as-ftx-criminal-cases-end/">FTX co-founder Gary Wang sentenced to &#8216;time served&#8217; as FTX criminal cases end</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Gary Wang, co-founder and former chief technology officer of crypto exchange FTX, was sentenced to time served with no additional jail time after providing extensive cooperation to U.S. prosecutors in one of the largest financial fraud cases in history, as <a href="https://x.com/innercitypress/status/1859258186001269095">reported</a> by Inner City Press.</p>
<p>Inner City Press shared live updates from the court via its X account detailing that Judge Lewis A. Kaplan acknowledged Wang&#8217;s significant assistance during the sentencing hearing, stating,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;If this wasn&#8217;t the biggest financial fraud in U.S. history, it was certainly among the biggest two or three.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Wang faced up to 50 years in prison but began cooperating with authorities shortly after FTX&#8217;s collapse in November 2022.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Andrew Roos emphasized the uniqueness of Wang&#8217;s cooperation, highlighting his technical expertise and willingness to assist from the outset. &#8220;He deciphered half the case for us on the first day of his cooperation,&#8221; Roos said. Wang&#8217;s insights were crucial in understanding how FTX&#8217;s code allowed for the misappropriation of customer funds, which played a central role in the fraudulent activities tied to the exchange.</p>
<p>Wang admitted that FTX had sent billions of dollars in customer funds to its sister trading firm, Alameda Research, without user consent. He revealed that Alameda was permitted to borrow unlimited amounts and maintain a negative balance on FTX, effectively using customer assets to cover losses and fund operations. These disclosures were instrumental in building the case against former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried and other executives.</p>
<p>Beyond his testimony, Wang took proactive steps to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gary-wang-faced-up-to-50-years-in-prison-before-plea-deal-still-not-guaranteed-leniency/">aid the investigation</a>. He developed software tools to help prosecutors detect securities fraud, dedicating personal time to these efforts. &#8220;He was the easiest cooperator I&#8217;ve ever worked with,&#8221; Roos noted, adding that Wang&#8217;s contributions could assist in uncovering future fraud cases before they escalate.</p>
<p>During the hearing, Wang expressed deep remorse for his actions. &#8220;I am deeply sorry to all the customers and investors in FTX who trusted us,&#8221; he said. &#8220;There are so many things I could have done.&#8221; He pledged to continue assisting efforts to make customers whole and to support government investigations.</p>
<p>Wang&#8217;s attorney, Ilan Graff, highlighted his client&#8217;s commitment to rectifying the situation. He mentioned that Wang has since found employment outside the crypto industry, is expecting his first child, and seeks to move forward responsibly. Graff argued that a sentence of time served would allow Wang to &#8220;continue his cooperation with the government and the bankruptcy estate&#8221; and to &#8220;be the devoted husband and father he so desperately seeks to be.&#8221;</p>
<p>Judge Kaplan granted the prosecution&#8217;s motion recognizing the substantial assistance provided by Wang. In delivering the sentence, the judge stated, &#8220;You did the right thing for yourself and the right thing for the country.&#8221; Wang received time served and three years of supervised release.</p>
<p>Wang&#8217;s sentencing follows that of former Alameda Research CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/caroline-ellison-sentenced-to-24-months-in-prison-for-her-role-in-ftx-collapse/">Caroline Ellison</a>, who was sentenced to two years in prison after her own cooperation with authorities. Both individuals played key roles in exposing the inner workings of FTX and Alameda Research, shedding light on practices that led to significant financial losses for customers and investors.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-co-founder-gary-wang-sentenced-to-time-served-as-ftx-criminal-cases-end/">FTX co-founder Gary Wang sentenced to &#8216;time served&#8217; as FTX criminal cases end</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-co-founder-gary-wang-sentenced-to-time-served-as-ftx-criminal-cases-end/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Switzerland regulator warns of rising crypto money laundering risks</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/switzerland-regulator-warns-of-rising-crypto-money-laundering-risks/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/switzerland-regulator-warns-of-rising-crypto-money-laundering-risks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 14:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FINMA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Switzerland]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland&#8217;s Financial Market Supervisory Authority (FINMA) has raised concerns about increasing money laundering risks in the crypto sector. The warning, detailed in FINMA&#8217;s 2024 Risk Monitor report, highlights the growing misuse of digital assets like cryptocurrencies and stablecoins for illicit activities. The report indicated that stablecoins are increasingly used in illegal transactions, such as sanctions [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/switzerland-regulator-warns-of-rising-crypto-money-laundering-risks/">Switzerland regulator warns of rising crypto money laundering risks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Switzerland&#8217;s Financial Market Supervisory Authority (FINMA) has raised concerns about increasing money laundering risks in the crypto sector.</p>
<p>The warning, detailed in FINMA&#8217;s <a href="https://www.finma.ch/en/~/media/finma/dokumente/dokumentencenter/myfinma/finma-publikationen/risikomonitor/20241118-finma-risikomonitor-2024.pdf">2024 Risk Monitor report</a>, highlights the growing misuse of digital assets like cryptocurrencies and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-treasury-official-targets-tether-usdt-stablecoin-in-russian-sanction-evasion/">stablecoins for illicit activities</a>.</p>
<p>The report indicated that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/glossary/stablecoin/">stablecoins</a> are increasingly used in illegal transactions, such as sanctions evasion. This trend complicates enforcement efforts and heightens legal and reputational risks for financial institutions without robust risk management strategies.</p>
<p>The regulator emphasized the need for stronger measures to address vulnerabilities linked to the misuse of digital assets.</p>
<p>It added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Money laundering risks can be considerable for financial intermediaries with a crypto offering. Financial intermediaries active in this area without adequate management of money laundering risk can seriously damage the reputation of the Swiss financial centre.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This warning follows a <a href="https://www.finma.ch/en/news/2024/07/20240726-m-am-06-24-stablecoins/">similar advisory</a> issued earlier this year, where FINMA urged stablecoin issuers and banks to verify token holder identities to reduce exposure to money laundering.</p>
<p>According to the regulator:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;FINMA draws attention to the increased risks in the areas of money laundering, terrorist financing and the circumvention of sanctions. These also result in reputational risks for the Swiss financial centre as a whole.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Risk mitigation</h2>
<p>Due to this, FINMA has implemented institution-specific measures to mitigate these risks, including targeted oversight and enhanced risk management requirements. Broader efforts include on-site inspections and revisions to audit programs, aiming to strengthen defenses against money laundering.</p>
<p>The regulator has also called for clear risk tolerance definitions and effective risk management practices, particularly for institutions dealing with politically exposed individuals or clients in high-risk sectors.</p>
<p>These initiatives are designed to curb vulnerabilities and ensure compliance with anti-money laundering regulations.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, crypto organizations also have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-commits-to-freezing-addresses-linked-to-sanctions-as-scrutiny-over-usdt-misuse-grows/">stepped up efforts</a> to mitigate money laundering risks associated with the industry. For context, stablecoin issuer Tether, TRON blockchain, and analytical firm TRM Labs recently <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-teams-up-with-tron-and-trm-labs-to-combat-usdt-crime/">formed a dedicated financial crime unit</a> to combat the illicit use of the USDT stablecoin.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/switzerland-regulator-warns-of-rising-crypto-money-laundering-risks/">Switzerland regulator warns of rising crypto money laundering risks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/switzerland-regulator-warns-of-rising-crypto-money-laundering-risks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/switzerland-flag.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/switzerland-flag.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto phishing scam nets $129 million in USDT then funds mysteriously return</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-phishing-scam-nets-129-million-in-usdt-then-funds-mysteriously-return/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-phishing-scam-nets-129-million-in-usdt-then-funds-mysteriously-return/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 12:40:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tron]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDT]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A crypto whale narrowly avoided a $129 million USDT loss after falling victim to a phishing scam on the TRON blockchain. Blockchain security firm Scam Sniffer reported the incident on Nov. 20, detailing how the stolen funds were unexpectedly returned within hours. What happened? According to the firm, the scammer used a fake wallet address, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-phishing-scam-nets-129-million-in-usdt-then-funds-mysteriously-return/">Crypto phishing scam nets $129 million in USDT then funds mysteriously return</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A crypto whale narrowly avoided a $129 million <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tether/">USDT</a> loss after falling victim to a phishing scam on the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tron/">TRON</a> blockchain.</p>
<p>Blockchain security firm Scam Sniffer <a href="https://x.com/realScamSniffer/status/1859089504994554363">reported</a> the incident on Nov. 20, detailing how the stolen funds were unexpectedly returned within hours.</p>
<h2>What happened?</h2>
<p>According to the firm, the scammer used a fake wallet address, &#8220;THc&#8230;bu8,&#8221; crafted to closely resemble the intended recipient&#8217;s &#8220;TMS&#8230;bu8.&#8221; The fraudulent address mimicked the original by matching its starting and ending characters.</p>
<p>Despite testing the waters with a test 100 USDT transaction, the victim could not spot the subtle differences and eventually transferred $129 million to the wrong address.</p>
<p>Surprisingly, the fraudster returned 90% of the stolen funds—116.7 million USDT— within an hour of the incident and eventually returned the remaining balance of 12.96 million USDT after four hours.</p>
<p>Following the fund return, the victim promptly redirected the funds to their original destination, &#8220;TMS&#8230;bu8,&#8221; where they have since remained.</p>
<h2>Rising threat of address poisoning attacks</h2>
<p>Scam Sniffer identified this incident as a classic example of an address-poisoning attack, a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/phishing-scams-plague-crypto-with-46m-loss-in-september-126m-in-q3/">phishing tactic</a> gaining widespread traction in the industry.</p>
<p>This scam involves creating wallet addresses nearly identical to those used by victims, differing by just one or two characters. Fraudsters then send small token amounts to victims, embedding the fake address in their transaction history to exploit copy-and-paste errors during future transfers.</p>
<p>CertiK, another blockchain security firm, <a href="https://x.com/CertiKAlert/status/1857422755987124400?t=DdmxUMpIt-CBniPhJ8Z16g&amp;s=19">noted</a> that this phishing tactic, along with wallet drainers, has led to the loss of more than $800 million worth of crypto assets this year.</p>
<p>Due to this, Yu Xian, founder of web3 firm Slowmist, <a href="https://x.com/evilcos/status/1855590656108007870">cautioned</a> crypto users about the risks of copying sensitive information. He advised clearing clipboard data after use to avoid falling prey to such scams. Xian emphasized that no connected device is entirely secure, reinforcing the need for vigilance in safeguarding digital assets.</p>
<p>Observers stated that this case further emphasizes the evolving sophistication of crypto phishing scams and highlights the importance of double-checking wallet addresses before making transfers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-phishing-scam-nets-129-million-in-usdt-then-funds-mysteriously-return/">Crypto phishing scam nets $129 million in USDT then funds mysteriously return</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-phishing-scam-nets-129-million-in-usdt-then-funds-mysteriously-return/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/phishing-hack-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/phishing-hack-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Delhi police arrest key suspect in $235 million WazirX crypto breach</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/delhi-police-arrest-key-suspect-in-235m-wazirx-crypto-breach/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/delhi-police-arrest-key-suspect-in-235m-wazirx-crypto-breach/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 12:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WazirX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452966</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Delhi Police have made progress in investigating the $235 million breach of crypto exchange WazirX by arresting SK Masud Alam from Bengal. On Nov. 13, local media outlet IndiaToday reported that Alam allegedly set up a fake account on WazirX under the alias &#8220;Souvik Mondal.&#8221; He reportedly sold this account via Telegram to a person [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/delhi-police-arrest-key-suspect-in-235m-wazirx-crypto-breach/">Delhi police arrest key suspect in $235 million WazirX crypto breach</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Delhi Police have made progress in investigating the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hacker-nearly-completes-laundering-230-million-stolen-from-wazirx/">$235 million breach</a> of crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/wazirx/">WazirX</a> by arresting SK Masud Alam from Bengal.</p>
<p>On Nov. 13, local media outlet IndiaToday <a href="https://www.indiatoday.in/india/story/delhi-police-bengal-man-arrested-crypto-cyberattack-fake-account-wazirx-liminal-custody-chargesheet-2633006-2024-11-13">reported</a> that Alam allegedly set up a fake account on WazirX under the alias &#8220;Souvik Mondal.&#8221; He reportedly sold this account via Telegram to a person identified as M. Hasan, who then used it to carry out the exploit.</p>
<p>As part of the investigation, authorities have confiscated three laptops belonging to WazirX&#8217;s authorized signatories to examine possible misuse of multisig wallets.</p>
<p>The charge sheet reveals that WazirX has been fully cooperative in providing detailed KYC data and transaction records. However, an inspection by the Indian Cyber Crime Coordination Centre (IFSO) found no evidence of unauthorized access within WazirX&#8217;s internal systems.</p>
<p>In contrast, authorities report difficulties working with <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/liminal-cleared-by-independent-security-audit-after-wazirx-breach-no-vulnerabilities-found/">Liminal</a>, the digital asset custody provider initially responsible for securing WazirX&#8217;s wallets.</p>
<p>Police claim that despite repeated requests, Liminal failed to supply relevant information, hindering their ability to trace the breach fully. As a result, Liminal&#8217;s alleged lack of cooperation will be highlighted in a supplementary charge sheet as the investigation continues.</p>
<p>WazirX and Liminal had previously <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/liminal-cleared-by-independent-security-audit-after-wazirx-breach-no-vulnerabilities-found/">traded blame over the breach.</a> The exchange asserted that Liminal failed to uphold security standards, while the asset custodian faulted WazirX&#8217;s management practices.</p>
<h2>Fund recovery initiatives</h2>
<p>This development comes around a week after the exchange <a href="https://x.com/WazirXIndia/status/1854141317909299500">outlined strategies</a> to maximize fund recovery for its creditors.</p>
<p>The first step involves reopening the trading platform to restore trading volumes and generate revenue that benefits creditors. WazirX plans to share fees collected during this period with creditors, creating a direct pathway for financial recovery.</p>
<p>The second initiative would see WazirX diversify its revenue streams by launching new services, including a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wazirx-announces-plans-to-launch-dex-amid-fallout-from-record-crypto-theft/">decentralized exchange (DEX)</a>, staking, an over-the-counter (OTC) desk, and futures trading.</p>
<p>These services would be designed to attract users to the platform, and the revenue would also be aimed at making the platform whole.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, WazirX has also committed to recovering lost and illiquid assets through legal channels. The exchange aims to reclaim these assets to safeguard them for its creditors. The firm stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This process includes tracking these assets and preventing unauthorized withdrawals to maximize potential returns for Creditors.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The final part of WazirX&#8217;s recovery strategy involves exploring &#8220;White Knight&#8221; partnerships, where potential investors could provide rescue financing. This approach would introduce new funds into the recovery process, supporting WazirX&#8217;s efforts to compensate creditors and stabilize operations.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/delhi-police-arrest-key-suspect-in-235m-wazirx-crypto-breach/">Delhi police arrest key suspect in $235 million WazirX crypto breach</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/delhi-police-arrest-key-suspect-in-235m-wazirx-crypto-breach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/wazirx-hack.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/wazirx-hack.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
