<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Gaming News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/gaming/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/gaming/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 13:42:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Gaming News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/gaming/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Epic Games hit Off The Grid wins Game of the Year at first live 2024 GAM3 Awards</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 09:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Off The Grid secured the Game of the Year award at the 2024 GAM3 Awards, held live for the first time in Manila on Nov.22. Developed by Gunzilla Games, the Web3-enabled, free-to-play, third-person battle royale game also won awards for Best Shooter Game, Best Multiplayer Game, and Best Action Game, marking a significant achievement in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/">Epic Games hit Off The Grid wins Game of the Year at first live 2024 GAM3 Awards</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Off The Grid secured the Game of the Year award at the 2024 GAM3 Awards, held live for the first time in Manila on Nov.22.</p>
<p>Developed by Gunzilla Games, the Web3-enabled, free-to-play, third-person battle royale game also won awards for Best Shooter Game, Best Multiplayer Game, and Best Action Game, marking a significant achievement in the blockchain gaming industry.</p>
<p>Hosted in partnership with Yield Guild Games (YGG), the GAM3 Awards recognized excellence across 21 categories, celebrating the progress of the Web3 gaming sector over the past year. The event featured an increased prize pool of $5 million, comprising grants, products, services, marketing, and blockchain support from partners such as AWS, XAI, Thirdweb, Aethir, and Community Gaming.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455031" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455031" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-455031 size-large" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-1024x569.jpg" alt="Gam3 Awards (Source:gam3s.gg)" width="1024" height="569" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-1024x569.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-300x167.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-768x426.jpg 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-1536x853.jpg 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards.jpg 1758w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455031" class="wp-caption-text">Gam3 Awards (Source:gam3s.gg)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The selection process involved over 70 jurors from prominent gaming and blockchain organizations, including representatives from <em>CryptoSlate</em>, Amazon, Google, Ubisoft, Animoca Brands, Immutable, Arbitrum, Blockchain Game Alliance, Base, Ronin, and Avalanche. Community engagement was significant, with over one million votes from 143,000 unique voters contributing to the final decisions in several categories.</p>
<p>Off The Grid&#8217;s success reflects the growing integration of blockchain technology in gaming. Set in a dystopian cyberpunk future on Teardrop Island, the game incorporates blockchain elements through the GUNZ blockchain using an Avalanche subnet, offering a player-driven economy with tradable in-game assets.</p>
<p>Off The Grid&#8217;s early access release <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">achieved</a> rapid growth, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/">topping</a> Epic Games&#8217; free-to-play PC games list and surpassing popular titles like Fortnite and Rocket League. In its first five days, the game grew by more than one million wallets per day, accumulating 53 million transactions.</p>
<p>Other notable winners at the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/parallel-dominates-gam3-awards-with-triple-win-including-game-of-the-year/">GAM3 Awards</a> include Parallel, which claimed awards for Best Strategy Game, Best Card Game, and Best Esports Game. Pixels and Pirate Nation each took home two awards, further highlighting the diversity and innovation within the Web3 gaming space.</p>
<p>With over 300 in-person attendees, the event featured gameplay premieres and exclusive trailers from upcoming titles such as Golden Tides, Unfettered, Elumia, Providence, Shrapnel, and more. The ceremony reached a peak viewership of 48,000 concurrent viewers, amassing over 450,000 views in the first 24 hours.</p>
<p>The success of Off The Grid and the GAM3 Awards illustrates the increasing acceptance and integration of blockchain technology in mainstream gaming. Analysts <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">speculate</a> that Off The Grid could be a catalyst for a new crypto gaming bull run, potentially becoming as significant as Axie Infinity was in previous cycles.</p>
<p>The GAM3 Awards are expected to return next November for their fourth consecutive edition, signaling ongoing recognition of excellence in Web3 gaming.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/">Epic Games hit Off The Grid wins Game of the Year at first live 2024 GAM3 Awards</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3-awards-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3-awards-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The gaming lesson from Off The Grid and Telegram? Put blockchain in the background</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leo Li]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 06:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post from Leo Li, Chief Growth Officer at CARV. Off The Grid could be the mainstream moment we&#8217;ve been waiting for in web3 gaming – not because it flaunts blockchain features, but because it doesn&#8217;t. The major console release integrates NFTs and blockchain in the background, letting gameplay take center [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">The gaming lesson from Off The Grid and Telegram? Put blockchain in the background</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest post from Leo Li, Chief Growth Officer at CARV.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Off The Grid could be the mainstream moment we&#8217;ve been waiting for in web3 gaming – not because it flaunts blockchain features, but because it doesn&#8217;t. The major console release integrates NFTs and blockchain in the background, letting gameplay take center stage. The game is the main appeal, while the blockchain is a bonus that furthers trading, ownership, and expression.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much like Telegram, which is quietly slipping crypto wallet functionality into hundreds of millions of pockets, game developers realize that simplicity is vital. Hitting gamers over the head with painful onboarding and crypto-heavy concepts can alienate potential players. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next gaming bull run will not be driven by </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gaming/">blockchain games</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">—it will be driven by great games that happen to use blockchain.</span></p>
<h2><b>The quiet revolution in blockchain gaming</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Off The Grid is causing a lot of noise for a game that&#8217;s not officially out yet. The cyberpunk battle royale from Gunzilla Games – only available via early access on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X – is getting plenty of attention for its tongue-in-cheek violence and gritty visuals from filmmaker Neill Blomkamp (District 9, Elysium). </span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“Part schlocky satire of streaming culture, part sendup of gamers, all shrewd self-aware storytelling: Off The Grid is a fun time,” </strong><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/gaming/why-you-should-be-playing-off-the-grid-a-new-battle-royale-right-now/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CNET wrote in October.</span></a></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s a fun time, indeed, that&#8217;s entirely on the blockchain. Blink, and you might miss it, but Off The Grid is a native web3 title built upon an Avalanche subnet. This enables crypto capabilities alongside gameplay, including a forthcoming token and the NFT minting and trading of in-game weapons and skins on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/opensea/">OpenSea</a>. The best part? So far, players aren&#8217;t obligated to engage with these features. The blockchain and the game are separate yet complementary, with the former intended to enhance the latter rather than override it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s a similar story over on Telegram. Players are flocking to the simplicity and engagement of clicker games inside the chat platform. Thanks to endorsing <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/telegram-open-network/">The Open Network (TON)</a> as its official web3 infrastructure and integrating wallet functionality, Telegram makes it easy for gamers to embrace crypto without knowing it. Gone are complicated onboarding and clunky interfaces. Telegram&#8217;s mini-app gaming occurs automatically inside the known and trusted chat platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The successes are impressive across the board. TON clicker <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/notcoin/">Notcoin</a> and its eponymous token rose to a market cap of more than half a billion dollars, and BANANA earned 12 million players just over a month after launch. Meanwhile, Off The Grid is also gaining serious traction, with millions of wallets created during the first week of early access before becoming the top free game on the Epic Games Store. The numbers tell a clear story: mass adoption follows when blockchain integration is invisible.</span></p>
<h2><b>The lesson for blockchain game makers</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the sector&#8217;s inception, we&#8217;ve been waiting for the blockchain gaming &#8220;mainstream moment.&#8221; The one-two punch of Off The Grid and Telegram suggests we&#8217;re inching closer, but their wins hold essential lessons for developers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, arming your game with blockchain isn&#8217;t enough. </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/heres-why-31-of-blockchains-games-were-shuttered-in-2023/">About 400 crypto games</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> stopped development last year, and since 2018, more than </span><strong><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/three-quarters-web3-blockchain-games-failed-last-five-years-coingecko">three-quarters of all blockchain games</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have failed to gain traction and been discontinued. The reason? Games weren&#8217;t fun enough, and blockchain features weren&#8217;t compelling enough. Going forward, game makers must start with both the game and the blockchain use case before working backward. Without a good game behind it, the blockchain elements never have a chance to take off.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second lesson is about accessibility. </span><strong><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/onboarding-crypto-adoption-challenges">One-quarter of web3 leaders agree</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the learning curve for blockchain technology and the lack of user-friendly interfaces remain significant hurdles to adoption. Solutions like </span><strong><a href="https://protocol.carv.io/identity">CARV ID</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are instructive here, uniting gamer profiles under one banner to improve interoperability and showcase achievements across games. This new crop of games shows that we need to start with great gameplay, make it easy to access, and bake blockchain into the foundation. This is the best way to make both sides of &#8220;blockchain gaming&#8221; work together.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my view, it&#8217;s time to think of blockchain gaming like cloud computing—something consumers seldom encounter, but that drives the backend thanks to invisible integration. Just as we don&#8217;t think about cloud computing when using Netflix, players shouldn&#8217;t have to think about blockchain when inside our games.</span></p>
<h2><b>Balancing gameplay and blockchain in 2025</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heading into the new year, blockchain gaming is better positioned to break into the mainstream. AAA studios are taking us seriously, and gamers are coming around the idea of blockchain features that further the play experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, there&#8217;s a fine line between creating a great game and ensuring meaningful crypto synergy. Neopets Metaverse, an NFT-powered game based on the massively popular 1999 pet simulator, was in development for roughly two years before it was abruptly canceled. The reason? The CEO said gamers </span><a href="https://decrypt.co/151644/neopets-fans-care-less-about-crypto-ceo-says"><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;<strong>didn&#8217;t care</strong>&#8220;</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about blockchain, with the title intended to repurpose it as a regular mobile game. Clearly, the game needs to be good, and adding blockchain needs to make sense, add value, and improve the ecosystem.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here, understanding the audience is crucial. Gamers trend younger and want better ways to express themselves, own their identities, and make money online – all things blockchain can enable. Therefore, making these features accessible and meaningful with blockchain will drive the next web3 gaming bull run.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the challenge for our sector in 2025 – making blockchain relevant to the game, invisible to the player, and powerful enough to drive adoption. It&#8217;s now up to us – the developers – to get there. Off The Grid and Telegram are showing us the way forward – put blockchain in the background and let the games lead the charge.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">The gaming lesson from Off The Grid and Telegram? Put blockchain in the background</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/web3-gaming-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/web3-gaming-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DeepLink harnesses blockchain and AI to reinvent cloud gaming</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/deeplink-harnesses-blockchain-and-ai-to-reinvent-cloud-gaming/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/deeplink-harnesses-blockchain-and-ai-to-reinvent-cloud-gaming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Desk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sponsored]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Imagine gaming in ultra-high-definition from any device, without the need for expensive hardware, and with the security of blockchain at your fingertips. DeepLink is making this possible—redefining cloud gaming by harnessing the power of decentralization and AI. With an intelligent, tokenized ecosystem, DeepLink isn’t just a cloud gaming platform; it’s a movement towards a more [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/deeplink-harnesses-blockchain-and-ai-to-reinvent-cloud-gaming/">DeepLink harnesses blockchain and AI to reinvent cloud gaming</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Imagine gaming in ultra-high-definition from any device, without the need for expensive hardware, and with the security of blockchain at your fingertips. DeepLink is making this possible—redefining cloud gaming by harnessing the power of decentralization and AI. With an intelligent, tokenized ecosystem, <a href="https://www.deeplink.cloud/"><span class="s1">DeepLink</span></a> isn’t just a cloud gaming platform; it’s a movement towards a more accessible, efficient, and secure future for gamers and GPU providers alike.</p>
<p class="p3">DeepLink is a decentralized cloud gaming platform that combines blockchain and AI technology to deliver high-performance gaming experiences. By leveraging a distributed network of GPU nodes, DeepLink aims to provide low-latency, cost-effective cloud gaming accessible on any device. In this article we will explore how DeepLink is disrupting the cloud gaming industry.</p>
<h2 class="p4"><b>Decentralized infrastructure for reduced latency</b></h2>
<p class="p1">The core of DeepLink&#8217;s approach is its decentralized network architecture. Rather than relying on centralized data centers, DeepLink taps into a global network of &#8220;Aether Edge&#8221; nodes contributed by GPU providers worldwide.</p>
<p class="p3">As a DeepLink spokesperson explained, &#8220;The distributed network of nodes brings computing power closer to users, reducing lag and improving the gameplay experience.&#8221; This decentralized infrastructure is powered by blockchain technology, which ensures the integrity and transparency of transactions and data within the ecosystem.</p>
<h2 class="p4"><b>AI-Driven resource allocation and optimization</b></h2>
<p class="p1">At the core of DeepLink&#8217;s platform is its sophisticated use of artificial intelligence to enhance the cloud gaming experience. The company leverages AI algorithms to dynamically manage and optimize the distribution of computing resources across its decentralized network.</p>
<p class="p1">As the DeepLink spokesperson explained, &#8220;Artificial intelligence is used to analyze gaming patterns and user behavior in real-time. This allows us to intelligently adjust graphics settings, network resources, and other parameters to maintain smooth, low-latency performance.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">The AI systems constantly monitor factors like individual device capabilities, network conditions, and game requirements. By predicting user needs and proactively allocating the appropriate GPU power and bandwidth, DeepLink is able to minimize latency and deliver a seamless gaming experience.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p5"><i>&#8220;Our AI-driven resource allocation is pretty smart about energy use as well,&#8221; the spokesperson noted. &#8220;It&#8217;s constantly optimizing, making sure we&#8217;re using just the right amount of power for each gaming session. No waste, no overkill.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">This level of intelligent optimization is a key differentiator for DeepLink, allowing it to extract maximum performance from its decentralized infrastructure. The spokesperson emphasized that this AI-powered approach is critical to fulfilling the promise of cloud gaming at scale:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p6"><i>&#8220;Traditional cloud gaming services often struggle with latency and consistency issues. But by harnessing the power of artificial intelligence, we&#8217;re able to overcome those challenges and provide a truly next-level gaming experience, no matter the device or location.&#8221;</i><i></i></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 class="p4"><b>Tokenized ecosystem incentivizes GPU providers</b></h2>
<p class="p1">At the heart of DeepLink&#8217;s model is a tokenized economy centered around the DLC token. When users rent GPU resources to play games, they pay DLC tokens, which are then destroyed. GPU providers receive DLC rewards for contributing their computing power to the network.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-451376" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/image1.jpg" alt="" width="936" height="516" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/image1.jpg 936w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/image1-300x165.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/image1-768x423.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 936px) 100vw, 936px" /></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1"><i>&#8220;This pledging system gives us a level of certainty that traditional systems can&#8217;t match,&#8221; the spokesperson said. &#8220;We know exactly how much computing power we have available at any given time, and smart contracts automatically adjust rewards based on providers&#8217; performance.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">The spokesperson emphasized that this creates a mutually beneficial ecosystem: &#8220;Providers are incentivized to offer the best service possible, and gamers get a reliable, high-quality experience. It&#8217;s a win-win situation, all powered by the magic of blockchain and smart contracts.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="p2"><b>Benefits for gamers and GPU providers</b></h2>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-451379" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink-.jpg" alt="" width="1200" height="674" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink-.jpg 1200w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink--300x169.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink--1024x575.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink--768x431.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /></p>
<p class="p1">DeepLink&#8217;s decentralized approach offers several key advantages for both gamers and GPU providers:</p>
<p class="p1">For Gamers:</p>
<ul class="ul1">
<li class="li1">Lower Latency: The distributed network reduces lag and improves gameplay.</li>
<li class="li1">Device Flexibility: Gamers can access high-quality games on any device.</li>
<li class="li1">Cost-Effective: No need to invest in expensive gaming hardware.</li>
<li class="li1">Play-to-Earn Opportunities: Potential to earn rewards through gameplay.</li>
<li class="li1">Improved Game Selection: Access to a wider range of games.</li>
</ul>
<p class="p1">For GPU Providers:</p>
<ul class="ul1">
<li class="li1">Passive Income: Earn DLC token rewards for providing computing power.</li>
<li class="li1">Asset Utilization: Monetize idle GPU resources.</li>
<li class="li1">Low Entry Barrier: Participate in the cloud gaming market with minimal infrastructure.</li>
<li class="li3">Potential for Growth: As the network expands, rewards and token value may appreciate.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="p4"><b>Widespread adoption across 110+ countries</b></h2>
<p class="p1">DeepLink currently operates in over 110 countries, which has presented some challenges. As the spokesperson noted:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;Achieving such widespread adoption requires navigating different regulatory environments, infrastructure capabilities, and user preferences across various markets.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p4">One key initiative to drive adoption is DeepLink&#8217;s Orion GPU Race, a decentralized platform for renting and sharing GPU resources powered by blockchain. The spokesperson explained,</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p4">&#8220;This is a great opportunity for GPU Miners to earn extra rewards and maximize their computation power in this early mining stage.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 class="p5"><b>Addressing security in decentralized cloud gaming</b></h2>
<p class="p1">Security is a top priority for DeepLink, especially given the risks associated with decentralized systems. The spokesperson outlined several measures the platform has implemented:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;We&#8217;re using blockchain technology to create an immutable audit trail of all transactions and data transfers. This makes it incredibly difficult for anyone to tamper with the system without being detected. We&#8217;ve also implemented multi-layered security measures, including advanced encryption, a rigorous vetting process for node operators, and AI-driven continuous monitoring for suspicious activity.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p4">Additionally, DeepLink leverages zero-knowledge proof technology to ensure user privacy without compromising the integrity of the network.</p>
<h2 class="p5"><b>Future Plans: Expanding Game Library and Partnerships</b></h2>
<p class="p1">Looking ahead, DeepLink plans to continue expanding its game library, with a focus on partnering with traditional AAA game studios. The spokesperson highlighted this as a key priority:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;Currently, we have some of the hottest blockchain-based AAA games, and we plan on adding traditional AAA games by partnering with specific gaming companies and studios. This will allow us to bring high-quality, mainstream titles to our decentralized cloud gaming platform.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">By bridging the gap between blockchain-native and traditional gaming, <a href="https://www.deeplink.cloud/"><span class="s1">DeepLink</span></a> aims to offer users a comprehensive and compelling cloud gaming experience that leverages the benefits of decentralization, AI, and blockchain technology.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/deeplink-harnesses-blockchain-and-ai-to-reinvent-cloud-gaming/">DeepLink harnesses blockchain and AI to reinvent cloud gaming</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/deeplink-harnesses-blockchain-and-ai-to-reinvent-cloud-gaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink-cover.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/deeplink-cover.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEC crackdown continues with Immutable latest to receive Wells Notice</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-crackdown-continues-with-immutable-latest-to-receive-wells-notice/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-crackdown-continues-with-immutable-latest-to-receive-wells-notice/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 23:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The SEC has issued a Wells notice to blockchain gaming platform Immutable in what has become a widespread crackdown on crypto companies ahead of the US election. Immutable said in an Oct. 31 blog post that the move is the latest instance of the SEC&#8217;s &#8220;regulation-by-enforcement&#8221; policy targeting the crypto industry. It added that the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-crackdown-continues-with-immutable-latest-to-receive-wells-notice/">SEC crackdown continues with Immutable latest to receive Wells Notice</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The SEC has issued a Wells notice to blockchain gaming platform <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/immutable-x/">Immutable</a> in what has become a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/digital-chamber-slams-secs-robinhood-wells-notice/">widespread crackdown</a> on crypto companies ahead of the US election.</p>
<p>Immutable said in an Oct. 31 blog post that the move is the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-com-sues-sec-for-illegal-actions-in-crypto-regulation-following-wells-notice/">latest instance</a> of the SEC&#8217;s &#8220;regulation-by-enforcement&#8221; policy targeting the crypto industry. It added that the watchdog issued the notice without prior discussions</p>
<p>According to Immutable, the SEC&#8217;s allegations, though vague, appear to focus on the 2021 listing and private sales of its native token IMX. The network contends that the IMX token does not meet the criteria of a security and that the regulator&#8217;s actions bypass meaningful dialogue.</p>
<p>Immutable said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;To manufacture a case on a listing that occurred in 2021, with practically no direct communication with the company, is precisely the reason the industry is so skeptical of any attempts from this SEC to argue it is attempting to provide clarity.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Immutable&#8217;s statement indicated that the SEC&#8217;s allegations, though non-specific in the Wells notice, seem to center on potential securities law violations related to the listing and private sales of its IMX token in 2021.</p>
<p>The company expressed frustration that the SEC&#8217;s notice contained only limited detail — fewer than 20 words of substantive explanation — and lacked a clear basis for the investigation.</p>
<p>Additionally, Immutable suggested that the SEC&#8217;s allegations implied inaccurate claims of &#8220;fraudulent misrepresentations&#8221; tied to a 2021 blog post about the IMX token&#8217;s pre-launch investment pricing.</p>
<p>The company argued that the regulator mischaracterized this information, stating that there was indeed &#8220;real consideration&#8221; involved in the investment, which the agency could have clarified had it engaged in constructive dialogue with Immutable before issuing the notice.</p>
<p>Immutable said it is prepared to &#8220;defend the rights of builders, creators, and gamers,&#8221; with its considerable war chest and extensive resources. It added that its commitment to the industry is clear and it will &#8220;keep building&#8221; regardless of the regulatory challenges.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-crackdown-continues-with-immutable-latest-to-receive-wells-notice/">SEC crackdown continues with Immutable latest to receive Wells Notice</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-crackdown-continues-with-immutable-latest-to-receive-wells-notice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/sec-wells-notice-defi.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/sec-wells-notice-defi.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GameFi set to leap to $301 billion by 2030 with real-world rewards – Nansen</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/gamefi-set-to-leap-to-301-billion-by-2030-with-real-world-rewards-nansen/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/gamefi-set-to-leap-to-301-billion-by-2030-with-real-world-rewards-nansen/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The blockchain gaming (GameFi) ecosystem is entering a pivotal phase of growth and is expected to hit a market cap of $301.5 billion by 2030, according to a recent report by blockchain analytics firm Nansen. The report said that growth will be driven by the decentralized ownership of in-game assets like fungible and non-fungible tokens [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gamefi-set-to-leap-to-301-billion-by-2030-with-real-world-rewards-nansen/">GameFi set to leap to $301 billion by 2030 with real-world rewards – Nansen</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The blockchain gaming (GameFi) ecosystem is entering a pivotal phase of growth and is expected to hit a market cap of $301.5 billion by 2030, according to a <a href="https://research.nansen.ai/articles/future-of-gamefi-in-web3">recent report</a> by blockchain analytics firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/nansen/">Nansen</a>.</p>
<p>The report said that growth will be driven by the decentralized ownership of in-game assets like fungible and non-fungible tokens (NFT). It added that implementing tokens offers real-world value and financial incentives that traditional gaming platforms cannot match.</p>
<p>As a result, Nansen estimates the sector will experience a compound annual growth rate (CAGR) of 68% over the next six years.</p>
<p>The report noted that, despite the broader crypto market&#8217;s volatility, the GameFi sector showed resilience in August 2024, with daily active wallets rising by 8.94%.</p>
<p>Blockchain infrastructure improvements — such as increased transaction capacity, lower gas fees, and better scalability — are helping GameFi projects thrive.</p>
<p>Moreover, leading blockchain networks like opBNB, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ronin/">Ronin</a>, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/immutable-x/">Immutable</a> are gaining attention due to their balance of speed, cost-effectiveness, and scalability, which are attracting developers and gamers alike.</p>
<h2>True ownership</h2>
<p>GameFi&#8217;s unique value proposition, where players have true ownership of in-game assets, is revolutionizing the gaming landscape. This decentralized structure contrasts with traditional gaming ecosystems, where the value of in-game achievements remains locked within the platform.</p>
<p>Role-playing games (RPGs) are particularly well-suited to the decentralized model, as they allow players to own and trade rare in-game items as NFTs. RPGs currently account for 22% of all web3 games, making them the most popular genre in the space, followed by action games at 17%.</p>
<p>The GameFi sector is also witnessing a rise in high-quality titles, labeled as AAA games, which boast high production value and immersive gameplay.</p>
<p>Although AAA titles account for just 1% of Web3 games today, they are outpacing their traditional Web2 counterparts in growth, signaling a shift in investment toward blockchain-based gaming.</p>
<p>Notably, GameFi is the crypto sector with the fourth-largest amount raised from venture capital funds, with over $651 million directed at this industry, according to Rootdata <a href="https://www.rootdata.com/dashboard">numbers</a>.</p>
<h2>Importance of community</h2>
<p>Nansen&#8217;s report highlighted games like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/illuvium/">Illuvium</a>, Axie Infinity, and Seraph as prime examples of Web3 gaming innovation. These games combine high-quality gameplay with decentralized economic systems, offering players real-world financial rewards.</p>
<p>The report added that Axie Infinity popularized the ‘play-to-earn’ model, allowing users to generate income through gameplay. Illuvium and Seraph stand out for their visually immersive environments and robust NFT economies.</p>
<p>The success of these games is driven by their in-game economies. Axie Infinity uses a dual-token system — Smooth Love Potion (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/smooth-love-potion/">SLP</a>) for gameplay rewards and Axie Infinity Shards (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/axie-infinity/">AXS</a>) for governance — while Illuvium and Seraph integrate NFTs to enhance gameplay and player engagement.</p>
<p>In addition to gameplay, the report pointed out that social engagement plays a crucial role in Web3 gaming success. Platforms like X, Discord, and Telegram are essential tools for building and maintaining active communities.</p>
<p>Axie Infinity and Seraph lead the pack with strong community engagement, evidenced by their large followings and rapid growth across social platforms.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gamefi-set-to-leap-to-301-billion-by-2030-with-real-world-rewards-nansen/">GameFi set to leap to $301 billion by 2030 with real-world rewards – Nansen</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/gamefi-set-to-leap-to-301-billion-by-2030-with-real-world-rewards-nansen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/blockchain-gaming.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/blockchain-gaming.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GAM3 Awards 2024 finalists revealed including Epic Games Store smash hit Off The Grid</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=448179</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The GAM3 Awards 2024 has revealed its final shortlist for a $5 million prize pool. Returning for its third year, the annual web3 gaming event will, for the first time, feature a physical ceremony held in the Philippines in partnership with Yield Guild Games (YGG). The event serves as the grand finale for the YGG [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/">GAM3 Awards 2024 finalists revealed including Epic Games Store smash hit Off The Grid</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">The GAM3 Awards 2024 has revealed its final shortlist for a $5 million prize pool. Returning for its third year, the annual web3 gaming event will, for the first time, feature a physical ceremony held in the Philippines in partnership with Yield Guild Games (YGG).</p>
<p class="p1">The event serves as the grand finale for the YGG Play Summit, highlighting the Philippines&#8217; significant role in the web3 gaming landscape. YGG Co-Founder Gabby Dizon stated,</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">“The YGG Play Summit is about the gamers, first and foremost. It’s the biggest web3 gaming consumer event of the year. This is why we’re so excited to host the 2024 GAM3 Awards here in Manila. The real players of all the hottest web3 games will be there to vote and cheer for their favorite titles.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">GAM3S.GG has also partnered with Arbitrum, Magic Eden, Immutable, Avalanche, and Skale to enhance this year&#8217;s event. Since its inception in 2022, the GAM3 Awards have become a landmark in the blockchain gaming industry, recognizing top games and creators. The awards celebrate innovation across various genres and criteria, such as art direction and the most anticipated games.</p>
<p class="p1">In <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/parallel-dominates-gam3-awards-with-triple-win-including-game-of-the-year/">2023</a>, the event saw over 450,000 votes cast from 50,000 unique voters. The ceremony was streamed online, attracting over 50,000 live viewers and peaking at more than 36,000 concurrent viewers on Twitch. Winners shared a prize pool of $2 million, with the web3 trading card game Parallel taking multiple awards, including &#8220;Game of the Year.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">GAM3S.GG Co-Founder and CEO Omar Ghanem remarked,</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">“This is the third year we run these awards, and we really wanted to do something special this time. The Philippines has long been one of the main hubs for web3 gaming, and some of the earliest adopters and most passionate community members are based right here.</p>
<p class="p1">That’s why it only feels right that our first ever physical version of the GAM3 Awards takes place at the heart of Manila—the heart of web3 gaming.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">This year&#8217;s awards include all categories from the previous edition and introduce two new ones: Best Ecosystem and Best Browser Game, bringing the total to 21 categories. The &#8220;Best Graphics&#8221; award returns under the new title &#8220;Best Art Direction&#8221; to honor creativity and unique art styles without overemphasizing high-fidelity graphics.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-448181" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/12.png" alt="" width="512" height="288" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/12.png 512w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/12-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></p>
<p class="p1">The GAM3 Awards will feature exclusive trailers and announcements from leading studios, offering attendees a preview of some of the most anticipated web3 games in development. These premieres have become fan favorites, with titles like Riftstorm debuting in previous editions.</p>
<p class="p1">Over 70 prominent figures from traditional and blockchain gaming will participate, including representatives from Amazon, Google, Samsung, Ubisoft, Animoca Brands, Immutable, Arbitrum, Blockchain Game Alliance, Base, Ronin, and Avalanche.</p>
<p class="p1">For most categories, the voting process assigns 90% of the final decision to the jury and 10% to the community, except for People&#8217;s Choice and Best Content Creator, which are entirely community-based. Shortlisted game studios voting for their favorite title determines the Games&#8217; Choice award.</p>
<p class="p1">The nominees include seventeen blockchain networks, highlighting the industry&#8217;s diversity and innovation. The top five networks in the final shortlists are Immutable, Polygon, Avalanche, Arbitrum, and Solana.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-448180" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/11.png" alt="" width="512" height="288" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/11.png 512w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/11-300x169.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 512px) 100vw, 512px" /></p>
<p class="p1">The Game of the Year finalists are <a href="https://store.epicgames.com/en-US/collection/most-played">Off The Grid</a>, Pirate Nation, Parallel, Nyan Heroes, and Pixels. Voting begins on Oct. 15 and runs until Nov. 15 on GAM3S. GG&#8217;s platform. For the complete list of nominees, visit <a href="http://gam3awards.com">gam3awards.com</a>.</p>
<p class="p1">This year&#8217;s prize pool has increased to $5 million, including grants, products, services, marketing, and blockchain support from partners such as AWS, XAI, Thirdweb, Aethir, and Community Gaming. This substantial increase highlights the event&#8217;s commitment to supporting the next generation of web3 games.</p>
<p class="p1">The GAM3 Awards 2024 aims to be the most significant event in web3 gaming to date. Attendees can look forward to exclusive content, major announcements, entertainment performances, and celebrating the creativity defining web3 gaming. The event is scheduled for Nov. 22.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/">GAM3 Awards 2024 finalists revealed including Epic Games Store smash hit Off The Grid</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/gam3-awards.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/gam3-awards.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GameFi&#8217;s next boom: How TON-based games and crypto airdrops are attracting millions of users</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/gamefis-next-boom-how-ton-based-games-and-crypto-airdrops-are-attracting-millions-of-users/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/gamefis-next-boom-how-ton-based-games-and-crypto-airdrops-are-attracting-millions-of-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Yaniv Baruch]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 16:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airdrop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TON blockchain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=446658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post from Yaniv Baruch, COO at Playnance. Blockchain gaming recently hit a record high of 4.2 million daily active users, according to a DappRadar report. The GameFi industry is seeing an unprecedented surge in new users. However, this growth is somewhat overshadowed by buzzier trends like AI and memecoins. Three [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gamefis-next-boom-how-ton-based-games-and-crypto-airdrops-are-attracting-millions-of-users/">GameFi&#8217;s next boom: How TON-based games and crypto airdrops are attracting millions of users</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest post from Yaniv Baruch, COO at Playnance.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Blockchain gaming recently hit a record high of 4.2 million daily active users, according to a </span><strong><a href="https://dappradar.com/blog/blockchain-gaming-reaches-new-record-4-2-million-daily-active-users">DappRadar report</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The GameFi industry is seeing an unprecedented surge in new users. However, this growth is somewhat overshadowed by buzzier trends like <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/ai">AI</a> and <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/meme">memecoins</a>. Three key factors drive the influx of users: advancements in crypto products (including TON ecosystem developments), airdrops, and broader technological progress in the crypto space.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These factors helped attract – and, most importantly, retain – this massive user base, setting the stage for a new GameFi boom by 2025.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Transforming Tomorrow With TON</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Telegram’s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/toncoin/">TON</a> (The Open Network) is fast, scalable, and charges minimal fees, making it an ideal blockchain for gaming. After all, gaming networks need to process player interactions in real time to ensure a smooth experience. Any delays can frustrate players and lead to them abandoning the game.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">TON’s capabilities allow for more advanced gaming experiences, like Catizen and TapSwap, and its integration into the Telegram app makes it one of the most accessible gaming networks out there. This isn&#8217;t just speculation &#8211; it&#8217;s a fact, proven by over 239 million players in Hamster Kombat, 21 million in Catizen, and over 60 million users of Tapswap. The figure is impressive for standard blockchain-based games and even Web2 video games. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The crucial role of TON for the coming GameFi boom next year is that the majority of this audience, according to the </span><strong><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/hamster-kombat-web3-gaming-adoption">developers</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> themselves, is completely new to the cryptocurrency industry. After gaining their first Web3 gaming experience or airdrops in these and other Dapps, some of them will eventually turn to other GameFi products and other blockchain ecosystems. </span></p>
<h2><strong>Crypto Airdrops: A Double-Edged Necessity </strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to TON’s growing GameFi audience, airdrops play a key role. They distribute in-game tokens to newer players, allowing them to explore a game’s capabilities without investing.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/hamster-kombat/">Hamster Kombat</a>, the TON network&#8217;s most successful tap-to-play game, held an airdrop alongside its HMSTR token launch on September 26th for its 131 million eligible users. Players have been enjoying the game&#8217;s first season of content for the past few months, and rewards were paid out based on player activity and other criteria.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This method incentivizes players to log in and level up every day, complete quests, finish limited-time activities, and boost the game’s daily active player base. The promise of a payout based on performance also encourages players to share the game with their friends, further increasing the player count. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While crypto airdrops have their downsides – such as “airdrop farmers” who hop from game to game to collect tokens and sell them off without investing in the game – these challenges are outweighed by the benefits. Despite the fact that 88% of tokens launched alongside airdrops this year have declined in price, the overall advantages of airdrops remain significant.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">They kickstart a game’s community and draw in a dedicated group of gamers encouraged by the initial free funds. That group will then spread the word and attract more players, strengthening its fanbase while bringing in a GameFi product performance. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This increases awareness of the project&#8217;s token, potentially increasing its value and rewarding early adopters. When done properly, with fair and thoughtful token distribution to loyal users, the user airdrop mechanism creates a cycle of awareness, participation, and rewards. This mechanic has helped many projects rise during the bear market, and it will create even more traction for the upcoming GameFi boom soon.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Maintaining Steady Momentum</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As is the case with several Web3 sectors, GameFi is currently experiencing an uptick in users. However, keeping players involved in a game is equally, if not more, important. To create another GameFi boom next year, developers need to harness the best practices of new technologies, projects and ecosystems like TON to create new, meaningful, and seamless gaming experiences for their players (in this case, recent developments in L3, zero-gas and Account Abstraction-based solutions have made great strides).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Approaching Web3 game development with these goals in mind will encourage developers to attract players and earn from their gaming efforts, but a good gaming experience ties the player to it on an emotional level. That strong tie then prompts them to stick with a game beyond its financial benefits. A meaningful experience will also invite them to tell their friends and get other players involved, ultimately benefiting the GameFi ecosystem as a whole.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That said, we’re still waiting on the emergence of a dominating force – akin to Clash of Clans or Candy Crush in Web2 several years before – that will finally redefine the current GameFi market state. We’re all waiting for an experience that will capture the minds (and hands!) of the millions playing modern blockchain-based games. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Striking the right balance between play-to-earn models and fun gameplay ensures that players stay engaged even as financial rewards fluctuate. Together, these gaming experiences will keep users in the industry for the long haul. With the recent $1.4BN of </span><a href="https://dappradar.com/blog/state-of-blockchain-gaming-in-q2-2024/#Chapter-4"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>investments</strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in the GameFi industry in H1 2024, the records of daily active users this year, and the wave of absolutely new users attracted by GameFi projects on TON, we will definitely see a new GameFi industry boom in 2025.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By that time, we’re bound to see new technologies and game mechanics come to light. Developers must then apply the previous concepts to these new ideas to create even better experiences for their players. These factors could fuel a new GameFi boom in 2025 as technologies and game mechanics mature. </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gamefis-next-boom-how-ton-based-games-and-crypto-airdrops-are-attracting-millions-of-users/">GameFi&#8217;s next boom: How TON-based games and crypto airdrops are attracting millions of users</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/gamefis-next-boom-how-ton-based-games-and-crypto-airdrops-are-attracting-millions-of-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/telegram-ton-gamefi.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/telegram-ton-gamefi.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto startups secure $691 million in venture capital during September</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-startups-secure-691-million-in-venture-capital-during-september/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-startups-secure-691-million-in-venture-capital-during-september/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 22:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=446603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Venture capital (VC) funds invested over $659 million in crypto startups last month, representing a 3% increase compared to August, according to DefiLlama data. The blockchain gaming sector grew for the second consecutive month, with VC funds pouring $63 million into blockchain titles, marking a 32% monthly growth. Nearly half of the money raised by [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-startups-secure-691-million-in-venture-capital-during-september/">Crypto startups secure $691 million in venture capital during September</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Venture capital (VC) funds invested over $659 million in crypto startups last month, representing a 3% increase compared to August, according to DefiLlama <a href="https://defillama.com/raises">data</a>.</p>
<p>The blockchain gaming sector grew for the second consecutive month, with VC funds pouring $63 million into blockchain titles, marking a 32% monthly growth.</p>
<p>Nearly half of the money raised by blockchain gaming startups was directed at Balance Games. The project received $30 million from companies such as Animoca, a16z, Aptos Labs, and DWF Labs to combine blockchain and artificial intelligence to create more enjoyable user experiences.</p>
<h2>Infrastructure</h2>
<p>Projects building blockchain infrastructure received $457 million in September, dominating 71.5% of the funds received by the whole crypto ecosystem in the period. This is virtually the same amount captured by the sector in August.</p>
<p>Celestia (TIA) raised $100 million through a &#8220;strategic&#8221; funding round, the largest among infrastructure startups. The round was led by Bain Capital Crypto and included participation from 1kx, Robot Ventures, Syncracy Capital, and Placeholder.</p>
<p>Additionally, Huma Finance raised $38 million to develop its blockchain-based payment network in a round that included participation from Fenbushi Capital, HashKey Capital, and ParaFi Capital.</p>
<h2>DeFi funding declines</h2>
<p>Despite the stability in blockchain infrastructure-related investments, DeFi ecosystem startups received $58 million last month, down 55% from August.</p>
<p>Drift led the largest DeFi funding round, securing $25 million in a Series B round led by Multicoin Capital. The second-largest investment round by DeFi startups was led by Puffpaw, a &#8220;vape-to-earn&#8221; application developed on Berachain.</p>
<p>Web3 adoption received a boost last month, with $59 million directed toward startups building blockchain-based versions of traditional services.</p>
<p>Tune.fm, a decentralized music streaming platform similar to Spotify, raised $50 million during the month from Global Emerging Markets Group.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-startups-secure-691-million-in-venture-capital-during-september/">Crypto startups secure $691 million in venture capital during September</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-startups-secure-691-million-in-venture-capital-during-september/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/stablecoin-investment.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/stablecoin-investment.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance to launch Moonbix play-to-earn game as Telegram Mini App</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-launch-moonbix-play-to-earn-game-on-telegram-mini-app/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-launch-moonbix-play-to-earn-game-on-telegram-mini-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 10:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=444164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Binance has announced the upcoming release of &#8220;Moonbix,&#8221; a new play-to-earn (P2E) game on Telegram&#8217;s Mini App, according to a Sept. 17 post on X. Moonbix is a Binance crypto-themed game that lets players explore galaxies, collect items, and boost their scores. In videos shared on X, users can be seen controlling a spaceship equipped [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-launch-moonbix-play-to-earn-game-on-telegram-mini-app/">Binance to launch Moonbix play-to-earn game as Telegram Mini App</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> has announced the upcoming release of &#8220;Moonbix,&#8221; a new play-to-earn (P2E) game on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/telegram/">Telegram&#8217;s</a> Mini App, according to a Sept. 17 post on X.</p>
<p>Moonbix is a Binance crypto-themed game that lets players explore galaxies, collect items, and boost their scores. In <a href="https://x.com/kriptobiwan/status/1836116183869010271">videos</a> shared on X, users can be seen controlling a spaceship equipped with a claw-like tool that allows them to collect items like yellow stones and gifts scattered across the galaxy.</p>
<p>These items hold in-game value, and collecting them helps players climb the leaderboard. Based on their progress, top performers earn crypto rewards.</p>
<p>Binance stated that the game leaked ahead of schedule as the application was still being fine-tuned to deliver the best possible experience upon the official launch. It added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We apologize for any inconvenience, and we&#8217;re reviewing individual cases for users affected. We truly appreciate your patience, and the official release will be announced soon!&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The exchange also urged users to remain cautious of impersonation accounts and advised them to rely on official Binance channels for updates.</p>
<p>As of press time, Binance had released the Terms and Conditions for its Telegram Mini App.</p>
<h2>Telegram Mini Apps</h2>
<p>Telegram Mini Apps (TMAs) are web-based applications running within Telegram, introduced in 2023. Since then, TMAs have seen huge success, with 500 million of Telegram&#8217;s 950 million users engaging with them monthly.</p>
<p>Popular apps like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/notcoin-donates-7-million-in-tokens-to-telegram-and-its-founder-pavel-durov/">Notcoin</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/telegram-based-web3-game-hamster-kombat-draws-irani-generals-ire-amid-rising-local-player-base/">Hamster Kombat</a> have contributed to this surge. Hamster Kombat, in particular, snowballed, gaining over 300 million users since its launch in March 2024.</p>
<p>The rise of these apps has further supported crypto adoption, aided by Telegram&#8217;s integration with The Open Network (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/toncoin/">TON</a>), one of the top-performing blockchains this year.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-launch-moonbix-play-to-earn-game-on-telegram-mini-app/">Binance to launch Moonbix play-to-earn game as Telegram Mini App</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-launch-moonbix-play-to-earn-game-on-telegram-mini-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/moon-minigame.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/moon-minigame.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain gaming sets new record with 4.2 million daily active users in August</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-gaming-sets-new-record-with-4-2-million-daily-active-users-in-august/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-gaming-sets-new-record-with-4-2-million-daily-active-users-in-august/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 19:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=443671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain gaming has reached a new milestone with 4.2 million daily active users in August, according to a recent DappRadar report. The web3 gaming industry saw a 5% increase in daily unique active wallets (dUAW) last month despite falling to second place in terms of the most active crypto sector amid the AI boom. Ronin keeps its [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-gaming-sets-new-record-with-4-2-million-daily-active-users-in-august/">Blockchain gaming sets new record with 4.2 million daily active users in August</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain gaming has reached a new milestone with <a href="https://dappradar.com/blog/blockchain-gaming-reaches-new-record-4-2-million-daily-active-users">4.2 million</a> daily active users in August, according to a recent <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/dappradar/">DappRadar</a> report.</p>
<p>The web3 gaming industry saw a 5% increase in daily unique active wallets (dUAW) last month despite falling to second place in terms of the most active crypto sector amid the AI boom.</p>
<h2>Ronin keeps its dominance</h2>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ronin/">Ronin</a> continues to dominate the blockchain gaming landscape with the highest average number of Unique Active Wallets (UAW), which grew 24% in August to 1.32 million. <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pixels/">Pixels</a> and Forgotten Runiverse were the main games driving activity on the network during the month.</p>
<p>The second most active network was opBNB with 688,000 UAW during the period. The network experienced a 50% growth in active users, thanks to the game &#8220;SERAPH: In the Darkness” and the mobile games platform Gomble Games.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/skale-network/">SKALE Network</a> rounded out the top three most active blockchains for web3 gaming in August, recording a 10% growth during the month to hit 352,000 UAW on the back of games like motoDEX and World of Dypians.</p>
<h2>Multichain ecosystem captures users</h2>
<p>KGeN emerged as the leading gaming application last month, achieving over 2.3 million UAW. KGeN is a gaming ecosystem based on nine different blockchains that offers rewards and gamified quests for its users.</p>
<p>Immutable-based mobile title BoomLand recorded the second-largest number of active users during the month, gathering nearly 1.9 million UAW. Meanwhile, Pixels wrapped up the trio of most played games in August with 1.34 million UAW.</p>
<p>Additionally, the report highlighted the completion of the closed beta test phase of the MMORPG Lumiterra on Ronin. The game, which included a $1 million prize pool, reported a player retention rate of over 80% during the first seven days of the test and a total UAW of 728,000 UAW in August.</p>
<h2>Nearly $580 million invested</h2>
<p>Blockchain gaming is the crypto industry sector with the fifth-largest amount of capital raised from venture capital (VC) funds in 2024, <a href="https://www.rootdata.com/dashboard">according</a> to RootData.</p>
<p>The gaming sector has captured nearly $580 million in investments so far, close to the $583 million gathered by centralized crypto platforms.</p>
<p>Notably, the amount raised by projects in the blockchain gaming industry this year is less than $100 million shy of the total $664 million raised last year.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-gaming-sets-new-record-with-4-2-million-daily-active-users-in-august/">Blockchain gaming sets new record with 4.2 million daily active users in August</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/blockchain-gaming-sets-new-record-with-4-2-million-daily-active-users-in-august/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/blockchain-gaming.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/blockchain-gaming.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
