<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Web3 News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/web3/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/web3/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:36:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Web3 News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/web3/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Web3 Meets Black Friday: Changelly Embraces Holiday Shopping Season with Crypto Offers</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/web3-meets-black-friday-changelly-embraces-holiday-shopping-season-with-crypto-offers/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/web3-meets-black-friday-changelly-embraces-holiday-shopping-season-with-crypto-offers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Desk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 13:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sponsored]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As the holiday shopping season kicks off, the Web3 world is embracing its own version of the Black Friday fever. While traditional retailers prepare their doorbusters and digital deals, Web3 platforms and crypto companies are reimagining seasonal shopping. According to Adobe Analytics, U.S. holiday sales in 2024 are projected to reach $1 trillion, including pre-Thanksgiving [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/web3-meets-black-friday-changelly-embraces-holiday-shopping-season-with-crypto-offers/">Web3 Meets Black Friday: Changelly Embraces Holiday Shopping Season with Crypto Offers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">As the holiday shopping season kicks off, the Web3 world is embracing its own version of the Black Friday fever. While traditional retailers prepare their doorbusters and digital deals, Web3 platforms and crypto companies are reimagining seasonal shopping.</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1"><a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/u-consumers-holiday-spending-spree-221939712.html">According to Adobe Analytics</a></span>, U.S. holiday sales in 2024 are projected to reach $1 trillion, including pre-Thanksgiving purchases, with online spending expected to hit $240.8 billion—a 12% increase from 2023. Meanwhile, Donald Trump&#8217;s victory in the U.S. presidential election in early November has significantly impacted cryptocurrency markets, driving crypto demand across both new and existing users, as evidenced by the market surge.</p>
<p class="p1">Blockchain is transforming traditional holiday bargain hunting into a digital adventure, where smart contracts replace shopping carts and digital assets become the season&#8217;s must-have items. One such initiative comes from market veteran Changelly, a global instant crypto exchange that has operated since 2015 and serves millions of users and hundreds of partners.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Strategic Partnership that Brings Big Discounts</h2>
<p class="p1">The <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/partnership/changelly-black-friday/?utm_campaign=bf_24&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_source=cryptoslate"><span class="s1">Black Friday campaign</span></a> developed by Changelly in collaboration with Topper by Uphold introduces a number of user-centric offers, aiming to boost mass adoption and make crypto more accessible to users during the holiday shopping season. Most notably, transactions exceeding $500 qualify for special rates using the promo code BF2024, potentially saving users up to $1,000 on fees and positioning Changelly as one of the most cost-effective instant exchange platforms in the market during this holiday season.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Reducing Barriers to Entry</h2>
<p class="p1">Through its partnership with Topper by Uphold, Changelly is offering a 50% reduction on processing fees for cryptocurrency purchases. Users can access this discount using the promo code BUY2024, significantly lowering the barrier to entry for those interested in digital assets.</p>
<p class="p3">“Changelly has a knack for identifying amazing milestones in the industry and celebrating them. Topper is thrilled to partner with Changelly again on an exciting promotion for their existing community and newcomers, especially at a time when there’s a lot of enthusiasm for the crypto market.”—Robin O’Connell, CEO at Uphold Enterprise, commented.</p>
<p class="p3">Zifa Mae, Head of Product at Changelly, highlighted this campaign&#8217;s festive and revolutionizing nature: &#8220;This Black Friday, we&#8217;re not just slashing prices—we&#8217;re redefining the crypto landscape with tailored offers for this holiday season. Our platform is becoming a crucible where market volatility meets opportunity, allowing both seasoned traders and crypto-curious individuals to forge their financial futures. We&#8217;re not merely facilitating transactions; we&#8217;re catalyzing a shift in how people perceive and interact with digital assets during this high-stakes period.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="p2">User Rewards and Engagement</h2>
<p class="p1">To encourage user participation, Changelly has launched a giveaway with a total prize pool of $5,000. Users who register on the platform and complete any transactions at floating rates are automatically entered into the draw, with five winners to be selected in total. This reward system adds a game-like element to the traditional holiday shopping experience.</p>
<h2 class="p2">Save and Win BIG</h2>
<p class="p4">To match the excitement of traditional Black Friday celebrations, Changelly partnered with various notable companies and projects from the cryptocurrency sphere.</p>
<p class="p4">In addition to the strategic partnership with Topper by Uphold, the campaign also features industry leaders such as MoonPay, Tangem, HAQQ, Ellipal, CoolWallet, and ZenGo. Together, Changelly and its partners are bringing users a celebration packed with opportunities to save and win big on crypto swaps and purchases during one of the most significant crypto bull runs in recent years.</p>
<p class="p6">Learn more about all offers and rules of the Changelly Black Friday campaign <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/partnership/changelly-black-friday/?utm_campaign=bf_24&amp;utm_medium=pr&amp;utm_source=cryptoslate"><span class="s1">here</span></a>.</p>
<h2 class="p7">Looking Ahead</h2>
<p class="p1">This transformation of traditional holiday commerce into the digital realm represents a broader shift in consumer behavior, where blockchain technology facilitates new forms of value exchange. Moreover, the integration of holiday shopping traditions with Web3-native companies signals a maturing digital asset ecosystem.</p>
<p class="p1">As a veteran of the crypto market, Changelly provides its users with comprehensive, cost-efficient offerings and user-friendly interfaces, driving mass adoption and lowering the entry barrier to crypto. Founded in 2015, Changelly offers crypto-to-crypto and fiat-to-crypto exchanges of over 700 digital assets with 24/7 live customer support. As a CeDeFi ecosystem, Changelly provides its B2B partners with instant exchange and fiat on-/off-ramp APIs, a platform for listing, and a DEX aggregator for decentralized swaps.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/web3-meets-black-friday-changelly-embraces-holiday-shopping-season-with-crypto-offers/">Web3 Meets Black Friday: Changelly Embraces Holiday Shopping Season with Crypto Offers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/web3-meets-black-friday-changelly-embraces-holiday-shopping-season-with-crypto-offers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/changelly-pr-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/changelly-pr-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Epic Games hit Off The Grid wins Game of the Year at first live 2024 GAM3 Awards</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 09:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455030</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Off The Grid secured the Game of the Year award at the 2024 GAM3 Awards, held live for the first time in Manila on Nov.22. Developed by Gunzilla Games, the Web3-enabled, free-to-play, third-person battle royale game also won awards for Best Shooter Game, Best Multiplayer Game, and Best Action Game, marking a significant achievement in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/">Epic Games hit Off The Grid wins Game of the Year at first live 2024 GAM3 Awards</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Off The Grid secured the Game of the Year award at the 2024 GAM3 Awards, held live for the first time in Manila on Nov.22.</p>
<p>Developed by Gunzilla Games, the Web3-enabled, free-to-play, third-person battle royale game also won awards for Best Shooter Game, Best Multiplayer Game, and Best Action Game, marking a significant achievement in the blockchain gaming industry.</p>
<p>Hosted in partnership with Yield Guild Games (YGG), the GAM3 Awards recognized excellence across 21 categories, celebrating the progress of the Web3 gaming sector over the past year. The event featured an increased prize pool of $5 million, comprising grants, products, services, marketing, and blockchain support from partners such as AWS, XAI, Thirdweb, Aethir, and Community Gaming.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455031" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455031" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-455031 size-large" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-1024x569.jpg" alt="Gam3 Awards (Source:gam3s.gg)" width="1024" height="569" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-1024x569.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-300x167.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-768x426.jpg 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards-1536x853.jpg 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3s-awards.jpg 1758w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455031" class="wp-caption-text">Gam3 Awards (Source:gam3s.gg)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The selection process involved over 70 jurors from prominent gaming and blockchain organizations, including representatives from <em>CryptoSlate</em>, Amazon, Google, Ubisoft, Animoca Brands, Immutable, Arbitrum, Blockchain Game Alliance, Base, Ronin, and Avalanche. Community engagement was significant, with over one million votes from 143,000 unique voters contributing to the final decisions in several categories.</p>
<p>Off The Grid&#8217;s success reflects the growing integration of blockchain technology in gaming. Set in a dystopian cyberpunk future on Teardrop Island, the game incorporates blockchain elements through the GUNZ blockchain using an Avalanche subnet, offering a player-driven economy with tradable in-game assets.</p>
<p>Off The Grid&#8217;s early access release <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">achieved</a> rapid growth, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gam3-awards-2024-finalists-revealed-including-epic-games-store-smash-hit-off-the-grid/">topping</a> Epic Games&#8217; free-to-play PC games list and surpassing popular titles like Fortnite and Rocket League. In its first five days, the game grew by more than one million wallets per day, accumulating 53 million transactions.</p>
<p>Other notable winners at the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/parallel-dominates-gam3-awards-with-triple-win-including-game-of-the-year/">GAM3 Awards</a> include Parallel, which claimed awards for Best Strategy Game, Best Card Game, and Best Esports Game. Pixels and Pirate Nation each took home two awards, further highlighting the diversity and innovation within the Web3 gaming space.</p>
<p>With over 300 in-person attendees, the event featured gameplay premieres and exclusive trailers from upcoming titles such as Golden Tides, Unfettered, Elumia, Providence, Shrapnel, and more. The ceremony reached a peak viewership of 48,000 concurrent viewers, amassing over 450,000 views in the first 24 hours.</p>
<p>The success of Off The Grid and the GAM3 Awards illustrates the increasing acceptance and integration of blockchain technology in mainstream gaming. Analysts <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">speculate</a> that Off The Grid could be a catalyst for a new crypto gaming bull run, potentially becoming as significant as Axie Infinity was in previous cycles.</p>
<p>The GAM3 Awards are expected to return next November for their fourth consecutive edition, signaling ongoing recognition of excellence in Web3 gaming.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/">Epic Games hit Off The Grid wins Game of the Year at first live 2024 GAM3 Awards</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/epic-games-hit-off-the-grid-wins-game-of-the-year-at-first-live-2024-gam3-awards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3-awards-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/gam3-awards-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The gaming lesson from Off The Grid and Telegram? Put blockchain in the background</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Leo Li]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 06:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post from Leo Li, Chief Growth Officer at CARV. Off The Grid could be the mainstream moment we&#8217;ve been waiting for in web3 gaming – not because it flaunts blockchain features, but because it doesn&#8217;t. The major console release integrates NFTs and blockchain in the background, letting gameplay take center [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">The gaming lesson from Off The Grid and Telegram? Put blockchain in the background</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest post from Leo Li, Chief Growth Officer at CARV.</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Off The Grid could be the mainstream moment we&#8217;ve been waiting for in web3 gaming – not because it flaunts blockchain features, but because it doesn&#8217;t. The major console release integrates NFTs and blockchain in the background, letting gameplay take center stage. The game is the main appeal, while the blockchain is a bonus that furthers trading, ownership, and expression.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Much like Telegram, which is quietly slipping crypto wallet functionality into hundreds of millions of pockets, game developers realize that simplicity is vital. Hitting gamers over the head with painful onboarding and crypto-heavy concepts can alienate potential players. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The next gaming bull run will not be driven by </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gaming/">blockchain games</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">—it will be driven by great games that happen to use blockchain.</span></p>
<h2><b>The quiet revolution in blockchain gaming</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Off The Grid is causing a lot of noise for a game that&#8217;s not officially out yet. The cyberpunk battle royale from Gunzilla Games – only available via early access on PC, PlayStation 5, and Xbox Series X – is getting plenty of attention for its tongue-in-cheek violence and gritty visuals from filmmaker Neill Blomkamp (District 9, Elysium). </span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“Part schlocky satire of streaming culture, part sendup of gamers, all shrewd self-aware storytelling: Off The Grid is a fun time,” </strong><a href="https://www.cnet.com/tech/gaming/why-you-should-be-playing-off-the-grid-a-new-battle-royale-right-now/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">CNET wrote in October.</span></a></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s a fun time, indeed, that&#8217;s entirely on the blockchain. Blink, and you might miss it, but Off The Grid is a native web3 title built upon an Avalanche subnet. This enables crypto capabilities alongside gameplay, including a forthcoming token and the NFT minting and trading of in-game weapons and skins on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/opensea/">OpenSea</a>. The best part? So far, players aren&#8217;t obligated to engage with these features. The blockchain and the game are separate yet complementary, with the former intended to enhance the latter rather than override it.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&#8217;s a similar story over on Telegram. Players are flocking to the simplicity and engagement of clicker games inside the chat platform. Thanks to endorsing <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/telegram-open-network/">The Open Network (TON)</a> as its official web3 infrastructure and integrating wallet functionality, Telegram makes it easy for gamers to embrace crypto without knowing it. Gone are complicated onboarding and clunky interfaces. Telegram&#8217;s mini-app gaming occurs automatically inside the known and trusted chat platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The successes are impressive across the board. TON clicker <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/notcoin/">Notcoin</a> and its eponymous token rose to a market cap of more than half a billion dollars, and BANANA earned 12 million players just over a month after launch. Meanwhile, Off The Grid is also gaining serious traction, with millions of wallets created during the first week of early access before becoming the top free game on the Epic Games Store. The numbers tell a clear story: mass adoption follows when blockchain integration is invisible.</span></p>
<h2><b>The lesson for blockchain game makers</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since the sector&#8217;s inception, we&#8217;ve been waiting for the blockchain gaming &#8220;mainstream moment.&#8221; The one-two punch of Off The Grid and Telegram suggests we&#8217;re inching closer, but their wins hold essential lessons for developers.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First, arming your game with blockchain isn&#8217;t enough. </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/heres-why-31-of-blockchains-games-were-shuttered-in-2023/">About 400 crypto games</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> stopped development last year, and since 2018, more than </span><strong><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/three-quarters-web3-blockchain-games-failed-last-five-years-coingecko">three-quarters of all blockchain games</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> have failed to gain traction and been discontinued. The reason? Games weren&#8217;t fun enough, and blockchain features weren&#8217;t compelling enough. Going forward, game makers must start with both the game and the blockchain use case before working backward. Without a good game behind it, the blockchain elements never have a chance to take off.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The second lesson is about accessibility. </span><strong><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/onboarding-crypto-adoption-challenges">One-quarter of web3 leaders agree</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the learning curve for blockchain technology and the lack of user-friendly interfaces remain significant hurdles to adoption. Solutions like </span><strong><a href="https://protocol.carv.io/identity">CARV ID</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are instructive here, uniting gamer profiles under one banner to improve interoperability and showcase achievements across games. This new crop of games shows that we need to start with great gameplay, make it easy to access, and bake blockchain into the foundation. This is the best way to make both sides of &#8220;blockchain gaming&#8221; work together.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In my view, it&#8217;s time to think of blockchain gaming like cloud computing—something consumers seldom encounter, but that drives the backend thanks to invisible integration. Just as we don&#8217;t think about cloud computing when using Netflix, players shouldn&#8217;t have to think about blockchain when inside our games.</span></p>
<h2><b>Balancing gameplay and blockchain in 2025</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Heading into the new year, blockchain gaming is better positioned to break into the mainstream. AAA studios are taking us seriously, and gamers are coming around the idea of blockchain features that further the play experience.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, there&#8217;s a fine line between creating a great game and ensuring meaningful crypto synergy. Neopets Metaverse, an NFT-powered game based on the massively popular 1999 pet simulator, was in development for roughly two years before it was abruptly canceled. The reason? The CEO said gamers </span><a href="https://decrypt.co/151644/neopets-fans-care-less-about-crypto-ceo-says"><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;<strong>didn&#8217;t care</strong>&#8220;</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> about blockchain, with the title intended to repurpose it as a regular mobile game. Clearly, the game needs to be good, and adding blockchain needs to make sense, add value, and improve the ecosystem.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Here, understanding the audience is crucial. Gamers trend younger and want better ways to express themselves, own their identities, and make money online – all things blockchain can enable. Therefore, making these features accessible and meaningful with blockchain will drive the next web3 gaming bull run.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the challenge for our sector in 2025 – making blockchain relevant to the game, invisible to the player, and powerful enough to drive adoption. It&#8217;s now up to us – the developers – to get there. Off The Grid and Telegram are showing us the way forward – put blockchain in the background and let the games lead the charge.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/">The gaming lesson from Off The Grid and Telegram? Put blockchain in the background</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/the-gaming-lesson-from-off-the-grid-and-telegram-put-blockchain-in-the-background/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/web3-gaming-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/web3-gaming-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ICP identity protocol DecideID to launch on Solana eliminating any KYC need for DeFi</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/icp-identity-protocol-decideid-launches-on-solana-to-reduce-kyc-need-for-defi/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/icp-identity-protocol-decideid-launches-on-solana-to-reduce-kyc-need-for-defi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 15:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DecideAI has announced the integration of its biometric identity verification solution, DecideID, into the Solana blockchain, aiming to enhance security and trust within the ecosystem. This move introduces Proof-of-Personhood (PoP) capabilities to Solana, ensuring that users are verified as unique individuals without the need for traditional Know-Your-Customer procedures. Raheel Govindji, founder and CEO of DecideAI, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/icp-identity-protocol-decideid-launches-on-solana-to-reduce-kyc-need-for-defi/">ICP identity protocol DecideID to launch on Solana eliminating any KYC need for DeFi</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>DecideAI has announced the integration of its biometric <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/decideai/">identity verification</a> solution, DecideID, into the Solana blockchain, aiming to enhance security and trust within the ecosystem. This move introduces Proof-of-Personhood (PoP) capabilities to Solana, ensuring that users are verified as unique individuals without the need for traditional Know-Your-Customer procedures.</p>
<p>Raheel Govindji, founder and CEO of DecideAI, commented,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;DecideID is positioned to set a new standard in identity verification across the blockchain space. The Solana integration is just the beginning, and we anticipate a significant surge in user growth and adoption&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The integration is expected to address longstanding vulnerabilities in Solana&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/solana-liquid-staking-token-jto-surges-85-post-exchange-debut-following-unique-airdrop-event/">airdrop</a> ecosystem, which has previously been susceptible to Sybil attacks and botting. By verifying real users through AI-driven facial recognition and liveness detection technologies, DecideID aims to prevent fraudulent activities and ensure fair token distributions.</p>
<p><a href="/coins/solana">Solana</a> developers will now have the opportunity to leverage DecideID&#8217;s identity verification tools to enhance the integrity of decentralized applications. This is particularly significant for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-token-whalefarm-drops-99-after-latest-defi-exploit/">DeFi projects</a>, where ensuring that transactions are conducted by real and unique individuals adds a crucial layer of trust. The technology analyzes facial movement, depth, and micro-expressions to confirm user authenticity, utilizing Zero-Knowledge proofs to protect personal data during the verification process.</p>
<p>According to DecideAI, the integration will,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Add a layer of trust in lending, staking, and yield farming by ensuring that only real and unique humans are behind transactions.</p>
<p>Additionally, DecideID’s AI facial recognition technology doesn’t require any Know-Your-Customer procedures or documentation, making it an easy and quick scan for users.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The integration is currently in the testing phase and is expected to be fully launched before the end of the year. Upon release, Solana users will be able to link their wallets, participate in airdrops, and verify their personhood without extensive documentation. DecideAI is also in discussions with several Solana-based DeFi and NFT platforms that plan to adopt DecideID for enhanced security and fair governance participation.</p>
<p>This development is facilitated by the Internet Computer&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dfinitys-new-api-boosts-internet-computer-smart-contracts-with-cross-chain-prowess/">Chain Fusion</a> technology, which allows for seamless protocol-level integration with other blockchains. The Internet Computer (ICP) acts as a powerful general-purpose blockchain and Web3 platform, enabling DecideID to extend its services beyond Solana with potential future integrations into networks like Ethereum.</p>
<p>DecideID reportedly has already verified over 14,000 unique users and aims to foster trust and accountability in decentralized applications. By preventing malicious activities and ensuring secure interactions, it contributes to a more transparent and fair blockchain environment.</p>
<p>Per the recent announcement, DecideAI&#8217;s mission extends beyond identity verification. It aims to reshape the landscape of large language models by prioritizing quality, collaboration, and ownership. Through its ecosystem comprising Decide Protocol, DecideID, and Decide Cortex, the company seeks to democratize access to AI resources while rewarding contributors and setting new standards for open-source collaboration.</p>
<h2>Proof of personhood protocols on the rise</h2>
<p>This integration places DecideID among notable Proof-of-Personhood initiatives such as World, Proof of Humanity, Idena, CorePass, and Anima Protocol.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/worldcoin-rebrands-as-world-targets-1-billion-users-with-new-blockchain-and-biometric-tech/">World</a> (formerly Worldcoin,) founded by Sam Altman, uses iris scans to generate unique identifiers for individuals, though it has faced privacy concerns over biometric data collection.</p>
<p>Proof of Humanity combines video verification with community endorsement to establish unique identities on the Ethereum blockchain. It aims to facilitate fair distribution in Universal Basic Income projects.</p>
<p>Idena employs AI-resistant tasks called &#8220;flips&#8221; to ensure each node in its network represents a unique human, enhancing decentralization and resistance to Sybil attacks.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ping-exchange-debuts-with-unique-corepass-id-authentication-and-native-crypto-trading/">CorePass,</a> on the Core Blockchain network, allows users to verify and tokenize credentials such as passports, driving licenses, emails, and names. Data can then be sold to dApps, allowing users to realize the value of their data instead of giving it away for free.</p>
<p>Anima Protocol provides decentralized identity services on the BNB Chain, focusing on privacy while verifying user authenticity.</p>
<p>These projects, like DecideID, showcase how blockchain can address challenges such as fraudulent activities and fair resource distribution in digital ecosystems, but each takes a different approach to balance security, privacy, and user experience.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/icp-identity-protocol-decideid-launches-on-solana-to-reduce-kyc-need-for-defi/">ICP identity protocol DecideID to launch on Solana eliminating any KYC need for DeFi</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/icp-identity-protocol-decideid-launches-on-solana-to-reduce-kyc-need-for-defi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/solana-2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/solana-2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Linea Association unveils plan for decentralized governance with LINEA token</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/linea-association-unveils-plan-for-decentralized-governance-with-linea-token/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/linea-association-unveils-plan-for-decentralized-governance-with-linea-token/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 09:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452742</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At Devcon in Bangkok, the Linea Association announced its formation to oversee the development and governance of Linea&#8217;s open-source technology and ecosystem. The Swiss non-profit aims to decentralize the Linea Network—the zkEVM Layer-2 solution designed to scale Ethereum—by launching the LINEA token by the end of Q1 2025, enabling community-driven governance. The Association&#8217;s mission includes [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/linea-association-unveils-plan-for-decentralized-governance-with-linea-token/">Linea Association unveils plan for decentralized governance with LINEA token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At Devcon in Bangkok, the Linea Association announced its formation to oversee the development and governance of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/consensys-launches-linea-mainnet-alpha-launch/">Linea&#8217;s</a> open-source technology and ecosystem. The Swiss non-profit aims to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-proposes-lowering-staking-threshold-to-boost-ethereum-decentralization/">decentralize</a> the Linea Network—the zkEVM Layer-2 solution designed to scale Ethereum—by launching the LINEA token by the end of Q1 2025, enabling community-driven governance.</p>
<p>The Association&#8217;s mission includes supporting the growth of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/consensys-launches-linea-mainnet-alpha-launch/">Linea Mainnet</a> to build a fast, affordable, and secure network accessible worldwide. It plans to advance decentralization through new governance mechanisms and implement decentralized sequencing and proving. Empowering developers to create decentralized applications with enhanced user experiences and fostering strong, engaged communities are also key priorities.</p>
<p>Nicolas Liochon, founder of Linea and board member of the Linea Association, said.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Decentralization is at the core of Linea&#8217;s vision. Linea must be owned and governed openly by all as a public good, just as Layer 1 Ethereum is.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The governance structure will feature a Board of Directors, a General Assembly, an Executive Director, and a token governance body. The LINEA token will allow holders to participate in governance, with details on token design and utility to be shared before the token generation event. More than 1.3 million verified addresses have joined the network, reflecting Linea&#8217;s focus on organic community growth.</p>
<p>Since its mainnet <a href="https://consensys.io/blog/consensys-launches-linea-mainnet-unlocking-a-new-level-of-user-experience">launch</a> in August 2023, Linea has processed over 230 million transactions, making it one of the fastest-growing zkEVMs on Ethereum. The ecosystem has also expanded to over 420 ecosystem partners. The technology is publicly available under the Apache license, allowing users to view, fork, and modify the code.</p>
<p>The Association operates independently of Consensys, aligning with CEO Joseph Lubin&#8217;s vision to decentralize core innovations progressively. Lubin said,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;As Consensys progresses toward decentralization, Linea represents a foundational step in our vision of creating a Network State for the emerging decentralized global economy.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Linea has integrated long-term Ethereum contributors like Status, developers of the Nimbus client that secures 10% of Ethereum&#8217;s proof-of-stake network. The Association plans to decentralize core protocol development and governance further, ensuring social and technical alignment within the community.</p>
<p>The Swiss Association structure allows token holders to have governance over managing IP and a treasury supporting Linea&#8217;s mission. The focus remains on furthering the growth and development of the open-source LINEA technology and the Linea Network.</p>
<p>Linea aims to empower users and businesses to manage valuable on-chain data, including identity and property. Per the announcement, the Linea Association seeks to be a significant step toward decentralizing the network and fostering collaborative, transparent governance. The initiative aims to empower the global community to shape the future of Linea and contribute to the broader Ethereum ecosystem.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/linea-association-unveils-plan-for-decentralized-governance-with-linea-token/">Linea Association unveils plan for decentralized governance with LINEA token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/linea-association-unveils-plan-for-decentralized-governance-with-linea-token/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/network-decentralization.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/network-decentralization.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vitalik Buterin outlines how Ethereum&#8217;s Verge can bring blockchain nodes to smartwatches</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-outlines-how-ethereums-verge-can-bring-blockchain-nodes-to-smartwatches/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-outlines-how-ethereums-verge-can-bring-blockchain-nodes-to-smartwatches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 10:16:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vitalik Buterin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin has laid out further plans to improve the blockchain&#8217;s Proof-of-Stake (PoS) system through a new upgrade called &#8220;The Verge.&#8221; In a blog post published on Oct. 23, Buterin explained that while running an Ethereum node is technically possible on a standard laptop, the current system&#8217;s data requirements make it impractical for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-outlines-how-ethereums-verge-can-bring-blockchain-nodes-to-smartwatches/">Vitalik Buterin outlines how Ethereum&#8217;s Verge can bring blockchain nodes to smartwatches</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> co-founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/vitalik-buterin/">Vitalik Buterin</a> has laid out further plans to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-lays-down-roadmap-to-minimize-centralization-risk-in-ethereum-pos-design/">improve the blockchain&#8217;s Proof-of-Stake (PoS) system</a> through a new upgrade called &#8220;The Verge.&#8221;</p>
<p>In a <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/10/23/futures4.html">blog post</a> published on Oct. 23, Buterin explained that while running an Ethereum node is technically possible on a standard laptop, the current system&#8217;s data requirements make it impractical for many users.</p>
<p>Operating a node demands hundreds of gigabytes of data to verify blocks, and this data grows by about 30 GB each year. These high storage needs restrict the number of users who can run fully verifying nodes on Ethereum.</p>
<p>Buterin&#8217;s proposed Verge update addresses this challenge by introducing &#8220;stateless client verification,&#8221; which allows devices to validate blockchain data without storing the entire dataset locally.</p>
<p>He explained:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The Verge is about changing this, and <strong>making fully-verifying the chain so computationally affordable that every mobile wallet, browser wallet, and even smart watch is doing it by default</strong>.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>The Verge</h2>
<p>Initially, &#8220;The Verge&#8221; focused on adopting Verkle trees, a data structure that facilitates more compact proofs and enables the stateless verification of Ethereum blocks.</p>
<p>However, the scope has since broadened. The update now aims to make Ethereum verification more resource-efficient by combining stateless validation techniques and advanced cryptographic proofs like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-adds-zk-snark-verification-to-its-proof-of-reserves-system/">SNARKs</a> (Succinct Non-Interactive Arguments of Knowledge).</p>
<p>SNARKs allow one party to prove they hold certain information without disclosing the details, making it possible to verify complex transactions swiftly on-chain. Buterin believes this technology could enable Ethereum&#8217;s blockchain to be verified on small devices like smartwatches, expanding the potential for widespread participation in the network.</p>
<p>Stateless verification, in particular, eliminates the need for nodes to store all blockchain data. Instead, each block would include a &#8220;witness&#8221; containing the essential data and cryptographic proofs needed to validate the block.</p>
<p>This shift toward stateless clients is crucial, as it reduces storage demands and accelerates blockchain performance. This would improve the overall user experience while lowering the barriers to running Ethereum nodes, making <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-proposes-lowering-staking-threshold-to-boost-ethereum-decentralization/">solo staking</a> much more accessible.</p>
<p>To implement these changes, Buterin proposes replacing Ethereum&#8217;s current state structure, known as the Merkle Patricia tree, with either Verkle trees or STARKed binary hash trees. While STARKs serve a similar function to SNARKs, they offer additional benefits in terms of scalability and security, helping Ethereum overcome some of the limitations of its existing proof systems.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-outlines-how-ethereums-verge-can-bring-blockchain-nodes-to-smartwatches/">Vitalik Buterin outlines how Ethereum&#8217;s Verge can bring blockchain nodes to smartwatches</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-outlines-how-ethereums-verge-can-bring-blockchain-nodes-to-smartwatches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/vitalik-buterin-ethereum-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/vitalik-buterin-ethereum-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan&#8217;s Web3 transformation: How Monex Group is powering the nation&#8217;s crypto ecosystem</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/japans-web3-transformation-how-monex-group-is-powering-the-nations-crypto-ecosystem/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/japans-web3-transformation-how-monex-group-is-powering-the-nations-crypto-ecosystem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Desk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 15:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sponsored]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=447741</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Japan&#8217;s government actively promotes Web3 as a national policy, creating a favorable environment for conducting Web3 businesses there. In an exclusive interview with CryptoSlate, Tsukada from Monex Group explains that this includes &#8220;tax reforms for handling digital assets, accounting preparations, the legal positioning of DAOs, recommendations for local governments to enter Web3 and adopt the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japans-web3-transformation-how-monex-group-is-powering-the-nations-crypto-ecosystem/">Japan&#8217;s Web3 transformation: How Monex Group is powering the nation&#8217;s crypto ecosystem</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Japan&#8217;s government actively promotes Web3 as a national policy, creating a favorable environment for conducting Web3 businesses there. In an exclusive interview with CryptoSlate, Tsukada from Monex Group explains that this includes &#8220;tax reforms for handling digital assets, accounting preparations, the legal positioning of DAOs, recommendations for local governments to enter Web3 and adopt the metaverse, support for exchanges with overseas talents, and Web3 events.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, Japan has required the registration of cryptocurrency exchange operators since 2017, ensuring the &#8220;safe management of user information, regulated advertising and solicitation, and established an environment where users can utilize services with maximum protection and safety.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This regulatory clarity has paved the way for further Web3 innovation, as Tsukada notes that in 2023, &#8220;it became possible to issue stablecoins backed by legal tender, allowing various companies, including existing financial institutions, to issue stablecoins.&#8221;</span></p>
<h2><b>Major Japanese Corporations are Diving into Web3</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The favorable regulatory environment has encouraged large Japanese corporations to enter the Web3 space. As Tsukada explains:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#8220;NTT Docomo, the largest telecommunications company, has started developing its own wallet and is working on creating a user-friendly Web3 environment and rules. In the gaming industry, major companies like Square Enix are developing Web3 games using their IPs.&#8221;</span></i></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The entry of these corporate giants signals the maturing of Japan&#8217;s Web3 ecosystem. Tsukada cites the success of Brilliant Crypto, which &#8220;conducted an IEO on Coincheck, our subsidiary and the largest CEX in Japan, reached a record high of 33.3 billion yen.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He says this &#8220;is a great example of leveraging Web2 know-how to enter the Web3 gaming space successfully.&#8221;</span></p>
<h2><b>Monex Group: A Diversified Financial Firm Embracing Web3</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monex Group, Inc. is a financial holding company with over 20 years of history, encompassing subsidiaries such as the centralized cryptocurrency exchange Coincheck, crypto asset consulting firms, AI startups, and securities companies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Tsukada explains:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;Monex Group provides various services related to crypto assets and blockchain, including the &#8216;MCB Web3 Newsletter&#8217; and &#8216;MCB Research,&#8217; the NFT project &#8216;OASIS,&#8217; and the news app &#8216;Cheeese,&#8217; which rewards users with Bitcoin. Established in December 2017, we have been focusing particularly on Web3 support services since last year, supporting the development of various services and the Japanese market.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<h2 class="p2"><b>Monex Group&#8217;s Web3 Consulting Business: Leveraging In-House Expertise</b></h2>
<p class="p1">Recognizing the growing demand for Web3 expertise in Japan, Monex Group has established a Web3 consulting business.<span class="Apple-converted-space">  </span>As Tsukada elaborated:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;In the Web3 consulting business, we support companies entering Web3 by leveraging the know-how accumulated by Monex Group. We offer a wide range of support, from NFT community building and operation to NFT planning, issuance, and tokenomics consultation.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">Monex has already supported the &#8220;construction and operation of NFT projects for major automotive and Japanese local governments&#8221; and is currently &#8220;strengthening our support for overseas Web3 projects entering the Japanese market.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">The company&#8217;s Web3 consulting services include:</p>
<ul class="ul1">
<li class="li4">Web3 Business Research and Planning</li>
<li class="li4">NFT Planning, Issuance, and Sales</li>
<li class="li4">Community Building/Operation</li>
<li class="li4">Metaverse Development/Collaboration</li>
<li class="li1">IEO Support/Tokenomics Design</li>
</ul>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-449645" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_5230.jpg" alt="" width="1280" height="520" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_5230.jpg 1280w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_5230-300x122.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_5230-1024x416.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/IMG_5230-768x312.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /></p>
<p class="p1">Tsukada notes that Monex&#8217;s strengths in this area include &#8220;the reliability of being associated with a listed company,&#8221; its ability to &#8220;collaborate across the group&#8221; in various business developments, and &#8220;real-time feedback and insights from our community and metaverse services, used to build Web3 communities and market them.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="p2"><b>The OASIS Project: Monex&#8217;s Innovative NFT Community</b></h2>
<p class="p1">A key part of Monex&#8217;s Web3 expertise comes from its in-house project, OASIS. As Asami explains:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;OASIS is a digital community that started in January 2023 with the concept of creating opportunities for transformation and new encounters. It was built from scratch as part of a listed company group in Japan&#8217;s highly regulated Web3 market. It is an innovative and challenging initiative, issuing and selling NFTs with almost no prior examples.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">One unique aspect of OASIS is its &#8220;cross-utilization of various metaverses.&#8221; Asami said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;We are developing cities in Web3 metaverses like The Sandbox and Decentraland. We also have worlds in Fortnite and Cluster, Japan&#8217;s largest metaverse, and XANA, with further expansion planned.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">This multi-metaverse approach has allowed OASIS to attract a large community of nearly 30,000 members, making it &#8220;one of Japan&#8217;s largest.&#8221; Asami notes that the community &#8220;facilitates easy collaboration with many companies and projects&#8221; by discussing a &#8220;rich variety of themes&#8221; such as AI and Japan&#8217;s Vtuber culture.</p>
<h2 class="p2"><b>Supporting Companies Entering the Japanese Web3 Market</b></h2>
<p class="p1">Monex&#8217;s experience with the OASIS project has provided valuable insights that the company is now leveraging to support other organizations entering the Japanese Web3 market.</p>
<p class="p1">As Tsukada explains:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p3"><i>&#8220;Through the OASIS project, we gained extensive knowledge about community management and handling NFTs. We learned that many companies struggle with Web3 community building through interactions with external organizations and overseas projects. Therefore, we thought we could support companies entering the Web3 space through consulting.&#8221;</i></p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">Monex&#8217;s strengths in this area include &#8220;the reliability of being associated with a listed company,&#8221; its ability to &#8220;collaborate across the group,&#8221; and access to &#8220;real-time feedback and insights from our community and metaverse services, used to build Web3 communities and market them.&#8221;</p>
<p class="p1">The company has already &#8220;started joint Web3 service construction with major domestic automotive&#8221; and &#8220;collaborated with local governments on regional contributions through Web3.&#8221;</p>
<h2 class="p2"><b>Looking Ahead: Monex Group&#8217;s Presence at Upcoming Web3 Events</b></h2>
<p class="p1">Monex Group actively showcases its Web3 expertise and services at major industry events. The company organized a side event called &#8220;Japan Crypto Fusion&#8221; at TOKEN2049 in Dubai, which attracted a strong turnout despite a schedule change due to record-breaking rainfall.</p>
<p class="p1">Additionally, Monex Group is planning to have a significant presence at the upcoming &#8220;NexTeck Week2024&#8221; technology festival in Tokyo in November, where the company is seeking partners to exhibit with them.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-447743" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/monex-event.jpg" alt="" width="1214" height="915" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/monex-event.jpg 1214w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/monex-event-300x226.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/monex-event-1024x772.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/monex-event-768x579.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1214px) 100vw, 1214px" /></p>
<p class="p1">As the Japanese Web3 market continues to evolve, Monex Group&#8217;s diverse financial services and innovative approach to community building and consulting make it a key player in the country&#8217;s burgeoning ecosystem. <span class="s1">If you have even a slight interest in expanding into the Japanese market, it would be wise to submit an inquiry.</span></p>
<p class="p1">To learn more:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Monex Group Zero Department: <a href="mailto:mg-monexzero@monex.co.jp">mg-monexzero@monex.co.jp</a></span></li>
<li class="li2"><span class="s2">OASIS: <a href="https://x.com/Oasis_pj"><span class="s3">https://x.com/Oasis_pj</span></a></span></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Disclosure:</strong> This is a sponsored post. Readers should conduct further research prior to taking any actions. <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sponsored-post-disclaimer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Learn more ›</a></p>
<p><em>Coincheck Group B.V., a planned holding company for Coincheck, Inc., a consolidated subsidiary of Monex Group, is scheduled to list on NASDAQ this December through a merger with Thunder Bridge Capital Partners IV, Inc., a special purpose acquisition company (SPAC) listed on NASDAQ in the United States.</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.monexgroup.jp/en/news_release/irnews/auto_20241112520488/pdfFile.pdf"><em>https://www.monexgroup.jp/en/news_release/irnews/auto_20241112520488/pdfFile.pdf</em></a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japans-web3-transformation-how-monex-group-is-powering-the-nations-crypto-ecosystem/">Japan&#8217;s Web3 transformation: How Monex Group is powering the nation&#8217;s crypto ecosystem</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/japans-web3-transformation-how-monex-group-is-powering-the-nations-crypto-ecosystem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/japan-web3.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/japan-web3.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OpenAI GPT 4o ranked as best AI model for writing Solidity smart contract code by IQ</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/openai-gpt-4o-ranked-as-best-ai-model-for-writing-solidity-smart-contract-code-by-iq/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/openai-gpt-4o-ranked-as-best-ai-model-for-writing-solidity-smart-contract-code-by-iq/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 10:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SolidityBench by IQ has launched as the first leaderboard to evaluate LLMs in Solidity code generation. Available on Hugging Face, it introduces two innovative benchmarks, NaïveJudge and HumanEval for Solidity, designed to assess and rank the proficiency of AI models in generating smart contract code. Developed by IQ&#8217;s BrainDAO as part of its forthcoming IQ [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/openai-gpt-4o-ranked-as-best-ai-model-for-writing-solidity-smart-contract-code-by-iq/">OpenAI GPT 4o ranked as best AI model for writing Solidity smart contract code by IQ</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">SolidityBench by IQ has launched as the first leaderboard to evaluate LLMs in Solidity code generation. Available on <a href="https://huggingface.co/spaces/braindao/soliditybench-leaderboard">Hugging Face</a>, it introduces two innovative benchmarks, NaïveJudge and HumanEval for Solidity, designed to assess and rank the proficiency of AI models in generating smart contract code.</p>
<p class="p1">Developed by IQ&#8217;s <a href="https://braindao.org/">BrainDAO</a> as part of its forthcoming IQ Code suite, SolidityBench serves to refine their own EVMind LLMs and compare them against generalist and community-created models. IQ Code aims to offer AI models tailored for generating and auditing smart contract code, addressing the growing need for secure and efficient blockchain applications.</p>
<p class="p1">As IQ told <em>CryptoSlate</em>, NaïveJudge offers a novel approach by tasking LLMs with implementing smart contracts based on detailed specifications derived from audited OpenZeppelin contracts. These contracts provide a gold standard for correctness and efficiency. The generated code is evaluated against a reference implementation using criteria such as functional completeness, adherence to Solidity best practices and security standards, and optimization efficiency.</p>
<p class="p1">The evaluation process leverages <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/press-releases/spectral-launches-syntax-an-llm-enabling-web3-users-to-build-autonomous-agents-and-deploy-onchain-products/">advanced LLMs</a>, including different versions of OpenAI&#8217;s GPT-4 and Claude 3.5 Sonnet as impartial code reviewers. They assess the code based on rigorous criteria, including implementing all key functionalities, handling edge cases, error management, proper syntax usage, and overall code structure and maintainability.</p>
<p class="p1">Optimization considerations such as gas efficiency and storage management are also evaluated. Scores range from 0 to 100, providing a comprehensive assessment across functionality, security, and efficiency, mirroring the complexities of professional smart contract development.</p>
<h2>Which AI models are best for solidity smart contract development?</h2>
<p>Benchmarking results showed that OpenAI&#8217;s GPT-4o model achieved the highest overall score of 80.05, with a NaïveJudge score of 72.18 and HumanEval for Solidity pass rates of 80% at pass@1 and 92% at pass@3.</p>
<p>Interestingly, newer reasoning models like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/openai-launches-next-gen-llm-model-o1-using-reasoning-tokens-to-plan-outputs/">OpenAI&#8217;s o1-preview</a> and o1-mini were beaten to the top spot, scoring 77.61 and 75.08, respectively. Models from Anthropic and XAI, including Claude 3.5 Sonnet and grok-2, demonstrated competitive performance with overall scores hovering around 74. Nvidia&#8217;s Llama-3.1-Nemotron-70B scored lowest in the top 10 at 52.54.</p>
<figure id="attachment_449206" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-449206" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-449206" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-21-at-10.47.21-1024x390.png" alt="SolidityBench scores for LLMs (Hugging Face)" width="1024" height="390" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-21-at-10.47.21-1024x390.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-21-at-10.47.21-300x114.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-21-at-10.47.21-768x292.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-21-at-10.47.21-1536x585.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/Screenshot-2024-10-21-at-10.47.21-2048x780.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-449206" class="wp-caption-text">SolidityBench scores for LLMs (Hugging Face)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">Per IQ, HumanEval for Solidity adapts OpenAI&#8217;s original HumanEval benchmark from Python to Solidity, encompassing 25 tasks of varying difficulty. Each task includes corresponding tests compatible with Hardhat, a popular Ethereum development environment, facilitating accurate compilation and testing of generated code. The evaluation metrics, pass@1 and pass@3, measure the model&#8217;s success on initial attempts and over multiple tries, offering insights into both precision and problem-solving capabilities.</p>
<h2>Goals of utilizing AI models in smart contract development</h2>
<p class="p1">By introducing these benchmarks, SolidityBench seeks to advance AI-assisted smart contract development. It encourages the creation of more sophisticated and reliable AI models while providing developers and researchers with valuable insights into AI&#8217;s current capabilities and limitations in Solidity development.</p>
<p class="p1">The benchmarking toolkit aims to advance IQ Code&#8217;s EVMind LLMs and also sets new standards for AI-assisted smart contract development across the blockchain ecosystem. The initiative hopes to address a critical need in the industry, where the demand for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/understanding-the-pros-and-cons-of-smart-contract-upgradeability-in-defi/">secure</a> and efficient smart contracts continues to grow.</p>
<p class="p1">Developers, researchers, and AI enthusiasts are invited to explore and contribute to SolidityBench, which aims to drive the continuous refinement of AI models, promote best practices, and advance decentralized applications.</p>
<p class="p1">Visit the SolidityBench <a href="https://huggingface.co/spaces/braindao/soliditybench-leaderboard">leaderboard</a> on Hugging Face to learn more and begin benchmarking Solidity generation models.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/openai-gpt-4o-ranked-as-best-ai-model-for-writing-solidity-smart-contract-code-by-iq/">OpenAI GPT 4o ranked as best AI model for writing Solidity smart contract code by IQ</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/openai-gpt-4o-ranked-as-best-ai-model-for-writing-solidity-smart-contract-code-by-iq/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/braindao-ai-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/braindao-ai-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana content tokenization grows with Cube listing of Access Protocol following Argentine government partnership</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/solana-content-tokenization-grows-with-cube-listing-of-access-protocol-following-argentine-government-partnership/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/solana-content-tokenization-grows-with-cube-listing-of-access-protocol-following-argentine-government-partnership/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 08:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=448757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cube, a hybrid exchange that settles trades on-chain using secure multi-party computation, has listed Access Protocol (ACS), a content monetization platform built on Solana. The listing follows Cube&#8217;s recent announcement of Isometric (ISO), an intent-based transaction network that aims to enable cross-chain trading without asset bridging. At the Solana Breakpoint conference, Cube&#8217;s CEO and co-founder [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/solana-content-tokenization-grows-with-cube-listing-of-access-protocol-following-argentine-government-partnership/">Solana content tokenization grows with Cube listing of Access Protocol following Argentine government partnership</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Cube, a hybrid exchange that settles trades on-chain using secure multi-party computation, has listed Access Protocol (ACS), a content monetization platform built on <a href="/coins/solana">Solana</a>. The listing follows Cube&#8217;s recent announcement of Isometric (ISO), an intent-based transaction network that aims to enable cross-chain trading without asset bridging.</p>
<p class="p1">At the Solana Breakpoint conference, Cube&#8217;s CEO and co-founder Bartosz Lipinski outlined the vision behind Isometric. &#8220;When we started building Cube, we wanted everything to be an intent,&#8221; Lipinski stated.</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="p1">&#8220;Everyone will be able to submit intents to the network and verify settlements on multiple chains using the decentralized MPC that we&#8217;ve built.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="p1">He emphasized that the decentralized MPC integration layer allows users to utilize value across layer-one blockchains without diminishing it.</p>
<p class="p1">Isometric&#8217;s platform token, ISO, will power governance, staking, and decentralized custody within the network. Cube has scheduled both the token and mainnet launch for the second quarter of 2025, aiming to streamline cross-chain interactions and enhance blockchain transaction efficiency.</p>
<p class="p1">In addition to technological advancements, Cube announced a <a href="https://x.com/cubexch/status/1846960011211075721">partnership</a> with the Argentine government this week. The collaboration intends to explore leveraging the Isometric network as a catalyst for Argentina&#8217;s financial system, signaling a significant step in integrating blockchain technology with national financial infrastructures.</p>
<p class="p1">The timing of the <a href="/coins/access-protocol">ACS</a> listing is notable as it highlights the growing use of content tokenization on the chain. Cube&#8217;s custom rewards platform, Blocks, engages users through unique packages for listing traders and token holders. Participants in the ACS listing will be eligible for Blocks campaign rewards, potentially increasing user engagement and liquidity for the token.</p>
<p class="p1">Access Protocol has been expanding its ecosystem. The protocol is <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/access-protocol-taps-solanas-actions-and-blinks-for-streamlined-user-experience/">integrating</a> Solana&#8217;s new &#8220;Actions&#8221; and &#8220;Blinks&#8221; features to enhance the user experience by allowing crypto transactions through any website or application using shareable links. This integration will enable one-click purchases of staked ACS subscriptions for top crypto media platforms using Solana&#8217;s native token, SOL.</p>
<p class="p1">Founded by DeFi investing expert Mika Honkasalo and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/access-protocol-to-go-live-feb-15-with-acs-airdrop-for-coingecko-candies/">launched in February 2023</a>, Access Protocol offers a blockchain-based subscription model for content creators and digital media publications. Users can access exclusive content by staking ACS tokens rather than through traditional subscriptions.</p>
<p class="p1">Cube&#8217;s listing of ACS and developments with Isometric reflect a broader trend of innovation in cross-chain solutions and content monetization models within the blockchain industry. The partnership with Argentina emphasizes the growing interest of national governments in leveraging blockchain technology for financial system enhancements.</p>
<p><em>CryptoSlate</em> <a href="/alpha">Alpha</a> is powered by Access Protocol, which gives exclusive access to enhanced crypto research and insights.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/solana-content-tokenization-grows-with-cube-listing-of-access-protocol-following-argentine-government-partnership/">Solana content tokenization grows with Cube listing of Access Protocol following Argentine government partnership</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/solana-content-tokenization-grows-with-cube-listing-of-access-protocol-following-argentine-government-partnership/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/access-protocol.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/access-protocol.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The success of DePIN is in all of our pockets</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/the-success-of-depin-is-in-all-of-our-pockets/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/the-success-of-depin-is-in-all-of-our-pockets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[J.D. Seraphine]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 11:49:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DePIN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web3]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=446696</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post from J.D. Seraphine, Founder and CEO at Raiinmaker. In an era where technology advancements continuously reshape the landscape of our daily lives, mobile devices have emerged as an integral tool for driving connectivity. Growing hand in hand with this connectivity has been the public’s consciousness and concern for the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-success-of-depin-is-in-all-of-our-pockets/">The success of DePIN is in all of our pockets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><em>The following is a guest post from <span data-sheets-root="1">J.D. Seraphine</span>, Founder and CEO at Raiinmaker.</em></span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In an era where technology advancements continuously reshape the landscape of our daily lives, mobile devices have emerged as an integral tool for driving connectivity. Growing hand in hand with this connectivity has been the public’s consciousness and concern for the security and privacy of their data, as well as their awareness of the suboptimally centralized nature of many of our legacy systems. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Intriguingly, however, it is mobile devices, the source and driver of many of society’s privacy and security issues, that may hold the key to realizing a more decentralized and secure digital future via decentralized physical infrastructure networks (DePIN). Smartphones, with their omnipresence, advanced capabilities, and seamless connectivity, provide the perfect platform to support and expand decentralized infrastructure and distributed networks. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, Web3 phones are now hitting the market in earnest – just this month, </span><strong><a href="https://www.dlnews.com/articles/web3/solana-mobile-crypto-phone-hits-usd-70-million-in-preorders/">Solana Mobile</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> garnered $70 million in preorders for its second blockchain smartphone, Seeker, which is set to launch in 2025. Among its features, Seeker includes an upgraded crypto wallet and new reward mechanisms that are specifically tailored toward unlocking the transformational potential of DePIN.</span></p>
<h2><b>DePIN as the Solution to the Crisis of Centralization</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The recent technical issue with </span><strong><a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2024/07/24/tech/crowdstrike-outage-cost-cause/index.html">CrowdStrike’s centralized software</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – which led to a global outage affecting numerous sectors – again highlighted the issues created by the centralization of much of the core systems that the modern world relies upon, and the urgent need to move away from monolithic entities, towards a more decentralized future.</span></p>
<p><a href="https://messari.io/report/the-depin-sector-map"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Projected to grow up to $3.5 trillion by 2028</strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> – DePIN technology has emerged as one of the revolutionary advancements in the journey toward a more distributed world. DePIN projects seek to replace the existing centralized model by creating peer-to-peer (P2P) networks where individuals can contribute and own shared control over the network, ​​promoting active community participation, and giving users decision making authority. As well as decentralizing control, data is distributed across multiple nodes – making it less vulnerable to single points of failure, and attack from malicious actors.</span></p>
<h2><b>Mobile Devices Key to Achieving DePIN at Scale</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">First and foremost, leveraging DePIN on mobile devices has the clear benefit of enhancing security through decentralized data distribution, providing users with greater control over their personal data, and addressing their privacy concerns. Additionally, for DePIN to really take off and provide a credible alternative to the current centralized system, a key requirement will be the ample availability of nodes to drive the efficiency and effectiveness of networks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the modern world, the ubiquity of mobile devices means that people are always connected, always online – the World Advertising Research Center (WARC) has </span><strong><a href="https://www.warc.com/content/paywall/article/warc-curated-datapoints/almost-three-quarters-of-internet-users-will-be-mobile-only-by-2025/en-gb/124845?#:~:text=Almost%20three%20quarters%20%E2%80%93%203.7%20billion,%2C%20Indonesia%2C%20Nigeria%20and%20Pakistan.">predicted</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that by 2025 72.6% of internet users or nearly 3.7 billion people will access the web through their smartphones. This constant connectivity of the modern population is a crucial factor for DePIN technology, which relies on the network effect – the more people who are connected and contributing to the network, the more robust and efficient the network becomes. With smartphones in billions of people’s pockets, DePIN projects can leverage this vast, existing infrastructure to reach and engage users at an incredibly significant scale.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taking things to the next level, mobile phones are becoming ever more powerful and capable – equipped with advanced processors, significant storage, and high-speed 5G internet connectivity. These capabilities make them ever-improving and ideal nodes in a decentralized network, capable of performing complex tasks, storing data securely, and communicating with other devices seamlessly. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A </span><strong><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2404.08306">recent study</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> also reinforced the idea of mobile devices as catalysts for efficient decentralized infrastructure networks. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The research found that by harnessing the power of mobile devices, projects can: enhance network efficiency and accessibility, promote decentralization by distributing computational tasks – reducing reliance on centralized data centers, and become more energy-efficient, contributing to sustainable network operations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Clearly</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the integration of mobile devices into DePINs has the very real potential to represent a significant step in the evolution of decentralized networks, improving accessibility, efficiency, and sustainability – offering a scaled alternative to the current centralized models and opening up more and more transformative real-world use cases.</span></p>
<h2><b>Transformative Real-World Use Cases</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It should also be stressed that while DePIN technology must scale further, it is not just a theoretical concept at this stage – it is already demonstrating its capabilities to transform critical infrastructure and create real-world impact across various industries, such as AI training and development, AI reputation management, telecommunications, and much more.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To explain further, training AI models requires massive amounts of data and computational power and therefore, access to powerful AI capabilities has been monopolized by major tech players. <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/depin">DePIN</a> opens the door for individuals and smaller entities to harness the potential of AI, by leveraging a decentralized network of mobile devices that is more efficient and cost-effective.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This decentralized approach democratizes AI development, allowing more individuals and organizations to participate in and benefit from AI advancements. Projects like </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/rendertoken/">Render Network</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><a href="https://www.valdi.ai/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>VALDI</strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are just some examples of this process already in action – and allow users worldwide to leverage decentralized infrastructure for AI, fostering inclusivity, and also sparking innovation from the ground up.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Similarly, DePIN has transformative potential in the realm of telecommunications – as the traditional infrastructure systems are centralized, expensive, and often fail to reach remote or underserved areas. A distributed network approach, pursued by projects like </span><a href="https://www.helium.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Helium</strong></span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, offers a decentralized alternative where individuals can share their internet connections, creating a community-driven network. This approach can significantly reduce costs and extend connectivity, addressing the urgent need to bridge the digital divide for the </span><strong><a href="https://www.gsma.com/r/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/The-State-of-Mobile-Internet-Connectivity-Report-2023.pdf">3 billion people who still remain unconnected</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. This increase in connectivity has the added benefit of increasing the availability of mobile devices to act as nodes for DePIN projects, driving forward additional adoption.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These use cases are just a small glimpse into DePIN’s potential and illustrate the diverse applications across various industries, leveraging decentralized infrastructure to enhance efficiency, security, and sustainability.​</span></p>
<h2><b>Path Forward</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The path forward is clear – a mobile device-driven approach is key to the mass adoption of Web3 technologies, ​and key to realizing the full potential of DePIN to achieve scaled trustless networks built on reputation and present genuine alternatives to existing centralized solutions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ubiquity of mobile devices around the world presents a major opportunity for DePIN to succeed, if we can just find ways to attract more and more people to participate, contribute, and benefit from decentralized networks. As more people join, the network becomes stronger and more robust, driving further adoption and creating a positive feedback loop.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-success-of-depin-is-in-all-of-our-pockets/">The success of DePIN is in all of our pockets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/the-success-of-depin-is-in-all-of-our-pockets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/depin-mobile-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/depin-mobile-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
