<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Analysis News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/analysis/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/analysis/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:57:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Analysis News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/analysis/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>StanChart updates Bitcoin price projection to $200k by 2025-end</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/stanchart-updates-bitcoin-price-projection-to-200k-by-2025-end/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/stanchart-updates-bitcoin-price-projection-to-200k-by-2025-end/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 20:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TradFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456394</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Standard Chartered believes Bitcoin (BTC) could reach $200,000 by the end of 2025 as institutional investments and anticipated regulatory shifts solidify its position as a mainstream asset. In its latest report, the bank attributed Bitcoin&#8217;s surge past $100,000 this year to unprecedented institutional inflows and projected a clear path for further growth. Growing interest StanChart&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/stanchart-updates-bitcoin-price-projection-to-200k-by-2025-end/">StanChart updates Bitcoin price projection to $200k by 2025-end</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/standard-chartered/">Standard Chartered</a> believes Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) could reach $200,000 by the end of 2025 as institutional investments and anticipated regulatory shifts solidify its position as a mainstream asset.</p>
<p>In its latest report, the bank attributed Bitcoin&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-historic-100000-price-level-as-1000-sats-now-equal-1/">surge past $100,000</a> this year to unprecedented institutional inflows and projected a clear path for further growth.</p>
<h2>Growing interest</h2>
<p>StanChart&#8217;s head of digital assets research, Geoffrey Kendrick, highlighted that institutions acquired 683,000 BTC in 2024, with a significant amount — 245,000 BTC — purchased in the weeks following the US election, a period marked by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trump-celebrates-bitcoin-surpassing-100k-milestone-following-election-win/">heightened optimism</a> about regulatory reform under the incoming <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/">Trump</a> administration.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microstrategy/">MicroStrategy</a> alone accounted for 213,000 BTC, significantly exceeding its annual target, while US spot exchange-traded funds (ETFs) added 470,000 BTC to their portfolios.</p>
<p>According to Kendrick:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;MicroStrategy&#8217;s pace of accumulation has exceeded expectations, and its commitment to raising $42 billion over three years indicates further significant inflows in 2025.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Kendrick said he anticipates <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-policy-executive-predicts-fast-crypto-regulation-under-trump/">regulatory changes</a> in early 2025, including a repeal of SAB 121, the passage of stablecoin legislation, and leadership changes at the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), as pivotal for unlocking additional institutional participation.</p>
<p>These reforms are expected to enable retirement funds and pension accounts — representing a $40 trillion market — to allocate a fraction of their assets to Bitcoin. The report noted that even a 1% allocation could drive inflows worth $400 billion, with transformative effects on Bitcoin&#8217;s price.</p>
<p>Additionally, the report highlighted the role of sovereign wealth funds, such as Norway&#8217;s NBIM, which indirectly holds 7,000 BTC through its investment in MicroStrategy. The report also floated the possibility of a US strategic Bitcoin reserve fund, a move that could catalyze broader adoption by other global sovereign wealth funds.</p>
<h2>Lower market volatility</h2>
<p>Standard Chartered noted that the launch of Bitcoin ETF options in November has further reduced market volatility, a factor likely to attract more traditional finance players. The growing appeal of Bitcoin as a portfolio asset is reflected in metrics such as MicroStrategy&#8217;s market cap-to-Bitcoin holdings ratio, which has tripled this year, signaling excess demand.</p>
<p>Additionally, the potential for corporate treasuries and global investors to deepen their Bitcoin exposure has increased with the success experienced by companies like Japan&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/metaplanet/">Metaplanet</a> and Germany&#8217;s Acurx Pharmaceuticals. Both firms have made recent Bitcoin investments, while <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microsoft/">Microsoft&#8217;s</a> board is set to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/michael-saylor-tells-microsoft-board-bitcoin-could-boost-its-market-cap-by-5-trillion/">vote on a similar move</a> this month.</p>
<p>While challenges remain, including the speed of regulatory implementation and broader adoption among conservative asset managers, Standard Chartered <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-advises-buying-bitcoin-below-60000-despite-geopolitical-uncertainty/">reaffirmed its confidence</a> in Bitcoin&#8217;s upward trajectory.</p>
<p>According to the lender:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Bitcoin&#8217;s limited market capitalization, relative to potential institutional demand, positions it uniquely for outsized growth.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/stanchart-updates-bitcoin-price-projection-to-200k-by-2025-end/">StanChart updates Bitcoin price projection to $200k by 2025-end</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/stanchart-updates-bitcoin-price-projection-to-200k-by-2025-end/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/standard-chartered-bitcoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/standard-chartered-bitcoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin flash crashes to $90,200 causing over $885 million in liquidations</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-flash-crashes-to-90200-causing-over-885-million-in-liquidations/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-flash-crashes-to-90200-causing-over-885-million-in-liquidations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 22:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Watch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456210</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s (BTC) historic rally above $100,000 hit a roadblock on Dec. 5 as the flagship crypto fell back into five-figure territory, leaving a trail of liquidations across the market. BTC gave up almost all of the 24-hour gains that took it to a new all-time high of $103,679. It fell to a low of roughly [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-flash-crashes-to-90200-causing-over-885-million-in-liquidations/">Bitcoin flash crashes to $90,200 causing over $885 million in liquidations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) historic rally above $100,000 hit a roadblock on Dec. 5 as the flagship crypto fell back into five-figure territory, leaving a trail of liquidations across the market.</p>
<p>BTC gave up almost all of the 24-hour gains that took it to a new all-time high of $103,679. It fell to a low of roughly $90,300 for the day before attempting a recovery.</p>
<p>Bitcoin was trading at $95,500 as of press time amid heavy volatility, based on <em>CryptoSlate</em> data.</p>
<h2>Liquidations</h2>
<p>Roughly $885.61 million in leveraged positions were liquidated in the past 24 hours, impacting 202,956 traders worldwide. Bitcoin accounted for $540 million of the total liquidations, followed by Ethereum (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">ETH</a>) with $105.53 million.</p>
<p>Other altcoins also experienced substantial liquidations, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a> with $57.07 million, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/dogecoin/">DOGE</a> with $37.54 million, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a> with $29.28 million. A combined $92 million was liquidated across other cryptocurrencies, highlighting the broad impact of Bitcoin&#8217;s price movement.</p>
<p>Long traders, who bet on rising prices, bore the brunt of the impact, with $640.83 million in liquidated positions — 72.4% of the total.</p>
<p>Short positions, which bet on price declines, accounted for $244.78 million. The largest single liquidation occurred on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/okx/">OKX</a>, where an $18.63 million BTC-USDT swap was forcibly closed.</p>
<h2>High volatility</h2>
<p>Breaking down the data further, $284.43 million was liquidated in just one hour, of which $279.50 million were longs. Over the last 12 hours, $552.54 million in liquidations were recorded, including $482.81 million in longs and $69.72 million in shorts.</p>
<p>The four-hour liquidation figure stood at $428.42 million, reflecting heightened volatility during Bitcoin&#8217;s decline.</p>
<p><em>Editor&#8217;s Note: The liquidation numbers may not be fully accurate due to extremely high volatility at the time the article was published.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-flash-crashes-to-90200-causing-over-885-million-in-liquidations/">Bitcoin flash crashes to $90,200 causing over $885 million in liquidations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-flash-crashes-to-90200-causing-over-885-million-in-liquidations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/bitcoin-down-red.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/bitcoin-down-red.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kraken survey reveals crypto holders&#8217; struggle with emotional trading decisions</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-survey-reveals-crypto-holders-struggle-with-emotional-trading-decisions/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-survey-reveals-crypto-holders-struggle-with-emotional-trading-decisions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 21:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trading]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A new survey by Kraken revealed that 63% of US crypto holders believe emotional decision-making has negatively impacted their portfolios, with fear of missing out (FOMO) and fear, uncertainty, and doubt (FUD) playing significant roles. The survey, which gathered responses from 1,248 crypto investors, found that 84% had made decisions influenced by FOMO, and 81% [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-survey-reveals-crypto-holders-struggle-with-emotional-trading-decisions/">Kraken survey reveals crypto holders&#8217; struggle with emotional trading decisions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A new <a href="https://www.kraken.com/learn/crypto-fomo">survey</a> by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken</a> revealed that 63% of US crypto holders believe emotional decision-making has negatively impacted their portfolios, with fear of missing out (FOMO) and fear, uncertainty, and doubt (FUD) playing significant roles.</p>
<p>The survey, which gathered responses from 1,248 crypto investors, found that 84% had made decisions influenced by FOMO, and 81% acted on FUD.  Missing out on significant price surges emerged as the top emotional trigger for 60% of participants, compared to 17% who feared missing price dips.</p>
<p>The findings underline how emotions continue to drive trading strategies in the volatile crypto market, especially as crypto becomes an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/survey-suggests-democrats-see-crypto-as-more-important-to-election-than-republicans/">increasingly important</a> part of investors&#8217; portfolios.</p>
<h2>FOMO and FUD</h2>
<p>FOMO, the anxiety of missing a profitable opportunity, frequently pushes investors to act impulsively, particularly during market highs. The survey revealed that 58% of crypto holders frequently make decisions influenced by FOMO, with 26% occasionally succumbing to its effects.</p>
<p>FUD, on the other hand, often causes hesitation or panic. Despite this, many respondents acknowledged that their reactions to these emotions had caused them to miss long-term opportunities. In fact, 88% of investors said they felt they had missed out on major gains.</p>
<p>Age and gender differences play a role in emotional investing. Investors aged 45 to 60 were the most likely to feel they missed out on early gains (78%) but were also the most optimistic about the future, with 74% expressing confidence in significant returns ahead.</p>
<p>Gender disparities were also evident, as men reported more frequent decisions based on FOMO (66%) compared to women (42%). Male investors also expressed higher regret, with 70% believing they had missed out on major gains, versus 48% of female respondents.</p>
<h2>Social media influence</h2>
<p>Social media emerged as a major factor influencing trading behavior.</p>
<p>Among respondents who relied on platforms like Twitter or Instagram for market insights, 85% reported significant portfolio impacts from emotional trades. The rapid flow of information often amplifies FOMO and FUD, making it challenging for investors to maintain a rational approach.</p>
<p>Despite the challenges, many investors are turning to strategies designed to reduce impulsive decisions. The survey found that 59% of respondents use dollar-cost averaging (DCA), a method involving regular investments regardless of price fluctuations.</p>
<p>Other tools gaining traction include automated recurring buys, custom orders to target specific prices, and AI trading bots to eliminate emotional bias. These strategies help investors focus on long-term goals rather than reacting to short-term market movements.</p>
<p>Despite the prevalence of FOMO and FUD, 84% of respondents <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-top-two-choice-for-etf-investors-in-latest-schwab-survey/">remain hopeful</a> about the future of crypto. Older investors, particularly those aged 45 and up, displayed the highest levels of optimism, with many believing significant gains still lie ahead.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-survey-reveals-crypto-holders-struggle-with-emotional-trading-decisions/">Kraken survey reveals crypto holders&#8217; struggle with emotional trading decisions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-survey-reveals-crypto-holders-struggle-with-emotional-trading-decisions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/kraken-blockchain-security.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/kraken-blockchain-security.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin hits historic $100,000 price level as 1,000 sats now equal $1</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-historic-100000-price-level-as-1000-sats-now-equal-1/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-historic-100000-price-level-as-1000-sats-now-equal-1/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 03:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Watch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For the first time, Bitcoin has surpassed the $100,000 mark, pushing its market capitalization to $2 trillion. This milestone follows a series of new all-time highs over the past few weeks, fueled by market momentum after the U.S. presidential election. The election of Donald Trump, who has promised pro-cryptocurrency policies, contributed to Bitcoin&#8217;s surge. Since [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-historic-100000-price-level-as-1000-sats-now-equal-1/">Bitcoin hits historic $100,000 price level as 1,000 sats now equal $1</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For the first time, <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> has surpassed the $100,000 mark, pushing its market capitalization to $2 trillion. This milestone follows a series of new all-time highs over the past few weeks, fueled by market momentum after the U.S. presidential election.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The election of Donald Trump, who has promised pro-cryptocurrency policies, contributed to Bitcoin&#8217;s surge. Since his victory in early November, Bitcoin&#8217;s price has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-etfs-record-1-billion-inflows-in-2-days-as-new-price-peak-boosts-investments/">climbed</a> over 30%, reaching $93,400 on Nov. 13.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The digital asset continued to set records, hitting $93,900 on Nov. 19 and $94,300 on Nov. 20. On Nov. 21, Bitcoin soared to $98,200 before retracing to around $97,000, coming within 3% of the $100,000 milestone. The following day, it was denied again at $99,600, which led to a decline to $90,700 by Nov. 26. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">By Nov. 29, Bitcoin managed to reclaim $98,000 again but failed to sustain the momentum amid a surge in leverage to all-time highs. The next few days saw the flagship crypto trading in a tight sideways range between $93,000 and $97,250 before finally reclaiming $99,000 late on Dec. 3.</span></p>
<p>Bitcoin took three hours from there to decisively break the six-figure level as Asia began Dec. 4 trading. BTC was trading at $101,450 as of press time, up 6.64% over the past 24 hours.</p>
<h2><b>Bitcoin&#8217;s Price History</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin&#8217;s journey to $100,000 marks a significant milestone since its inception in 2009, when it held little to no monetary value. The first recorded price of Bitcoin was in 2010 when it was worth less than $0.10. By February 2011, Bitcoin had reached $1, and later in June 2011, it briefly exceeded $30. However, this early bubble burst, and Bitcoin&#8217;s price fell back to around $2 by the end of 2011.</span></p>
<h3><b>2012-2013: Halving and Major Rally</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In November 2012, Bitcoin experienced its first &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/post-halving-bitcoin-miners-are-choosing-between-hodling-btc-and-upgrading-to-ai/">halving&#8221;</a> event, where the reward for mining new blocks was cut in half. By the end of 2013, Bitcoin had reached $1,000, marking its first major rally. The years following saw Bitcoin go through significant volatility, including a decline to around $200 in 2015 before slowly stabilizing and growing stronger by 2016.</span></p>
<h3><b>2017: The Turning Point</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">2017 marked a turning point for Bitcoin, as the price started at around $1,000 and skyrocketed to nearly $20,000 by December. This surge brought Bitcoin into the mainstream spotlight, but it was followed by a prolonged bear market in 2018 known as the &#8220;crypto winter,&#8221; where the price fell to around $3,700 by the end of the year.</span></p>
<h3><b>2019-2020: Recovery and Pandemic Impact</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The price began to recover in 2019, and by 2020, despite the COVID-19 pandemic causing a sharp drop in March, Bitcoin ended the year at nearly $29,000. The rally continued into 2021, with Bitcoin reaching new all-time highs of $64,895 in April and $69,000 in November. The collapse of major crypto firms in 2022 led to a significant downturn, but Bitcoin began to recover again in 2023, surpassing $40,000 by the end of the year.</span></p>
<h2><b>2024: Breaking New Records</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The breach of the $100,000 mark in 2024 signifies a pivotal moment for the crypto market, reflecting increased institutional adoption, investor confidence, and strategic Bitcoin <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blackrock-supports-us-strategic-bitcoin-reserve-amid-rumors-of-executive-order/">reserve legislation</a>. Bitcoin&#8217;s ascent past $100,000 solidifies its position in global finance, underscoring its growing acceptance among investors and institutions alike.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-historic-100000-price-level-as-1000-sats-now-equal-1/">Bitcoin hits historic $100,000 price level as 1,000 sats now equal $1</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-historic-100000-price-level-as-1000-sats-now-equal-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/bitcoin-uptober.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/bitcoin-uptober.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After XRP surge, price now compares to America&#8217;s top 100 companies by market cap</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-xrp-price-surge-comapres-it-to-americas-top-100-companies-by-market-cap/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-xrp-price-surge-comapres-it-to-americas-top-100-companies-by-market-cap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 13:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>XRP&#8217;s price surge propelled its market capitalization past $150 billion, which would place it among the top 100 companies in the United States if it were a corporate entity. Data from CryptoSlate shows that the digital asset, whose value more than doubled in the past month to as high as $2.82 on Dec. 3, significantly [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-xrp-price-surge-comapres-it-to-americas-top-100-companies-by-market-cap/">After XRP surge, price now compares to America&#8217;s top 100 companies by market cap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP&#8217;s</a> price surge propelled its market capitalization past $150 billion, which would place it among the top 100 companies in the United States if it were a corporate entity.</p>
<p>Data from <em>CryptoSlate</em> shows that the digital asset, whose value <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">more than doubled in the past month</a> to as high as $2.82 on Dec. 3, significantly <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/">outperformed Bitcoin by a staggering 200%</a>.</p>
<p>While XRP&#8217;s price has slightly retraced to $2.61 as of press time, the asset still registered an impressive 409% increase after the November US elections.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, this surge has helped boost XRP&#8217;s market cap to around $150 billion, a more than five-times increase from around $28 billion at the beginning of November. XRP now ranks as the third-largest crypto, trailing only Bitcoin and Ethereum but surpassing Tether&#8217;s USDT stablecoin, the Binance-backed BNB Coin and Solana network.</p>
<p>Market analysts attribute this growth to several factors, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/">growing institutional interest</a>. There is optimism that a more crypto-friendly regulatory environment under the upcoming administration could further benefit both XRP and Ripple.</p>
<h2>XRP&#8217;s corporate comparisons</h2>
<p>According to CompanyMarketCap <a href="https://companiesmarketcap.com/usa/largest-companies-in-the-usa-by-market-cap/">data</a>, if XRP were classified as a standalone company, its market cap would rank it among the top 100 US firms, surpassing notable companies like Nike and financial institutions like Charles Schwab.</p>
<p>Further analysis with <a href="https://stockanalysis.com/list/sp-500-stocks/">Stock Analysis</a> suggests that XRP would be the 68th largest company in the S&amp;P 500, surpassing 86% of the stocks within the index.</p>
<p>Specifically, XRP would be valued higher than pharmaceutical giant Pfizer ($144 billion), Citigroup ($136 billion), and defense contractor Lockheed Martin ($122.5 billion). However, it would trail behind <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blackrock/">BlackRock</a>, the world&#8217;s largest asset management firm, with a market value of $160 billion, and Uber, the ride-hailing transportation company, with a valuation of $150 billion.</p>
<p>XRP&#8217;s market value would also be more than three times greater than that of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/nasdaq/">NASDAQ</a>, valued at $46.55 billion, and gaming firm Electronic Arts, worth $43.98 billion.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 Index, which tracks 500 of the largest publicly traded companies in the US, is a key performance benchmark for the American stock market. While it is not exclusively based on market cap, it is widely regarded as a critical measure of the performance of major US equities.</p>
<p><em>UPDATE: Removed mention of Ripple in headline and first paragraph.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-xrp-price-surge-comapres-it-to-americas-top-100-companies-by-market-cap/">After XRP surge, price now compares to America&#8217;s top 100 companies by market cap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-xrp-price-surge-comapres-it-to-americas-top-100-companies-by-market-cap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-ripple-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-ripple-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardano and XRP outperform Bitcoin by over 200% as developers hard work pays off</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 12:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Watch]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cardano (ADA) and the XRP Ledger (XRP) have started outperforming Bitcoin amid expectations of regulatory changes under the incoming Trump administration. Both tokens have surged remarkably since the US presidential election, capturing investor attention and signaling a potential realignment in the digital asset landscape. While the two previously underperforming coins have felt the pressure of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/">Cardano and XRP outperform Bitcoin by over 200% as developers hard work pays off</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cardano (<a href="/coins/cardano">ADA</a>) and the XRP Ledger (XRP) have started outperforming Bitcoin amid expectations of regulatory changes under the incoming Trump administration. Both tokens have surged remarkably since the US presidential election, capturing investor attention and signaling a potential realignment in the digital asset landscape.</p>
<p>While the two previously underperforming coins have felt the pressure of Gary Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-enforcement-to-take-a-back-seat-under-trump-as-immigration-becomes-priority/">regulation through enforcement</a>&#8216; tactics, developers continued to build, and business partnerships were secured. Now, the regulatory landscape in thUSUS looks to be about to perform a 180. Investors see ADA and XRP as value plays whose prices haven&#8217;t accurately reflected the projects&#8217; capabilities and potential.</p>
<h2>ADA&#8217;s meteoric surge fueled by regulatory optimism and technical advancements</h2>
<p>Cardano&#8217;s ADA token has seen an impressive 275% increase over the past 30 days, soaring above $1.20 and maintaining its momentum. This surge outpaces Bitcoin&#8217;s 38% rise to just shy of $100,000 before a slight retracement to around $95,000 as of press time. The catalyst behind ADA&#8217;s exceptional performance mainly anticipates a more favorable regulatory environment under President-elect Donald Trump.</p>
<p>Previously, ADA faced headwinds due to regulatory scrutiny, notably being <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sol-matic-ada-gain-over-20-on-bitcoin-as-sec-targeted-tokens-see-mixed-performance/">cited</a> by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in actions against major exchanges. The election outcome has shifted market sentiment, with participants expecting the new administration to alleviate regulatory pressures on digital assets like ADA. The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-chair-gary-gensler-to-step-down-on-jan-20/">resignation</a> of SEC Chair Gary Gensler has further fueled optimism for a crypto-friendly regulatory approach.</p>
<p>In addition to regulatory factors, Cardano&#8217;s ongoing technical developments have bolstered investor confidence. The platform has implemented significant network <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hoskinson-hails-cardanos-chang-hard-fork-as-dwarfing-bitcoin/">upgrades</a>, including Chang to increase decentralized governance, Hydra for enhanced scalability, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/how-will-cardano-scale-to-meet-the-demands-of-its-burgeoning-dapp-ecosystem/">Mithril</a> for efficient consensus mechanisms. These advancements have improved the ecosystem&#8217;s functionality, fostering a thriving environment for decentralized applications and strategic partnerships that enhance the network&#8217;s utility.</p>
<p>Whale activity around ADA has intensified, with wallets holding over $10 million worth of the token, increasing their <a href="https://x.com/ali_charts/status/1859094317819715649">holdings</a> by over 140%. Trading volume has also <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-defi-tvl-nears-record-700m-ada-skyrockets-20/">surged</a>, indicating growing interest from both retail and institutional investors.</p>
<p>Cardano&#8217;s focus on scalability, interoperability, and sustainability remains central to its growth strategy. In the Volatire development phase, the project aims to execute decentralized governance mechanisms, positioning Cardano as a robust and adaptable blockchain platform.</p>
<h2>XRP surges as business developments bear fruits</h2>
<p>Simultaneously, XRP has surged to become the third-largest digital asset by market capitalization. The token&#8217;s value climbed to $2.84, its highest level in seven years, surpassing major cryptocurrencies like Solana, USDT, and Binance Coin. Since the election, XRP has attracted over $120 billion in new <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/">investment</a> product purchases, helping to push its market cap to $162 billion.</p>
<p>Investors are optimistic that the incoming administration will adopt a more supportive stance toward cryptocurrencies, potentially benefiting XRP and Ripple&#8217;s operations. The anticipated regulatory shift is further accentuated by the possible <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/">approval</a> of an XRP Exchange-Traded Fund (ETF). Such a development could significantly increase institutional adoption and liquidity for XRP.</p>
<p>XRP has been under regulatory scrutiny since December 2020, when the SEC charged Ripple and two executives with conducting a $1.3 billion unregistered securities offering. The legal battle has weighed on XRP&#8217;s performance, but impending changes to the SEC leadership indicate an easing of regulatory pressures. Optimism about reduced legal hurdles has contributed to the token&#8217;s recent surge.</p>
<p>Technological advancements on the XRP Ledger have also enhanced the token&#8217;s appeal. The account reserve fee was reduced by 90%, from 10 XRP to 1 XRP, <a href="https://x.com/Vet_X0/status/1863722673777291532">significantly</a> lowering the network&#8217;s cost. The reserve fee for NFTs also decreased from 2 XRP to 0.2 XRP, making it more accessible for users and developers.</p>
<p>Ripple&#8217;s collaborations with financial institutions have further strengthened XRP&#8217;s prospects. The company <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-launches-first-tokenized-money-market-fund-on-xrp-ledger-through-uk-partnership/">introduced</a> tokenized money market funds on the XRP Ledger, signaling growing real-world use cases for the token. This move aligns with Ripple&#8217;s strategy to expand XRP&#8217;s utility within the global financial system.</p>
<p>Ripple&#8217;s long-awaited <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-starts-testing-its-stablecoin-rlusd-on-xrp-ledger-and-ethereum/">stablecoin</a>, RLUSD, is reportedly poised for launch <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/">tomorrow</a> amid regulatory approval in New York. This development could open new avenues for XRP&#8217;s utility in the financial sector. Meanwhile, Ripple continues unlocking 1 billion XRP tokens monthly but has immediately relocked 770 million tokens for another five years, showcasing a commitment to market stability.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin&#8217;s performance makes way for altcoin surge.</h2>
<p>While Bitcoin has reached new all-time highs, its recent gains have been outpaced by ADA and XRP&#8217;s. Bitcoin soared to $99,600 on Nov. 22 before settling around $95,000, remaining less than 5% shy of the $100,000 milestone. The outperformance of ADA and XRP highlights a shift in market conditions, where alternative cryptocurrencies are capturing significant investor attention.</p>
<p>The expected policy changes under the new administration have injected optimism into the market, particularly for tokens previously hindered by regulatory constraints.</p>
<p>Cardano and Ripple&#8217;s commitment to enhancing their platforms through continuous development has positioned them favorably in this newly emerging landscape. Their focus on scalability, efficiency, and real-world applications appears to resonate with investors seeking to capitalize on blockchain technology, which is free to grow without aggressive regulation by enforcement.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/">Cardano and XRP outperform Bitcoin by over 200% as developers hard work pays off</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-cardano-price-surge.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-cardano-price-surge.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin&#8217;s path to $100K hinges on short-term holder demand – Bitfinex</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-path-to-100k-hinges-on-short-term-holder-demand-bitfinex/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-path-to-100k-hinges-on-short-term-holder-demand-bitfinex/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 01:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s (BTC) journey to a potential $100,000 price point will depend on the balance between short-term holder (STH) demand and long-term holder (LTH) profit-taking, according to the latest edition of the &#8220;Bitfinex Alpha&#8221; report. Despite a sharp 8.64% intra-week pullback over the past few days, Bitcoin&#8217;s price surged to a record monthly close of $96,506 [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-path-to-100k-hinges-on-short-term-holder-demand-bitfinex/">Bitcoin&#8217;s path to $100K hinges on short-term holder demand – Bitfinex</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin&#8217;s (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) journey to a potential $100,000 price point will depend on the balance between short-term holder (STH) demand and long-term holder (LTH) profit-taking, according to the <a href="https://blog.bitfinex.com/bitfinex-alpha/bitfinex-alpha-btc-to-break-100k-if-sth-demand-can-meet-lth-supply/">latest edition</a> of the &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitfinex/">Bitfinex</a> Alpha&#8221;</span> report<span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite a sharp 8.64% intra-week pullback over the past few days, Bitcoin&#8217;s price surged to a record monthly close of $96,506 by the end of November.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The recovery came after Bitcoin dipped to $90,911 on Nov. 26, the largest decline since a pre-election sell-off in October. Despite the brief pullback, November saw Bitcoin gain 37.3%, the second-best monthly performance of the year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin&#8217;s strong momentum heading into December is seen as a positive signal. The report forecasted a continuation of the upward trend, particularly given BTC&#8217;s historical performance during halving years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past, halving years have seen exceptional price growth, with Bitcoin typically seeing an average increase of 38.86%. However, the report also suggests that December may see heightened volatility, especially as it coincides with the most significant options expiry of the year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, recent Bitcoin supply and demand trends suggest that the market could experience a temporary pullback before reaching new highs.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Supply trends</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the medium-term outlook for Bitcoin remains bullish, concerns about a short-term pullback persist. The report highlighted the sustained distribution of Bitcoin from long-term holders (LTHs) as a critical factor influencing price conditions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past two weeks, LTHs have capitalized on the increased demand by resuming large-scale distribution of their holdings. Since the peak in LTH supply in September, approximately 508,990 BTC has been distributed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This distribution level, while substantial, is still smaller than the 934,000 BTC sold during the rally leading to the March high of $73,666. Yet, it remains a critical factor in the short-term outlook. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the demand from short-term holders (STHs) and marginal buyers does not match the supply being offloaded by LTHs, Bitcoin could experience further price volatility and a deeper pullback before continuing its ascent.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">STH supply is nearing its cycle high of 3,282,000 BTC, with just over 3.25 million BTC held by short-term buyers. Historically, the final leg of Bitcoin&#8217;s bull market is triggered when STH supply surpasses pre-halving cycle highs.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> If STH demand can meet or exceed the supply from LTHs, Bitcoin could see continued upward momentum. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Long-Term Holder SOPR (Spent Output Profit Ratio), which tracks the profit margin at which LTHs sell their Bitcoin, currently sits at 2.6.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Notably, market tops have occurred when the SOPR is above 3, indicating a more significant profit-taking phase. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The current level suggests that while LTHs are still selling, they have yet to reach the peak of their distribution, leaving room for further upward movement if STH demand remains strong.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Outlook for December</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If the market can absorb the supply from LTHs, the path to $100,000 becomes increasingly likely. The report noted that while typically volatile, Bitcoin&#8217;s performance in December could remain neutral to positive due to the strong momentum from November, combined with the halving-year effects that often boost Bitcoin&#8217;s price.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the volatility expected in the latter part of the month — due to options expiring and the potential for profit-taking — could create short-term price fluctuations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report cautioned that traders and investors must remain vigilant in the coming weeks, monitoring both the supply trends and the demand from short-term holders to gauge Bitcoin&#8217;s next move.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With LTHs continuing to distribute, the key scenario for Bitcoin in the short term is whether enough new demand can enter the market to support the continued upward momentum. If the balance tips favor short-term holders, the $100,000 threshold may not be far off — but until then, volatility will likely remain a fixture in Bitcoin&#8217;s price action.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-path-to-100k-hinges-on-short-term-holder-demand-bitfinex/">Bitcoin&#8217;s path to $100K hinges on short-term holder demand – Bitfinex</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-path-to-100k-hinges-on-short-term-holder-demand-bitfinex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/spot-bitcoin-cboe.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/spot-bitcoin-cboe.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardano DeFi TVL nears record $700 million, ADA skyrockets 20%</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-defi-tvl-nears-record-700m-ada-skyrockets-20/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-defi-tvl-nears-record-700m-ada-skyrockets-20/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 21:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TVL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cardano&#8217;s DeFi ecosystem is hitting new heights, with its total value locked (TVL) nearing an all-time high of $700 million. DeFillama data shows that the blockchain network is riding the current bullish market sentiment by adding over $400 million to reach $680 million as of press time. This number marks a massive turnaround for the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-defi-tvl-nears-record-700m-ada-skyrockets-20/">Cardano DeFi TVL nears record $700 million, ADA skyrockets 20%</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Cardano&#8217;s DeFi ecosystem is hitting new heights, with its total value locked (TVL) nearing an all-time high of $700 million.</p>
<p>DeFillama <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Cardano">data</a> shows that the blockchain network is riding the current bullish market sentiment by adding over $400 million to reach $680 million as of press time. This number marks a massive turnaround for the blockchain network, which saw its TVL drop to as low as around $50 million in November 2022 following FTX&#8217;s shock collapse.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455551" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455551" style="width: 1081px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455551" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-172208.jpg" alt="Cardano DeFi" width="1081" height="373" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-172208.jpg 1081w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-172208-300x104.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-172208-1024x353.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-172208-768x265.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1081px) 100vw, 1081px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455551" class="wp-caption-text">Cardano DeFi (Source: DeFillama)</figcaption></figure>
<p>TVL is often seen as a barometer for the health and trust of a DeFi ecosystem. The metric reflects a blockchain network&#8217;s growing appeal in the crypto space, with an increase signaling a surge in investor&#8217;s confidence in the platform.</p>
<p>In addition to its TVL growth, Cardano&#8217;s decentralized exchanges (DEXs) reported a trading volume of $22.35 million in the past day, the highest since December 2023. <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">According to DeFillama data, weekly DEX trading volume also hit $117.32 million, marking the best performance since May 2023</span>.</p>
<p>Speaking on these numbers, Cardano founder Charles Hoskinson <a href="https://x.com/IOHK_Charles/status/1863310791786500316">said</a> they represent the dawn of DeFi activity on the blockchain network while highlighting the ecosystem&#8217;s progress and growing adoption.</p>
<h2>ADA price rally</h2>
<p>The improved DeFi activities come as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/altcoins-bag-massive-gains-amid-bitcoins-climb-stellar-cardano-and-kusama-up-double-digits/">Cardano&#8217;s ADA token</a> has emerged as a top performer during the current market uptrend.</p>
<p>Over the past week, the crypto asset has gained more than 20%, reaching a peak of $1.21. <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">According to <em>CryptoSlate </em>data, this is ADA&#8217;s highest price level since 2022</span>.</p>
<p>This momentum has propelled Cardano&#8217;s market capitalization to over $40 billion, making it the ninth-largest digital asset globally. The rally aligns with broader <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">bullish market conditions</a> and several ecosystem advancements.</p>
<p>Market observers noted that recent developments — including the implementation of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-deploys-first-zero-knowledge-smart-contract-expanding-blockchain-capabilities/">Zero-Knowledge (ZK) technology</a> and the transition towards <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-chang-hard-fork-to-redefine-decentralized-governance-from-sept-1/">decentralized governance</a> — have boosted <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-charles-hoskinson-envisions-defi-powered-bitcoin-ecosystem/">Cardano&#8217;s prospects</a>.</p>
<p>According to them, these innovations have provided a strong foundation for sustained growth and solidified the network&#8217;s position as a critical player in the crypto space.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-defi-tvl-nears-record-700m-ada-skyrockets-20/">Cardano DeFi TVL nears record $700 million, ADA skyrockets 20%</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-defi-tvl-nears-record-700m-ada-skyrockets-20/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cardano.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cardano.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Michael Saylor tells Microsoft board Bitcoin could boost its market cap by $5 trillion</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/michael-saylor-tells-microsoft-board-bitcoin-could-boost-its-market-cap-by-5-trillion/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/michael-saylor-tells-microsoft-board-bitcoin-could-boost-its-market-cap-by-5-trillion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MicroStrategy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>MicroStrategy executive chairman Michael Saylor has urged Microsoft to adopt Bitcoin as part of its strategy, according to a three-minute presentation to the company&#8217;s board that was shared on X (formerly Twitter). In the presentation, Saylor positioned Bitcoin as a critical component of the next technological wave. He warned that failing to integrate Bitcoin into [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/michael-saylor-tells-microsoft-board-bitcoin-could-boost-its-market-cap-by-5-trillion/">Michael Saylor tells Microsoft board Bitcoin could boost its market cap by $5 trillion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microstrategy/">MicroStrategy</a> executive chairman <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/michael-saylor/">Michael Saylor</a> has urged <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> to adopt <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> as part of its strategy, according to a three-minute <a href="https://x.com/saylor/status/1863323760511627565">presentation</a> to the company&#8217;s board that was shared on X (formerly Twitter).</p>
<p>In the presentation, Saylor positioned Bitcoin as a critical component of the next technological wave. He warned that failing to integrate Bitcoin into Microsoft&#8217;s operations could leave the company lagging behind competitors.</p>
<p>Saylor emphasized Bitcoin&#8217;s outperformance, noting it has delivered returns ten times higher than Microsoft&#8217;s stock annually. He argued that redirecting resources from stock buybacks to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chinese-data-miner-sos-stock-surges-100-after-board-approves-50-million-bitcoin-investment/">Bitcoin investments</a> would generate greater value.</p>
<p>He stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Microsoft can’t afford to miss the next technology wave and Bitcoin is that wave&#8230;It makes a lot more sense to buy Bitcoin than to buy your own stock back.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>According to him, Microsoft&#8217;s current treasury strategy is weakening its equity and options markets and eroding its position as a store of value.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455448" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455448" style="width: 1188px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455448" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125543.jpg" alt="Microsoft's Equity " width="1188" height="679" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125543.jpg 1188w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125543-300x171.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125543-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125543-768x439.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1188px) 100vw, 1188px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455448" class="wp-caption-text">Microsoft&#8217;s Current Equity Performance (Source: Michael Saylor)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Saylor also outlined a transformative roadmap for the Bitcoin ecosystem in 2025. This includes widespread <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/morgan-stanley-first-in-wall-street-to-authorize-spot-bitcoin-etfs-for-wealthy-clients/">Wall Street adoption of Bitcoin ETFs</a>, favorable fair-value accounting rules, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/220-pro-crypto-candidates-elected-in-us-while-elizabeth-warren-retains-seat-amid-bitcoin-all-time-high/">pro-crypto leadership in Congress</a>, and a shift in regulatory attitudes. He believes this evolving landscape makes Bitcoin adoption not just advantageous but essential.</p>
<p>He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;You have a choice to make: cling to the past, or embrace the future. Divest billions of dollars and slow your growth rate, invest billions of dollars and accelerate your growth rate.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>$5 trillion addition to Microsoft&#8217;s market cap</h2>
<p>As part of his pitch, Saylor projected that an aggressive <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/microstrategys-michael-saylor-to-pitch-bitcoin-strategy-to-microsofts-board/">Bitcoin strategy</a> could add around $5 trillion to Microsoft&#8217;s market cap over the next decade.</p>
<p>He proposed converting Microsoft&#8217;s cash flows, dividend payouts, and stock buybacks into Bitcoin. He argued that this would add hundreds of dollars to the company&#8217;s stock price while minimizing shareholder risk.</p>
<p>Based on his projections, if Bitcoin reaches $1.7 million per coin by 2034, Microsoft could gain $4.9 trillion in enterprise value.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455444" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455444" style="width: 1240px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-455444 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125342.jpg" alt="Microsoft Bitcoin Adoption" width="1240" height="693" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125342.jpg 1240w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125342-300x168.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125342-1024x572.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Screenshot-2024-12-02-125342-768x429.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1240px) 100vw, 1240px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455444" class="wp-caption-text">Microsoft&#8217;s Predicted Market Cap if it Adopts Bitcoin (Source: Michael Saylor)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Saylor also suggested investing $100 billion annually in Bitcoin instead of stock repurchases or bonds. He described Bitcoin as an asset free from counterparty risk, offering unmatched security and growth potential.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/michael-saylor-tells-microsoft-board-bitcoin-could-boost-its-market-cap-by-5-trillion/">Michael Saylor tells Microsoft board Bitcoin could boost its market cap by $5 trillion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/michael-saylor-tells-microsoft-board-bitcoin-could-boost-its-market-cap-by-5-trillion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/michael-saylor-microsoft.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/michael-saylor-microsoft.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>XRP flips Solana market cap, soars to seven-year high fueled by South Korean traders</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 09:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ripple&#8216;s XRP experienced a remarkable surge over the weekend, crossing the $2 mark for the first time in nearly seven years. Data from CryptoSlate shows that XRP reached a peak of $2.50, the highest price since January 2018, before stabilizing at $2.27 at press time. Despite this slight pullback, XRP has seen a daily increase [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">XRP flips Solana market cap, soars to seven-year high fueled by South Korean traders</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ripple/">Ripple</a>&#8216;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a> experienced a remarkable surge over the weekend, crossing the $2 mark for the first time in nearly seven years.</p>
<p>Data from <em>CryptoSlate</em> shows that XRP reached a peak of $2.50, the highest price since January 2018, before stabilizing at $2.27 at press time.</p>
<p>Despite this slight pullback, XRP has seen a daily increase of 20%, boosting its weekly gains to 54%. Over the past month, the token&#8217;s value has surged by 345%, marking an impressive fourfold rise.</p>
<p>This rally elevated XRP to the fourth spot among the top crypto by market capitalization, overtaking <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a>. XRP&#8217;s market cap is now $133.9 billion, while Solana trails at $112 billion.</p>
<p><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">If it maintains its current momentum, XRP&#8217;s market cap will surpass that of Tether&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tether/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDT,</a> currently at $134 billion.</span></p>
<h2>South Korean traders&#8217; fuel run</h2>
<p>A significant portion of XRP&#8217;s recent surge is attributed to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-trades-at-discount-in-korea-destroying-historical-kimchi-premium/">South Korean traders</a>.</p>
<p>Blockchain analytics firm Scopescan <a href="https://x.com/0xScopescan/status/1863453005473034411">noted</a> that XRP/KRW trading volume on Upbit, South Korea&#8217;s largest exchange, hit $3.8 billion in the last 24 hours, outpacing <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> trades by 11 times.</p>
<p>On Bithumb, another major South Korean platform, XRP trades reached $1.2 billion, representing 32% of the exchange&#8217;s total volume.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, global platforms like Binance and OKX reported increased XRP activity, but Bitcoin and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> retained higher trading volumes.</p>
<p>Ryan Kim, co-founder of Hashed, highlighted the loyalty of South Korea&#8217;s XRP community. He linked this enthusiasm to early adoption campaigns in the country, suggesting that long-time investors are reaping significant returns.</p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/0xryankim/status/1863398806714536168">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Ripple Labs sold XRP to Korean Ajummas with Ponzi scheme in 2014. It called &#8216;Ripple Market Korea.&#8217; There were so many people invested in XRP back then. Probably they made so much money lol There is genuine XRP community in Korea and That&#8217;s why Korean are buying XRP a lot.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Other catalysts</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, XRP&#8217;s rally also coincides with a significant shift in market sentiment, fueled by regulatory optimism and institutional interest.</p>
<p>Market observers noted that President-elect <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/">Donald Trump&#8217;s</a> pro-crypto stance and the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-chair-gary-gensler-to-step-down-on-jan-20/">resignation</a> of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) Chair <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gary-gensler/">Gary Gensler</a> have renewed hope for a favorable outcome in Ripple&#8217;s legal battles against the financial regulator.</p>
<p>Further, the potential approval of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-latest-to-eye-spot-xrp-etf-amid-heightened-market-optimism/">XRP-focused spot ETFs</a> adds to the excitement. Major players like 21Shares and Bitwise have filed applications for such products, signaling increased institutional interest. Ripple CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/brad-garlinghouse/">Brad Garlinghouse</a> believes an XRP ETF is only a matter of time, especially after the SEC approved similar funds for Bitcoin and Ethereum.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">XRP flips Solana market cap, soars to seven-year high fueled by South Korean traders</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ripple-xrp.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ripple-xrp.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
