<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Banking News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/banking/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/banking/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 21:56:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Banking News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/banking/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>ECB unveils second report on digital euro, announces prototype testing for 2025</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 22:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The European Central Bank (ECB) has unveiled its second progress report on developing the digital euro central bank digital currency (CBDC), outlining advancements in the preparation phase and mentioning a prototype for 2025.  In the report, the ECB reaffirms its commitment to providing a secure and efficient digital payment solution that complements cash while safeguarding [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/">ECB unveils second report on digital euro, announces prototype testing for 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The European Central Bank (ECB) has unveiled its</span> <strong><a href="https://www.ecb.europa.eu/euro/digital_euro/progress/html/ecb.deprp202412.en.html">second progress report</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on developing the digital euro central bank digital currency (CBDC), outlining advancements in the preparation phase and mentioning a prototype for 2025. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the report, the ECB reaffirms its commitment to providing a secure and efficient digital payment solution that complements cash while safeguarding monetary stability. Additionally, the digital euro is seen as a way to ensure the future competitiveness of the Eurozone&#8217;s financial system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The digital euro aims to support the European Union&#8217;s digital economy by providing a reliable digital payment method that could be widely accepted by consumers, businesses, and governments across the region.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Key findings on digital euro</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ECB&#8217;s progress report focused on two primary areas: technical and legal considerations, and the ongoing public consultation process. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past year, the ECB has made significant strides in addressing the technical aspects of the digital euro, including improvements in infrastructure, security features, and integration with existing payment systems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ECB has also been working closely with stakeholders, including financial institutions, academics, and policymakers, to ensure that the digital euro can seamlessly incorporate into the current monetary and economic frameworks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report highlighted the importance of ensuring privacy protection and compliance with European Union regulations, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), in designing the digital euro.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, the document provides an update on the ongoing public consultation, which has garnered significant interest from citizens, businesses, and institutions. The ECB received feedback on a wide range of issues, including how the digital euro could improve payment efficiency, the potential risks to financial stability, and concerns around privacy and cybersecurity.</span></p>
<h2>Outlook</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The consultation results are expected to play a crucial role in shaping the next phase of the digital euro project. The ECB emphasized that the public&#8217;s input will be vital in determining the final design and implementation of the digital euro.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, the ECB is focused on preparing for the next phase of the digital euro project, which will involve more detailed design work and pilot testing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The central bank plans to begin testing prototypes of the digital euro in 2025. Depending on the outcome of the ongoing research and development phase, the currency could be launched in the following years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the ECB has not set a definitive timeline for the launch, it remains committed to ensuring that the digital euro is introduced in a way that supports the stability and security of the European financial system.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/">ECB unveils second report on digital euro, announces prototype testing for 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/ecb-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/ecb-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto debanking wave tied to political figures, Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong alleges</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-debanking-wave-tied-to-political-figures-coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-alleges/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-debanking-wave-tied-to-political-figures-coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-alleges/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 10:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Armstrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455021</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong has revealed ongoing efforts to obtain documentation through the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to uncover US banks&#8217; full scope of crypto-related account closures. In a Nov. 27 post on X, Armstrong &#8220;confirmed&#8221; that several banks have cut ties with crypto stakeholders solely due to their involvement in the industry. He [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-debanking-wave-tied-to-political-figures-coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-alleges/">Crypto debanking wave tied to political figures, Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong alleges</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/brian-armstrong/">Brian Armstrong</a> has revealed ongoing efforts to obtain documentation through the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to uncover US banks&#8217; full scope of crypto-related account closures.</p>
<p>In a Nov. 27 <a href="https://x.com/brian_armstrong/status/1861890800268775923?t=BqxUIZLVzhKNC-18kP5Gdg&amp;s=19">post</a> on X, Armstrong &#8220;confirmed&#8221; that several banks have cut ties with crypto stakeholders solely due to their involvement in the industry. He labeled these actions as unethical and contrary to American values.</p>
<p>Armstrong suggested that anti-crypto sentiment, fueled by figures like Senator <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/elizabeth-warren/">Elizabeth Warren</a> and outgoing SEC Chair <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gary-gensler/">Gary Gensler</a>, could be at the root of these decisions. He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;My guess is we&#8217;ll find Elizabeth Warren&#8217;s fingerprints all over it (Biden himself was probably unaware).&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>He noted that these actions may have contributed to recent political losses for the Democratic Party. Armstrong urged the party to distance itself from figures like Senator Warren, whom he labeled a liability to their future electoral prospects. He added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Warren and Gensler tried to unlawfully kill our entire industry, and it was a major factor in the Dems losing the election.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Operation Chokepoint 2.0</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, other crypto stakeholders have shared similar experiences of being denied access to financial services.</p>
<p>On Nov. 27, Roman Storm, a developer behind the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-developer-gets-help-in-court-from-blockchain-advocacy-groups/">controversial Tornado Cash project</a>, <a href="https://x.com/rstormsf/status/1861881857610228042?t=6peKC7AcFQgXSB1D-1vrOQ&amp;s=19">revealed</a> that he had faced repeated debanking due to his association with the sanctioned crypto mixer. He expressed frustration, stating that he has &#8220;lost count&#8221; of the times this has occurred over the past two and a half years.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-kazemian/">Sam Kazemian</a>, the founder of Frax Finance, shared a similar experience. He disclosed that JPMorgan Chase had informed him last December that they would close the accounts of individuals whose primary income stems from crypto.</p>
<p>He attributed the decision to directives from top executives, adding that most customers likely receive no explanation for such closures. He <a href="https://x.com/samkazemian/status/1861956394079101391">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I had a close relationship with my banker so I assume 99% of people wouldn&#8217;t even get that kind of transparency/explanation. Wanted to add my own name to the debanked OCP list. It&#8217;s real. It happened.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>These revelations align with statements made by venture capitalist <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/marc-andreessen/">Marc Andreessen</a>, who recently highlighted the issue on Joe Rogan&#8217;s podcast.</p>
<p>Andreessen accused the Biden administration of expanding &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fed-escalates-operation-chokepoint-2-0-crackdown-against-crypto-winklevoss/">Operation Choke Point</a>&#8220;—initially aimed at industries like firearms and marijuana—to target crypto and tech startups. According to Andreessen, at least 30 founders have been debanked in the last four years, with no warnings or avenues to appeal.</p>
<p>The crypto community has since adopted the term &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-fdic-has-told-banks-to-refrain-from-providing-crypto-services-in-over-20-cases-coinbase-finds/">Operation Choke Point 2.0</a>&#8221; to describe what they perceive as coordinated efforts by US regulators to undermine the sector.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-debanking-wave-tied-to-political-figures-coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-alleges/">Crypto debanking wave tied to political figures, Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong alleges</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-debanking-wave-tied-to-political-figures-coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-alleges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/crypto-us.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/crypto-us.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian central bank in ‘no hurry&#8217; to rollout CBDC nationwide</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is adopting a cautious approach to the nationwide rollout of its Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC), the e-rupee, prioritizing financial stability and a thorough understanding of its potential impacts. Deputy Governor T. Rabi Sankar emphasized that the bank is &#8220;in no hurry to roll it out immediately,&#8221; indicating a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/">Indian central bank in ‘no hurry&#8217; to rollout CBDC nationwide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is adopting a cautious approach to the nationwide rollout of its Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC), the e-rupee, prioritizing financial stability and a thorough understanding of its potential impacts.</p>
<p>Deputy Governor T. Rabi Sankar emphasized that the bank is &#8220;in no hurry to roll it out immediately,&#8221; indicating a deliberate strategy to assess outcomes before broader implementation, Bloomberg News <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-20/india-expanding-payment-links-with-more-countries-rbi-says">reported</a> on Nov. 20.</p>
<h2>Evaluating long-term impact</h2>
<p>The e-rupee pilot, launched in December 2022, has made steady but modest progress, amassing over 5 million users and facilitating roughly 1 million retail transactions by mid-2024. Despite these numbers, Sankar highlighted the importance of e<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/csao-region-becomes-global-crypto-hub-with-india-singapore-and-indonesia-leading-the-charge-chainalysis/">valuating the long-term impac</a>t before scaling up.</p>
<p>He said during a conference in Cebu, Philippines:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Once we have clarity on the outcomes and potential effects, we will take the next steps.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The Reserve Bank&#8217;s deliberate approach reflects concerns about how CBDCs could disrupt traditional banking. Deputy Governor Michael Debabrata Patra previously noted that CBDCs might attract depositors during financial instability, posing risks to banks by encouraging mass withdrawals.</p>
<p>To mitigate such challenges, the central bank has limited its CBDC rollout to controlled experiments. Local banks participating in the pilot, such as ICICI Bank and State Bank of India, have introduced incentives like salary disbursements via e-rupee to encourage adoption.</p>
<p>Despite the reservations, regulators in the country have previously stated that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/india-favors-cbdcs-over-crypto-like-bitcoin-despite-top-rank-in-global-adoption/">they prefer a nationwide CBDC</a> over private digital currencies like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a>.</p>
<h2>Evolving features</h2>
<p>India is also enhancing the e-rupee&#8217;s functionality, including developing offline transfer capabilities to boost accessibility. Governor Shaktikanta Das acknowledged, however, that adoption remains far from the levels achieved by the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), India&#8217;s leading digital payments platform.</p>
<p>The wholesale e-rupee program has focused on interbank transactions and government securities trading, with nine major financial institutions participating. These trials aim to refine the currency’s operational design and identify key use cases.</p>
<p>India’s approach mirrors the global trajectory of CBDC development. According to the Atlantic Council, over 130 nations are actively exploring digital currencies, with countries like China and Nigeria already advancing their CBDC programs.</p>
<p>As India observes international developments, its central bank remains committed to ensuring that the e-rupee strengthens the financial system without compromising stability.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/">Indian central bank in ‘no hurry&#8217; to rollout CBDC nationwide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/india-cbdc.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/india-cbdc.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goldman Sachs sets sights on standalone blockchain entity for digital assets expansion</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-sets-sights-on-standalone-blockchain-entity-for-digital-assets-expansion/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-sets-sights-on-standalone-blockchain-entity-for-digital-assets-expansion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 18:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TradFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Goldman Sachs is charting a bold new course in financial technology, unveiling plans to transform its digital assets platform into a standalone blockchain-focused entity, Bloomberg News reported on Nov. 18. The initiative, slated for completion within the next 12 to 18 months, seeks to modernize the trading, settlement, and management of financial instruments. It is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-sets-sights-on-standalone-blockchain-entity-for-digital-assets-expansion/">Goldman Sachs sets sights on standalone blockchain entity for digital assets expansion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/goldman-sachs/">Goldman Sachs</a> is charting a bold new course in financial technology, unveiling plans to transform its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-eyes-tokenization-projects-for-institutional-clients-by-year-end/">digital assets platform</a> into a standalone blockchain-focused entity, Bloomberg News <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-18/goldman-readies-plans-to-spin-out-its-digital-assets-platform">reported</a> on Nov. 18.</p>
<p>The initiative, slated for completion within the next 12 to 18 months, seeks to modernize the trading, settlement, and management of financial instruments. It is currently pending regulatory approval.</p>
<p>The new company will cater to institutional clients, enabling them to execute transactions involving traditional assets like bonds and cash through blockchain while also expanding capabilities to serve private digital asset markets.</p>
<p>Goldman&#8217;s vision for the platform includes collaboration with Tradeweb Markets Inc., a leading electronic trading platform, which has joined as its first strategic partner. The partnership seeks to explore blockchain-based use cases that enhance efficiency across financial markets.</p>
<h2>Betting on blockchain</h2>
<p>Goldman’s decision reflects an industry-wide shift toward leveraging blockchain for operational efficiency. The firm intends to modernize financial workflows by adopting decentralized ledger technology, which will enable faster transactions and greater transparency.</p>
<p>The company is also eyeing secondary markets for digital asset firms, addressing a growing need for streamlined solutions in this evolving sector. Meanwhile, planned tokenization projects aim to provide institutional clients with new tools to diversify their portfolios and access emerging opportunities.</p>
<p>The initiative aligns with the lender&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-ceo-says-bitcoin-can-potentially-serve-as-store-of-value-akin-to-gold/">positive outlook</a> on blockchain and digital assets. Despite market volatility, the firm has remained optimistic about the long-term role of Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) and blockchain in institutional finance. Bitcoin&#8217;s recent rise to $93,000 has reinforced this confidence.</p>
<p>Goldman&#8217;s investments in Bitcoin ETFs and other blockchain-backed financial products underline its strategic commitment to digital assets. Earlier this year, the firm partnered with DRW Capital to deploy <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/goldman-sachs-discloses-nearly-420-million-in-bitcoin-etf-holdings/">$600 million</a> across spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs, signaling its readiness to capitalize on the sector&#8217;s growth.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-sets-sights-on-standalone-blockchain-entity-for-digital-assets-expansion/">Goldman Sachs sets sights on standalone blockchain entity for digital assets expansion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/goldman-sachs-sets-sights-on-standalone-blockchain-entity-for-digital-assets-expansion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/goldman-sachs-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/goldman-sachs-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>JPMorgan to launch instant euro-dollar conversions on its blockchain</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/jpmorgan-to-launch-instant-euro-dollar-conversions-on-its-blockchain/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/jpmorgan-to-launch-instant-euro-dollar-conversions-on-its-blockchain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 20:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TradFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451810</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>JPMorgan has developed instant dollar-euro settlements using its Kinexys blockchain, with the new feature slated to go live in the coming months.  According to a Bloomberg News report, the bank will leverage its proprietary JPM Coin to facilitate fast, secure transactions for participating institutions. Once regulatory approvals are obtained, JPMorgan plans to add sterling transactions to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jpmorgan-to-launch-instant-euro-dollar-conversions-on-its-blockchain/">JPMorgan to launch instant euro-dollar conversions on its blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/jpmorgan/">JPMorgan</a> has developed instant dollar-euro settlements using its Kinexys blockchain, with the new feature slated to go live in the coming months. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a Bloomberg News</span> <strong><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-06/jpmorgan-jpm-coin-to-offer-instant-dollar-euro-blockchain-trades">report</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the bank will leverage its proprietary JPM Coin to facilitate fast, secure transactions for participating institutions. Once regulatory approvals are obtained, JPMorgan plans to add sterling transactions to the platform.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kinexys processes over $2 billion in transactions daily and currently supports dollar- and euro-denominated payments. Yet, that figure represents a small fraction of JPMorgan&#8217;s $10 trillion daily payments volume.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Streamlining exchanges</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Naveen Mallela, JPMorgan&#8217;s global co-head of Kinexys, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">said the lender aims to leverage blockchain technology to reduce operation costs and bolster liquidity for its clients in the traditional banking industry, where dollar-euro exchanges usually take up to two days to settle.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Mallela added:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;If you look at JPM Coin, we generate revenues from fees, we also generate revenue from liquidity from holding those balances. We’re coming up with a third revenue stream from FX spreads.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Kinexys grows, the platform&#8217;s transaction volume has increased tenfold over the past year, with executives anticipating further scaling. </span></p>
<h2><strong>Seeking profitability</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, as JPMorgan expands functionality and customer reach, its blockchain operation is not profitable. Umar Farooq, global co-head of JPMorgan Payments, noted that balancing costs with revenue may take three to five years. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #333333;">The bank&#8217;s proprietary blockchain division, Onyx, </span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fraud-platform-integrates-jpmorgans-blockchain-solution-to-verify-vendor-banking-data/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">offers four major</a><span style="color: #333333;"> products, from blockchain-based clearing services to a tokenization platform.</span> </span></p>
<p><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">In November 2022, the lender executed its first <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-11-02/jpmorgan-executes-its-first-defi-trade-using-public-blockchain" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>foreign currency trade</strong></a> on a public blockchain</span> a forked version of the leading money market, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/avara/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aave,</a> to issue and swap 100,000 Singaporean dollars for Japan&#8217;s yen with SBI Digital Asset Holdings.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The transaction was conducted on the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/polygon/">Polygon</a> blockchain, a public network, as a part of the Monetary Authority of Singapore&#8217;s Project Guardian.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/jpmorgan-to-launch-instant-euro-dollar-conversions-on-its-blockchain/">JPMorgan to launch instant euro-dollar conversions on its blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/jpmorgan-to-launch-instant-euro-dollar-conversions-on-its-blockchain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/jpmorgan.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/jpmorgan.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swift&#8217;s tokenized fund settlement pilot with UBS and Chainlink deemed a success</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/swifts-tokenized-fund-settlement-pilot-with-ubs-and-chainlink-deemed-a-success/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/swifts-tokenized-fund-settlement-pilot-with-ubs-and-chainlink-deemed-a-success/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 15:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chainlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swift]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451545</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Swift, the global bank messaging network, announced on Nov. 5 that it has concluded a pilot program to streamline tokenized fund settlement and redemption using fiat currency on its network in collaboration with UBS Asset Management and Chainlink. This initiative aims to link digital asset transactions with existing fiat payment systems, reaching over 11,500 financial [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/swifts-tokenized-fund-settlement-pilot-with-ubs-and-chainlink-deemed-a-success/">Swift&#8217;s tokenized fund settlement pilot with UBS and Chainlink deemed a success</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swift, the global bank messaging network, announced on Nov. 5 that it has concluded a pilot program to streamline tokenized fund settlement and redemption using fiat currency on its network in collaboration with UBS Asset Management and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/chainlink/">Chainlink</a>.</p>
<p>This initiative aims to link digital asset transactions with existing fiat payment systems, reaching over 11,500 financial institutions globally in more than 200 countries.</p>
<p>According to Swift, traditional funds often encounter ineffective subscription and redemption processes, which require manual intervention, delay settlements, and lack real-time transparency. These challenges contribute to higher operational costs, reduced liquidity, and missed investment opportunities, particularly in the mutual fund market.</p>
<p>Through the pilot, financial institutions explored using blockchain technology to automate and speed up these processes. Leveraging <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chainlink-debuts-privacy-tech-triggering-links-rise-to-multi-week-high/">Chainlink&#8217;s platform</a> alongside Swift&#8217;s network, the program enabled efficient, on-chain processing for tokenized fund subscriptions and redemptions without needing direct on-chain payment. The result was a streamlined, automated fund subscription and redemption process.</p>
<h2>Expanding on cross-chain tokenized funds</h2>
<p>This pilot builds on prior efforts by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ubs-launches-its-first-tokenized-fund-on-ethereum-blockchain/">UBS Asset Management</a> and SBI Digital Markets, which focused on digital subscription and redemption systems for tokenized funds. This aligns with Singapore&#8217;s Monetary Authority&#8217;s (MAS) Project Guardian, which brings together regulators and industry leaders to explore innovations in digital finance.</p>
<p>The pilot used Swift&#8217;s infrastructure to demonstrate end-to-end payment orchestration for fund subscriptions and redemptions. Chainlink&#8217;s platform was used to coordinate transactions and fulfill the conditions necessary for UBS&#8217;s tokenized investment fund to mint or burn fund tokens on behalf of investors.</p>
<p>Swift&#8217;s Head of Strategy, Jonathan Ehrenfeld, noted that the initiative supports seamless integration with existing payment systems and digital currencies. According to Ehrenfeld, this collaboration with UBS Asset Management and Chainlink under Project Guardian leverages Swift&#8217;s global network to connect digital assets with conventional systems.</p>
<p>Similarly, Sergey Nazarov, Co-Founder of Chainlink, highlighted the benefits of integrating Swift&#8217;s infrastructure to enable off-chain payments for digital assets. He expressed optimism about the upcoming adoption of these capabilities and their potential to increase capital flows and broaden the digital asset user base.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/swifts-tokenized-fund-settlement-pilot-with-ubs-and-chainlink-deemed-a-success/">Swift&#8217;s tokenized fund settlement pilot with UBS and Chainlink deemed a success</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/swifts-tokenized-fund-settlement-pilot-with-ubs-and-chainlink-deemed-a-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/tokenization-swift.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/tokenization-swift.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>German tradFi giants confirm trial to mine Bitcoin with surplus energy to stabilize grid</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/german-giants-telekom-and-bankhaus-metzler-test-mining-bitcoin-with-surplus-energy-to-stabilize-grid/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/german-giants-telekom-and-bankhaus-metzler-test-mining-bitcoin-with-surplus-energy-to-stabilize-grid/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>German telecom giant Deutsche Telekom has partnered with Germany&#8217;s oldest bank, Bankhaus Metzler, to launch a pilot project testing Bitcoin mining infrastructure powered by surplus renewable energy. The initiative aims to utilize excess electricity from renewable sources that would otherwise remain unused due to grid limitations or insufficient storage options. Per the announcement on Monday, Nov. 4, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/german-giants-telekom-and-bankhaus-metzler-test-mining-bitcoin-with-surplus-energy-to-stabilize-grid/">German tradFi giants confirm trial to mine Bitcoin with surplus energy to stabilize grid</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #333333;">German telecom giant Deutsche Telekom has </span><a href="https://www.telekom.com/en/media/media-information/archive/test-bitcoin-mining-infrastructure-for-surplus-energy-1082684" target="_blank" rel="noopener">partnered</a><span style="color: #333333;"> with Germany&#8217;s oldest bank, Bankhaus Metzler, to launch a pilot project testing Bitcoin mining infrastructure powered by surplus renewable energy.</span> The initiative aims to utilize excess electricity from renewable sources that would otherwise remain unused due to grid limitations or insufficient storage options.</p>
<p>Per the announcement on Monday, Nov. 4, <span style="color: #333333;"> </span>increasing renewable energy production presents challenges in stabilizing the energy grid, as irregular production peaks occur depending on weather conditions. <span style="color: #333333;">Deutsche Telekom understands that <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a></span> mining could be crucial in balancing supply and demand within the grid. This method has already been <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/texas-sees-a-31-rise-in-bitcoin-mining-energy-use-paired-with-an-80-drop-in-electricity-prices/">successful</a> in countries like the United States and Finland, and the pilot project seeks to validate its effectiveness in Germany.</p>
<p>The mining operations are hosted by Metis Solutions GmbH and located at Riva GmbH Engineering&#8217;s facilities in Backnang, Germany. Riva Engineering, a manufacturer of metal and glass facades, generates its own electricity through a photovoltaic system. Telekom MMS is responsible for operating the mining devices, while Bankhaus Metzler is involved in defining test runs and analyzing data, exploring further possibilities for financial services with digital assets.</p>
<p>Oliver Nyderle, Head of Digital Trust &amp; Web3 Infrastructure at Deutsche Telekom MMS, stated that the project is a step toward testing the regulatory effect of Bitcoin miners on the energy grid. He said,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Surplus energy is converted into digital values through the miners. We call this digital monetary photosynthesis.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Hendrik König, Head of the Digital Assets Office at Bankhaus Metzler, emphasized gaining experience in blockchain technology applications. &#8220;Our goal is to further advance the innovative power of blockchain technology in Germany,&#8221; he noted. The bank established its Digital Assets Office in 2022 to focus exclusively on blockchain technology and the digital assets ecosystem.</p>
<p>Telekom MMS has been providing infrastructure for various decentralized protocols in the Web3 sector, including networks like Chainlink, Fetch.ai, and Polygon. In 2023, Telekom expanded its portfolio by operating a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/germanys-deutsche-telekom-to-mine-bitcoin-chinese-telecom-coolpad-adds-hashpower/">Bitcoin node,</a> marking its first involvement with a proof-of-work network.</p>
<p>The pilot project aims to gather field data and insights to plan subsequent initiatives, potentially contributing to stabilizing the energy grid during fluctuations. Wind power producers and photovoltaic plant operators could benefit from this technology, addressing the challenge of unpredictable regulating power.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/german-giants-telekom-and-bankhaus-metzler-test-mining-bitcoin-with-surplus-energy-to-stabilize-grid/">German tradFi giants confirm trial to mine Bitcoin with surplus energy to stabilize grid</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/german-giants-telekom-and-bankhaus-metzler-test-mining-bitcoin-with-surplus-energy-to-stabilize-grid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-windenergy.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-windenergy.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The FDIC has told banks to refrain from providing crypto services in over 20 cases, Coinbase finds</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/the-fdic-has-told-banks-to-refrain-from-providing-crypto-services-in-over-20-cases-coinbase-finds/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/the-fdic-has-told-banks-to-refrain-from-providing-crypto-services-in-over-20-cases-coinbase-finds/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monika Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 16:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase chief legal officer Paul Grewal said that the crypto exchange has discovered over 20 instances where the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) asked banks to “pause” or “refrain from providing” or “not proceed” with crypto-related banking services. In an X post, Grewal wrote: &#8220;In short, the contents are a shameful example of a government [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-fdic-has-told-banks-to-refrain-from-providing-crypto-services-in-over-20-cases-coinbase-finds/">The FDIC has told banks to refrain from providing crypto services in over 20 cases, Coinbase finds</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase chief legal officer <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paul-grewal/">Paul Grewal</a> said that the crypto exchange has discovered over 20 instances where the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) asked banks to “pause” or “refrain from providing” or “not proceed” with crypto-related banking services.</p>
<p>In an X post, Grewal <a href="https://x.com/iampaulgrewal/status/1852433093707387026">wrote</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;In short, the contents are a shameful example of a government agency trying to cut off financial access to law-abiding American companies.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The discovery was made after the FDIC shared 23 <a href="https://assets.ctfassets.net/c5bd0wqjc7v0/7nBWws5LwK6pwHTPcRO76u/7f7f0f78ae404e951c389d28f578a19f/-25-2-_Exhibit_B_-_Vaughn_Index.pdf">documents</a> with Coinbase in accordance with its two Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) requests. Coinbase had requested access to letters the FDIC sent to banks to pause crypto services.</p>
<p>The FDIC is yet to release the actual letters, but the shared documents provide condensed summaries. The letters, dated between March and October 2022, were addressed to bank presidents and boards of directors. The names of the banks were not disclosed.</p>
<p>In each of the letters, the FDIC said that it is reviewing the banks&#8217; proposed crypto services and advised them to hold off on providing such services until the review is completed. In most cases, the FDIC was concerned with the &#8220;bank’s legal analysis, assessment of compliance with FDIC regulations, safety and soundness, and consumer protection.&#8221;</p>
<p>In almost every letter, the FDIC states that it requires further information in order to determine whether the proposed crypto service is safe. According to Grewal, the FDIC sent the letter to the bank as part of Operation Chokepoint 2.0.</p>
<p>Grewal said that Coinbase will continue to &#8220;get clarity&#8221; from regulators through FOIA requests and &#8220;any other means necessary.&#8221; He added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The public deserves transparency, not an agency that’s working behind a bureaucratic curtain.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Earlier this week, in its shareholder letter for the third quarter of 2024, Coinbase said that it is &#8220;prepared to work with either administration,&#8221; regardless of whether Vice President Kamala Harris or Republican nominee Donald Trump wins the election on Nov 5.</p>
<p>This is because Coinbase believes that both presidential candidates have adopted crypto-friendly stances. The Oct 30 letter stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Both presidential candidates, as well as politicians across the political spectrum, have adopted more favorable positions toward crypto, a significant shift from previous years.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/the-fdic-has-told-banks-to-refrain-from-providing-crypto-services-in-over-20-cases-coinbase-finds/">The FDIC has told banks to refrain from providing crypto services in over 20 cases, Coinbase finds</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/the-fdic-has-told-banks-to-refrain-from-providing-crypto-services-in-over-20-cases-coinbase-finds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/coinbase.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/coinbase.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore&#8217;s DBS Bank integrates Ethereum-compatible tech for institutional finance</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/singapores-dbs-bank-integrates-ethereum-compatible-tech-for-institutional-finance/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/singapores-dbs-bank-integrates-ethereum-compatible-tech-for-institutional-finance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 14:15:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DBS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=448841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Singapore&#8217;s DBS Bank has introduced a blockchain-driven banking service for institutional investors, featuring tokenization and smart contract capabilities. On Oct. 18, the leading financial institution stated that its DBS Token Services is designed to enhance transaction banking and improve operational efficiency for its institutional clients. DBS Token Services According to the bank, DBS Token Services [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/singapores-dbs-bank-integrates-ethereum-compatible-tech-for-institutional-finance/">Singapore&#8217;s DBS Bank integrates Ethereum-compatible tech for institutional finance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tradfi-lender-dbs-launches-evm-compatible-blockchain-solution-for-treasury-liquidity-management/">Singapore&#8217;s DBS Bank</a> has introduced a blockchain-driven banking service for institutional investors, featuring tokenization and smart contract capabilities.</p>
<p>On Oct. 18, the leading financial institution <a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/in/news-releases/dbs-rolls-out-blockchain-powered-banking-for-institutions-with-dbs-token-services-marks-new-milestone-in-financial-services-302280120.html">stated</a> that its DBS Token Services is designed to enhance transaction banking and improve operational efficiency for its institutional clients.</p>
<h2>DBS Token Services</h2>
<p>According to the bank, DBS Token Services enables real-time, 24/7 payment settlements using the bank&#8217;s proprietary permissioned blockchain, which is compatible with the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> Virtual Machine (EVM).</p>
<p>This solution also integrates DBS&#8217; core payment engine with various industry payment networks. By utilizing smart contracts, institutions can manage funds according to pre-set conditions aimed at improving security and transparency.</p>
<p>The bank&#8217;s permissioned blockchain allows full control over these services, ensuring they comply with regulatory standards. Unlike open, public blockchains, permissioned blockchains provide controlled access, making them ideal for businesses and governments.</p>
<p>According to DBS, this approach allows the bank to harness the benefits of blockchain technology while maintaining compliance with global regulatory practices.</p>
<p>Lim Soon Chong, DBS Group Head of Global Transaction Services, highlighted that the service addresses the growing demand for on-chain digital solutions. He expects DBS Token Services to facilitate &#8220;always-on&#8221; banking, enabling institutional clients to optimize liquidity management, streamline operations, and boost business resilience.</p>
<p>Chong said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;DBS Token Services enables companies and public sector entities to optimise liquidity management, streamline operational workflows, strengthen business resilience, and unlock new opportunities for end-customer or end-user engagement.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>He added that the product marks a significant step in transaction banking and demonstrates how established financial institutions can leverage blockchain technology.</p>
<h2>DBS blockchain-powered solutions</h2>
<p>The new token service builds on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/singapores-dbs-bank-to-offer-bitcoin-and-ethereum-options-trading/">DBS&#8217; existing blockchain-based products</a>, such as Treasury Tokens, Conditional Payments, and Programmable Rewards.</p>
<p>Currently in a pilot with Ant International, Treasury Tokens offers a liquidity management solution. This service supports real-time multi-currency intra-group transfers and allows corporations to settle transactions instantly, regardless of time zones or banking hours.</p>
<p>DBS has also piloted Conditional Payments, a smart contract-based solution for streamlining payment workflows. In collaboration with Enterprise Singapore and the Singapore Fintech Association, DBS demonstrated how programmable contracts can enhance governance by controlling fund disbursements for intermediaries.</p>
<p>Additionally, DBS is exploring Programmable Rewards, which enable institutions to create cost-effective digital voucher programs. As part of this initiative, DBS Hong Kong recently participated in the second phase of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority&#8217;s e-HKD Pilot Programme. The pilot aims to test Programmable Rewards using a hypothetical <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-monetary-regulator-launches-second-phase-of-cbdc-project/">digital Hong Kong dollar (e-HKD)</a> to support an ESG-focused reward platform, enhancing consumer incentive programs.</p>
<p>These offerings demonstrate how traditional financial institutions can use blockchain technology and smart contracts to provide innovative client experiences.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/singapores-dbs-bank-integrates-ethereum-compatible-tech-for-institutional-finance/">Singapore&#8217;s DBS Bank integrates Ethereum-compatible tech for institutional finance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/singapores-dbs-bank-integrates-ethereum-compatible-tech-for-institutional-finance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dbs-blockchain.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/dbs-blockchain.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Siam Commercial becomes first Thai bank to adopt stablecoins for cross-border payments</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/siam-commercial-becomes-first-thai-bank-to-adopt-stablecoins-for-cross-border-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/siam-commercial-becomes-first-thai-bank-to-adopt-stablecoins-for-cross-border-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 19:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=448450</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Siam Commercial Bank (SCB), Thailand&#8217;s fourth largest and oldest lender, has become the first financial institution in the country to offer stablecoin-based cross-border payments and remittance services, Nikkei Asia reported on Oct. 16. The stablecoin remittance service will be offered in collaboration with fintech firm Lightnet. The move aims to reduce transaction fees and provide [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/siam-commercial-becomes-first-thai-bank-to-adopt-stablecoins-for-cross-border-payments/">Siam Commercial becomes first Thai bank to adopt stablecoins for cross-border payments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Siam Commercial Bank (SCB), Thailand&#8217;s fourth largest and oldest lender, has become the first financial institution in the country to offer stablecoin-based cross-border payments and remittance services, Nikkei Asia reported on Oct. 16.</p>
<p>The stablecoin remittance service will be offered in collaboration with fintech firm Lightnet. The move aims to reduce transaction fees and provide faster international transfers for its clients.</p>
<p>The introduction of stablecoin-based services will allow SCB customers to send and receive payments globally 24 hours a day, seven days a week. The service was trialed through the Bank of Thailand&#8217;s digital assets sandbox to ensure the system meets regulatory standards and has the flexibility for future expansion.</p>
<p>SCB&#8217;s adoption of stablecoin payments highlights the growing importance of blockchain technology in reshaping global finance, particularly in regions where traditional banking systems struggle to meet the needs of their populations.</p>
<p>This move is expected to further the development of Thailand&#8217;s digital economy, positioning SCB as a key player in the future of financial services.</p>
<h2>Stabelcoin adoption surge</h2>
<p>According to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/chainalysis/">Chainalysis&#8217;</a> latest global adoption report, stablecoins have become a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoins-defi-boost-nigeria-to-second-in-global-crypto-adoption-rankings-chainalysis/">critical tool</a> for cross-border payments, particularly in regions with unstable currencies or high remittance costs. They are increasingly used in countries like Brazil, Nigeria, and India, where traditional banking systems often fail to meet the needs of the population.</p>
<p>In Sub-Saharan Africa, stablecoins now account for 43% of all crypto transactions, playing a vital role in remittances and trade. Nigeria, in particular, has emerged as the second-largest adopter of crypto globally, with stablecoins offering a lifeline to those seeking a stable alternative to local currencies.</p>
<p>The growing role of stablecoins in financial inclusion is not without its challenges. Some experts have raised concerns about &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoins-redefine-financial-access-in-emerging-markets-report-finds/">crypto-dollarization</a>&#8221; in certain regions, where the widespread use of stablecoins could weaken local monetary policies.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the report noted that over 70% of respondents expect to increase their stablecoin usage over the next year, driven by their efficiency, speed, and accessibility in cross-border payments, payroll, and remittances.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/siam-commercial-becomes-first-thai-bank-to-adopt-stablecoins-for-cross-border-payments/">Siam Commercial becomes first Thai bank to adopt stablecoins for cross-border payments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/siam-commercial-becomes-first-thai-bank-to-adopt-stablecoins-for-cross-border-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/thailand.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/thailand.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
