<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Exchanges News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/exchanges/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/exchanges/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:36:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Exchanges News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/exchanges/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Coinbase-led TRUSThub set to enhance digital asset transparency</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-led-trusthub-set-to-enhance-digital-asset-transparency/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-led-trusthub-set-to-enhance-digital-asset-transparency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 19:36:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel rule]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TRUST]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TRUSThub]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Coinbase-led Travel Rule Universal Solution Technology (TRUST) has unveiled TRUSThub, a platform designed to streamline data sharing among Virtual Asset Service Providers (VASPs), according to a Dec. 5 statement shared with CryptoSlate. TRUSThub aims to enhance compliance capabilities and enable secure Travel Rule data exchange, even with non-members or unregulated entities. TRUST members can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-led-trusthub-set-to-enhance-digital-asset-transparency/">Coinbase-led TRUSThub set to enhance digital asset transparency</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>-led Travel Rule Universal Solution Technology (TRUST) has unveiled TRUSThub, a platform designed to streamline data sharing among Virtual Asset Service Providers (VASPs), according to a Dec. 5 statement shared with <em>CryptoSlate</em>.</p>
<p>TRUSThub aims to enhance compliance capabilities and enable secure Travel Rule data exchange, even with non-members or unregulated entities. TRUST members can expect to access the platform by the end of 2024.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.coinbase.com/en-fr/travelrule">TRUST&#8217;s membership</a> includes prominent VASPs such as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitgo/">BitGo</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance-us/">Binance.US</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/gemini/">Gemini</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/revolut/">Revolut</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/paypal/">PayPal</a>, and others. These industry leaders will benefit from Trusthub&#8217;s unique features, which will drive innovation and compliance in the evolving digital asset space.</p>
<h2>TRUSThub goals</h2>
<p>The introduction of TRUSThub addresses the growing demand for robust solutions that facilitate secure information sharing in the crypto industry.</p>
<p>Under the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/eba-updates-travel-rule-to-include-crypto-service-providers-in-anti-money-laundering-push/">Travel Rule</a>, VASPs must provide specific customer information for transactions exceeding a defined threshold. This requirement aims to improve transparency and reduce the anonymity that has long been associated with digital asset transactions.</p>
<p>The Travel Rule is expected to increase accountability and traceability in crypto transactions, making it more challenging for illicit actors to exploit the system.</p>
<p>TRUSThub simplifies this process by automating recipient identification and securely transmitting data, even to non-TRUST participants.</p>
<p>The platform emphasizes five key principles: compliance, interoperability, simplicity, usability, and security. These pillars enable seamless integration and ensure data sharing aligns with regulatory expectations without disrupting VASP operations.</p>
<p>Coinbase Institutional <a href="https://x.com/CoinbaseInsto/status/1864695744864657515">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;By providing an interoperable, user-friendly platform, TRUSThub makes compliance simple and scalable.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The platform&#8217;s benefits are significant for TRUST members. TRUSThub automates recipient identification and securely transmits Travel Rule data, even when dealing with non-TRUST VASPs. This feature eliminates barriers to compliance while preserving user satisfaction and privacy.</p>
<p>Additionally, TRUST members can execute cross-network transactions securely while upholding essential privacy standards.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-led-trusthub-set-to-enhance-digital-asset-transparency/">Coinbase-led TRUSThub set to enhance digital asset transparency</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-led-trusthub-set-to-enhance-digital-asset-transparency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-trust-exchange.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-trust-exchange.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korea&#8217;s crypto volumes spike as Woori eyes over $300 million Upbit exit</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Deals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UPbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Woori Technology, a South Korean venture capital firm, is reportedly considering selling its stake in Dunamu, the parent company of the Upbit crypto exchange. Upbit is the largest crypto trading platform in the East Asian country. According to local media reports, Woori invested 5.5 billion KRW in Dunamu in 2015, acquiring an undisclosed company share. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/">South Korea&#8217;s crypto volumes spike as Woori eyes over $300 million Upbit exit</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Woori Technology, a South Korean venture capital firm, is reportedly considering selling its stake in Dunamu, the parent company of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/upbit/">Upbit</a> crypto exchange.</p>
<p>Upbit is the largest crypto trading platform in the East Asian country.</p>
<p>According to local media <a href="https://www.bloter.net/news/articleView.html?idxno=627498">reports</a>, Woori invested 5.5 billion KRW in Dunamu in 2015, acquiring an undisclosed company share. Nearly nine years later, the firm holds a 7.22% stake, which reportedly has a current over-the-counter (OTC) value of around 425.3 billion KRW, or $300.7 million.</p>
<p>While the exact sale price remains unclear, reports suggest that it could exceed the current OTC market value, with a return potentially surpassing 100 times the original investment.</p>
<p>Speculation indicates that Woori is seeking international buyers after struggling to raise funds from domestic investors. The transaction will likely occur through a block deal, allowing large shareholders to transfer stocks after hours and preventing market manipulation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, this deal comes at an interesting time when South Korean authorities investigate the crypto trading platform for multiple issues, including potential <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-investigates-upbits-kyc-violations-amid-market-dominance-concerns/">Know-Your-Customer (KYC) violations</a> and concerns over its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-investigates-upbit-over-market-dominance-concerns/">local market dominance</a>.</p>
<h2>Ripping volume</h2>
<p>Woori&#8217;s potential sale comes as South Korea&#8217;s crypto market is experiencing a surge in trading volumes, coinciding with political unrest in the country.</p>
<p>On Dec. 3, President Yoon Suk Yeol declared an emergency martial law but reversed his decision six hours later.</p>
<p>This declaration significantly impacted the local crypto market, with blockchain analytical platform Kaiko pointing out that the president&#8217;s move resulted in 18 billion KRW worth of selling on Bitcoin in the first thirty minutes. It <a href="https://x.com/KaikoData/status/1864307350745629074">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;While the selling pressure abated for $BTC it remained for other assets, most notably there was significant $XRP selling throughout the day on Bithumb.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Unsurprisingly, the vast selling activity translated into heavy trading activities on local platforms in the country. Onchain data shows that Upbit saw a 44.7% rise in trading volume, reaching nearly $28 billion in the past 24 hours. Other exchanges, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bithumb/">Bithumb</a>, Coinone, Korbit, and Gopax, also reported substantial upticks in trading activity.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/">South Korea&#8217;s crypto volumes spike as Woori eyes over $300 million Upbit exit</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase faces backlash over discouraging VPN access due to security concerns</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-faces-backlash-over-blocking-vpn-access-due-to-security-concerns/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-faces-backlash-over-blocking-vpn-access-due-to-security-concerns/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 11:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VPN]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase, the largest US-based exchange, has faced criticism from the crypto community after reports surfaced about its restriction of users accessing accounts through Virtual Private Networks (VPNs). On Dec. 2, Scott Shapiro, a product designer at Coinbase, warned users to avoid using VPNs when accessing their accounts. He explained that Coinbase&#8217;s risk model treats VPN [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-faces-backlash-over-blocking-vpn-access-due-to-security-concerns/">Coinbase faces backlash over discouraging VPN access due to security concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>, the largest US-based exchange, has faced criticism from the crypto community after reports surfaced about its restriction of users accessing accounts through Virtual Private Networks (VPNs).</p>
<p>On Dec. 2, Scott Shapiro, a product designer at Coinbase, warned users to avoid using VPNs when accessing their accounts. He explained that Coinbase&#8217;s risk model treats VPN usage as a red flag, typically associated with malicious activity, even if the user is legitimate.</p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/scottshapiro/status/1863691538661883925?t=o0XVB-TN-OJJypcJHR0jYg&amp;s=19">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Attackers always use VPNs, so our risk models take that as a negative sign even if you’re legitimately using your own account.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>A VPN is an online tool that encrypts data and hides IP addresses to enhance privacy and security. By creating a secure connection between a device and a remote server, VPNs make data unreadable to anyone lacking the encryption key.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.security.org/resources/vpn-consumer-report-annual/">Reports</a> show that Americans&#8217; VPN use has surged in popularity, with 95% of adults familiar with the technology and 46% actively using VPNs. This equates to around 105 million people relying on VPNs for online activities.</p>
<h2>Community reaction</h2>
<p>The crypto community has strongly criticized Coinbase&#8217;s stance, with many comparing it to recent efforts to debank individuals in the US. Some users argue that a VPN is a fundamental right to privacy and that restricting it may push them to leave the exchange.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken&#8217;s</a> Chief Security Officer Nick Percoco argued that Coinbase&#8217;s action forced users to choose between financial freedom and personal safety. He pointed out that VPNs are crucial security tools for crypto users in certain regions.</p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/c7five/status/1863782435005022454?t=MhioyWp0YeBKSrUpu626NQ&amp;s=19">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Crypto users are some of the most privacy and security minded users on the planet. There are also places on the planet where is it physically dangerous to access a crypto exchange without a VPN masking their destination from the local ISP.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Security expert Sudo also <a href="https://x.com/pcaversaccio/status/1863862722636439772">criticized</a> Coinbase&#8217;s position, calling the decision &#8220;misguided.&#8221; He stressed that a VPN is a protective shield, especially when using public Wi-Fi or avoiding government and ISP surveillance.</p>
<p>He also pointed out the hypocrisy in Coinbase&#8217;s action, noting that the firm recently celebrated a legal victory <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tornado-cash-token-surges-to-2-year-high-after-us-court-rules-treasury-sanctions-unlawful/">overturning sanctions on privacy tool Tornado Cash</a> yet now deems VPN usage a problem.</p>
<p>However, crypto expert Evan Van Ness <a href="https://x.com/evan_van_ness/status/1864089452252938272">defended</a> Coinbase&#8217;s approach, describing it as standard anti-fraud measures.</p>
<p>He pointed out that fraudsters are the primary users of VPNs, and even those who rely on VPNs for legitimate reasons understand they may need to disable them for specific actions.</p>
<p>Van Ness added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Could Coinbase do better? Probably and perhaps the backlash will spur them to [address] their customer service could be better by all accounts But fundamentally this is a tradeoff that everyone makes and a very reasonable one.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-faces-backlash-over-blocking-vpn-access-due-to-security-concerns/">Coinbase faces backlash over discouraging VPN access due to security concerns</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-faces-backlash-over-blocking-vpn-access-due-to-security-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-vpn-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-vpn-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase cuts ties with law firms hiring ex-regulators linked to crypto crackdown</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-cuts-ties-with-law-firms-hiring-ex-regulators-linked-to-crypto-crackdown/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-cuts-ties-with-law-firms-hiring-ex-regulators-linked-to-crypto-crackdown/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 21:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455758</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong announced the exchange would sever ties with law firms that hire former regulatory officials linked to what he describes as &#8220;unlawful&#8221; actions against the crypto industry. Armstrong&#8217;s comments, made in a social media post on Dec. 3, follow news that former SEC Division of Enforcement Director Gurbir S. Grewal joined Milbank&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-cuts-ties-with-law-firms-hiring-ex-regulators-linked-to-crypto-crackdown/">Coinbase cuts ties with law firms hiring ex-regulators linked to crypto crackdown</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/brian-armstrong/">Brian Armstrong</a> announced the exchange would sever ties with law firms that hire former regulatory officials linked to what he describes as &#8220;unlawful&#8221; actions against the crypto industry.</p>
<p>Armstrong&#8217;s comments, made in a social media post on Dec. 3, follow news that former SEC Division of Enforcement Director Gurbir S. Grewal joined Milbank&#8217;s Litigation &amp; Arbitration Group — prompting the Coinbase CEO to single out the firm as one the exchange would no longer engage with.</p>
<p>Armstrong stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We&#8217;ve let all the law firms we work with know that, if they hire anyone who committed these bad deeds in the (soon to be) prior administration, we will no longer be a client of theirs.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Armstrong criticized senior partners at law firms for being &#8220;unaware of the crypto industry&#8217;s position&#8221; on the issue. He specifically referenced Grewal, accusing him of contributing to regulatory actions that he called &#8220;an ethics violation.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Coinbase CEO claimed the prior SEC administration under Gary Gensler had &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-debanking-wave-tied-to-political-figures-coinbase-ceo-brian-armstrong-alleges/">unlawfully</a>&#8221; targeted the crypto industry while refusing to provide clear guidance on compliance.</p>
<p>Armstrong wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This was not a normal SEC tenure. If you were a senior there, you cannot say you were just following orders. They had the option to leave the SEC, and many good people did.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Armstrong emphasized that while he does not believe in &#8220;permanently canceling people,&#8221; the crypto industry should avoid financially supporting individuals he alleges were <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-brian-armstrong-champions-crypto-mom-hester-peirce-for-sec-chair/">involved in harming</a> the sector.</p>
<p>He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Let your law firms know that hiring these folks means losing you as a client.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Milbank did not immediately respond to requests for comment.</p>
<p>The move highlights the deep-rooted tensions between the crypto industry and regulators. Coinbase has been at the forefront of legal and policy battles, with Armstrong often calling for clearer guidelines to foster innovation in digital assets.</p>
<p>Grewal&#8217;s tenure at the SEC coincided with increased enforcement actions targeting crypto platforms, including high-profile lawsuits against Coinbase and other firms. His move to private practice reflects a broader trend of regulators transitioning to legal advisory roles in the industries they once oversaw.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-cuts-ties-with-law-firms-hiring-ex-regulators-linked-to-crypto-crackdown/">Coinbase cuts ties with law firms hiring ex-regulators linked to crypto crackdown</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-cuts-ties-with-law-firms-hiring-ex-regulators-linked-to-crypto-crackdown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/brian-armstrong-sec.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/brian-armstrong-sec.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase integrates Apple Pay for fiat-to-crypto transactions</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-integrates-apple-pay-for-fiat-to-crypto-on-and-offramp/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-integrates-apple-pay-for-fiat-to-crypto-on-and-offramp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 22:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase announced the integration of Apple Pay into its Coinbase Onramp service, according to a Dec. 2 announcement. The addition will streamline the process for users looking to convert fiat into crypto, making it faster and more user-friendly. Apple Pay has more than 60 million active users in the US and over 500 million users globally [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-integrates-apple-pay-for-fiat-to-crypto-on-and-offramp/">Coinbase integrates Apple Pay for fiat-to-crypto transactions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coinbase</span> <strong><a href="https://www.coinbase.com/en-br/blog/Fiat-to-crypto-in-seconds-with-Apple-Pay">announced</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the integration of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/apple/">Apple</a> Pay into its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> Onramp service, according to a Dec. 2 announcement.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> The addition will streamline the process for users looking to convert fiat into crypto, making it faster and more user-friendly. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Apple Pay has more than 60 million active users in the US and over 500 million users globally as of 2023. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coinbase Onramp is a tool designed to integrate crypto purchases into apps and websites. It simplifies onboarding by offering lightweight Know Your Customer (KYC) processes for eligible users. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Alongside the integration with Apple Pay, Coinbase continues offering free USD Coin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/usd-coin/">USDC</a>) on and off-ramping, lowering the cost for users to enter and exit the crypto market through its stablecoin. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For developers already using Coinbase Onramp, the integration with Apple Pay will be seamless. Users will automatically see the new payment option when making eligible purchases.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Lowering barriers</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/metamask/">MetaMask</a> recently</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/metamask-integrates-venmo-to-enhance-fiat-to-crypto-onramp-options/">added Venmo</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> as a fiat-to-crypto option, along with Apple Pay, debit and credit cards, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/paypal/">PayPal,</a> wire transfers, and ACH bank transactions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/consensys/">Consensys</a>, the company behind MetaMask, also announced in August a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/mastercard-blockchain/">Mastercard</a>-powered crypto debit card that allows users to spend their balances on their wallets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As crypto prices rise and the stablecoin supply grows, suggesting a change of pace in retail investors&#8217; entry into crypto, companies are making efforts to make investing and using crypto easier.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #333333;">The stablecoin market has grown roughly 13% since reaching an all-time high of $187.4 billion in November and currently stands at nearly $22 billion</span>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to including accessibility options for new crypto investors, crypto firms are also looking to diversify their offerings. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/robinhood/">Robinhood</a> recently</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/robinhood-adds-support-for-sol-ada-xrp-and-pepe-for-us-investors/">added</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> four more cryptos to its platform, including the memecoin <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pepe/">PEPE</a>, while Coinbase is</span> <strong><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2024-11-21/coinbase-hopes-to-list-more-memecoins-in-the-trump-era">looking to ramp up</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its memecoin listings next year to attract more retail trading.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-integrates-apple-pay-for-fiat-to-crypto-on-and-offramp/">Coinbase integrates Apple Pay for fiat-to-crypto transactions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-integrates-apple-pay-for-fiat-to-crypto-on-and-offramp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japanese SBI supports DMM Bitcoin amid closure as Metaplanet partners for BTC lottery</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-bitcoin-and-metaplanet-partner-with-sbi-vc-trade-for-asset-transfers-and-btc-giveaway/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-bitcoin-and-metaplanet-partner-with-sbi-vc-trade-for-asset-transfers-and-btc-giveaway/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DMM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SBI Holdings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455420</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>SBI VC Trade, a subsidiary of Japan&#8217;s financial powerhouse SBI Holdings, has revealed new collaborations with DMM Bitcoin and Metaplanet. SBI Holdings is a leader in internet banking in Japan and a global leader in blockchain technologies. As of March 2024, the company held more than $190 billion in total assets. DMM Bitcoin is a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-bitcoin-and-metaplanet-partner-with-sbi-vc-trade-for-asset-transfers-and-btc-giveaway/">Japanese SBI supports DMM Bitcoin amid closure as Metaplanet partners for BTC lottery</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SBI VC Trade, a subsidiary of Japan&#8217;s financial powerhouse SBI Holdings, has revealed new collaborations with DMM Bitcoin and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/metaplanet/">Metaplanet</a>.</p>
<p>SBI Holdings is a leader in internet banking in Japan and a global leader in blockchain technologies. As of March 2024, the company held more than $190 billion in total assets. DMM Bitcoin is a distressed Japan-based crypto exchange, while Metaplanet is renowned for its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/metaplanet-becomes-asias-largest-bitcoin-holder-with-over-1000-btc/">aggressive Bitcoin acquisitions this year</a>.</p>
<p>Market observers pointed out that these partnerships reflect SBI&#8217;s commitment to expanding its influence in the blockchain sector.</p>
<p>Over the years, SBI Holdings has played a key role in Japan&#8217;s financial market, using its expertise to drive <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/oasys-partners-with-japanese-tradfi-giant-sbi-holdings-to-push-blockchain-gaming/">blockchain adoption across Asia.</a> Through SBI VC Trade, the firm operates a crypto exchange platform that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/circle-sbi-holdings-focus-efforts-on-usdc-growth-in-japanese-market/">fosters innovation in financial services</a> by forming impactful alliances and strategic investments.</p>
<h2>Transfer of DMM assets</h2>
<p>On Dec. 2, DMM Bitcoin, a crypto exchange impacted by a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-koreas-lazarus-group-tied-to-305m-crypto-breach-of-japans-dmm-exchange/">$305 million hack in May 2024</a>, <a href="https://www.sbigroup.co.jp/news/2024/1202_15071.html">announced</a> that it would cease operations by March 2025.</p>
<p>Before then, the company said it would transfer all user assets, including Japanese yen and cryptocurrencies, to SBI VC Trade. This agreement was finalized on Nov. 29.</p>
<p>The May hack, linked to North Korea&#8217;s Lazarus Group, led to strict platform restrictions, including <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-exchange-suspends-withdrawals-after-305-million-bitcoin-theft/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">suspending</a></span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-exchange-suspends-withdrawals-after-305-million-bitcoin-theft/"> withdrawals and spot trading</a>.</p>
<p>These measures severely affected user experience, prompting DMM Bitcoin to migrate its accounts and assets. However, the transfer will not include leveraged transaction positions and must be settled beforehand.</p>
<p>SBI VC Trade&#8217;s CEO, Tomohiko Kondo, highlighted plans to support 14 cryptocurrencies during this transition. He <a href="https://x.com/tomohiko_kondo/status/1863389806224646405">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We have reached a basic agreement to transfer DMM Bitcoin customer accounts and deposited assets to SBI VC Trade. There are 14 different types of cryptocurrencies available, and we are preparing to handle all of them through SBIVC.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>He added that both companies will finalize the asset transfer details, ensuring a smooth handover for affected users.</p>
<p>DMM Bitcoin&#8217;s exit marks a significant shift in Japan&#8217;s crypto landscape. However, the partnership with SBI VC Trade ensures the preservation of its users&#8217; assets while introducing them to a more stable platform.</p>
<h2>Metaplanet Bitcoin shareholder program</h2>
<p>In a parallel development, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a>-focused investment firm Metaplanet announced a shareholder benefit program in collaboration with SBI VC Trade.</p>
<p>Metaplanet CEO Simon Georvich <a href="https://x.com/gerovich/status/1863376120374280234">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;A total of 30 million yen worth of Bitcoin will be given away to 2,350 shareholders by lottery, and 50 shareholders will each receive $BTC worth 100,000 yen.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>He added that the program aims to increase Bitcoin adoption in Japan by offering potential users the top digital asset for free.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/metaplanet/">Metaplanet</a> has aggressively expanded its Bitcoin holdings throughout 2024, amassing 1,142 BTC valued at approximately $110 million. This makes it one of the largest Bitcoin holders in Asia.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-bitcoin-and-metaplanet-partner-with-sbi-vc-trade-for-asset-transfers-and-btc-giveaway/">Japanese SBI supports DMM Bitcoin amid closure as Metaplanet partners for BTC lottery</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/japanese-dmm-bitcoin-and-metaplanet-partner-with-sbi-vc-trade-for-asset-transfers-and-btc-giveaway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/japan-dmm-bitcoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/japan-dmm-bitcoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase resolves Solana transaction delays, admits internal missteps</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-resolves-solana-transaction-delays-admits-internal-missteps/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-resolves-solana-transaction-delays-admits-internal-missteps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 14:36:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Outage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Solana blockchain community has voiced concerns about Coinbase, citing prolonged transaction delays for the network. On social media platform X, screenshots shared by several Solana users revealed that transactions on the blockchain took up to 45 minutes to process. This delay was significantly longer than that of networks like Base, Algorand, Arbitrum, and Avalanche. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-resolves-solana-transaction-delays-admits-internal-missteps/">Coinbase resolves Solana transaction delays, admits internal missteps</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a> blockchain community has voiced concerns about <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>, citing prolonged transaction delays for the network.</p>
<p>On social media platform X, <a href="https://x.com/bangerzNFT/status/1862023598279725421">screenshots</a> shared by several Solana users revealed that transactions on the blockchain took up to 45 minutes to process. This delay was significantly longer than that of networks like Base, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/algorand/">Algorand</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbitrum/">Arbitrum</a>, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/avalanche/">Avalanche</a>.</p>
<p>In response, Coinbase&#8217;s support <a href="https://x.com/CoinbaseSupport/status/1862039987975340194?t=KupzLSledTpV4UJIdCFdTw&amp;s=19">attributed</a> the delays to wallet maintenance or blockchain issues, implying that Solana&#8217;s infrastructure was the root cause.</p>
<p>This explanation sparked frustration within the crypto community, with some members accusing Coinbase of downplaying Solana&#8217;s capabilities in favor of its Base network.</p>
<p>Solana is the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/solanas-price-could-flip-tethers-usdt-market-cap-at-270/">third-largest blockchain network</a> behind <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a>, while Base is an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/base-outpaces-optimism-and-arbitrum-amid-coinbases-smart-wallet-debut/">Ethereum layer-2 network</a> founded by the US-based crypto trading platform.</p>
<h2>Solana community responds</h2>
<p>Prominent figures within the Solana ecosystem quickly addressed these claims.</p>
<p>Mert Mumtaz, CEO of Helius Labs, a Solana-focused RPC provider, <a href="https://x.com/0xMert_/status/1862212099239223800">explained</a> that Coinbase&#8217;s internal indexing systems—not Solana&#8217;s infrastructure—were behind the delays.</p>
<p>Austin Federa, Solana&#8217;s Head of Strategy, echoed this sentiment. He dismissed Coinbase&#8217;s explanation and emphasized that the delays stemmed from internal technical issues at the US-based exchange. He <a href="https://x.com/Austin_Federa/status/1862208297492975808?t=1dlFindZyf_b35D6jWvSzA&amp;s=19">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Clear communications are extremely important and this one misses the mark&#8230;the issue has nothing to do with the Solana network, rpcs, or anything of the like. It’s a boring old internal system issue on the exchange side.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Moreover, a community note was also promptly added to Coinbase&#8217;s support statement, highlighting that the exchange had faced unexplained Solana delays for months.</p>
<p>The note also compared blockchain performance metrics, showing Solana&#8217;s Time to Finality (TTF) at 12 seconds—significantly faster than Base and Arbitrum at 16 minutes.</p>
<h2>Coinbase resolves issue</h2>
<p>On its status page, Coinbase <a href="https://status.coinbase.com/">acknowledged</a> the platform&#8217;s delays in processing Solana transactions but explained that the issues had been resolved as of Nov. 28.</p>
<p>Similarly, Andrew Allen, a Protocol Specialist at Coinbase, confirmed that the issue had been resolved. He <a href="https://x.com/ann_droo/status/1862279495123624160">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;To summarize, Coinbase’s indexer issues impacting Solana Send/Receive were resolved ~5am this morning. The UI didn’t automatically update. But both underlying issue and UI fix have now been applied.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite the resolution, some community members remained critical of the exchange and accused it of being unfriendly toward the network. However, Milk Road creator Kyle Reidhead <a href="https://x.com/kylereidhead/status/1862163056706347224?s=46&amp;t=aw6ZR-6aD050XLPVXY8AQA">urged</a> the crypto community to appreciate Coinbase&#8217;s broader contributions to the industry rather than dwell on this issue.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-resolves-solana-transaction-delays-admits-internal-missteps/">Coinbase resolves Solana transaction delays, admits internal missteps</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-resolves-solana-transaction-delays-admits-internal-missteps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/solana-transaction.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/solana-transaction.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-Binance executive alleges retaliatory firing over bribery whistleblowing</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 01:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A former senior executive at Binance has accused the company of retaliatory dismissal after she raised concerns about an alleged bribery scheme involving a colleague, Bloomberg News reported on Nov. 28. Amrita Srivastava, a London-based executive who worked remotely on Binance&#8217;s Link platform, testified that she was dismissed after reporting that a colleague solicited a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/">Ex-Binance executive alleges retaliatory firing over bribery whistleblowing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">A former senior executive at <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> has accused the company of retaliatory dismissal after she raised concerns about an alleged bribery scheme involving a colleague, Bloomberg News </span><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-28/ex-binance-executive-brings-whistleblower-claim-alleging-bribery">reported</a> on Nov. 28.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Amrita Srivastava, a London-based executive who worked remotely on Binance&#8217;s Link platform, testified that she was dismissed after reporting that a colleague solicited a bribe from a customer in exchange for expedited integration services. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The alleged payments were disguised as &#8220;consultative services&#8221; and executed while the colleague purportedly distanced himself from his formal ties to Binance. The colleague in question has since left the company.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Srivastava joined Binance in April 2022 after a role at Mastercard, where she managed fintech coverage for Western Europe. She told the tribunal that she initially believed in the company&#8217;s commitment to improving compliance, especially given the global regulatory pressure it faced. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, she described a &#8220;chaotic&#8221; work culture and said her unit faced mounting pressure to close deals, particularly after losing significant revenue streams tied to a client with alleged links to Iran.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Binance response</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The former executive claims she reported the bribery incident to her managers in April 2023 but was terminated a month later for what Binance claims was &#8220;poor performance.&#8221; </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a statement, Binance&#8217;s lawyer maintained that the decision to end Srivastava&#8217;s employment predated her whistleblowing, adding that the alleged bribery was already known and under internal review.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, Srivastava asserts that her dismissal was linked directly to her decision to report the alleged misconduct. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under UK law, whistleblowing awards in employment tribunals are uncapped, potentially exposing Binance to significant financial liabilities if the court upholds Srivastava&#8217;s claims. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">She has alleged that her experience at Binance caused severe damage to her career and reputation, which she anticipates will take years to repair. Srivastava concluded:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;My experience at Binance has been personally damaging to my career, an impact I will continue to have to undo over the next few years.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/">Ex-Binance executive alleges retaliatory firing over bribery whistleblowing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ex-binance-executive-alleges-retaliatory-firing-over-bribery-whistleblowing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/binance-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/binance-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celo&#8217;s token drops as Coinbase skips Layer-2 migration support</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 15:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Celo, a prominent Layer-1 blockchain, has seen its native token dump 5% after its upcoming transition to an Ethereum Layer-2 network within Optimism&#8217;s Superchain ecosystem turned &#8220;contentious.&#8221; On Nov. 27, Coinbase, the largest US-based crypto exchange, announced that it would not support Celo&#8217;s migration into a Layer 2 network. In contrast, Tether&#8217;s CEO Paolo Ardoino [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/">Celo&#8217;s token drops as Coinbase skips Layer-2 migration support</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/celo/">Celo</a>, a prominent Layer-1 blockchain, has seen its native token dump 5% after its upcoming transition to an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> Layer-2 network within <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/optimism/">Optimism&#8217;s</a> Superchain ecosystem turned &#8220;contentious.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Nov. 27, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>, the largest US-based crypto exchange, announced that it would not support Celo&#8217;s migration into a Layer 2 network. In contrast, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/tether/">Tether&#8217;s</a> CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paolo-ardoino/">Paolo Ardoino</a> confirmed the stablecoin issuer&#8217;s continued support for the network post-transition into the Ethereum ecosystem.</p>
<p>Data from <em>CryptoSlate</em> showed that this uncertainty negatively impacted the network&#8217;s CELO token, which fell 5% to $<span class="holepunch holepunch-coin_price_usd">0.81039 at press time.</span></p>
<h2>Community reaction</h2>
<p>These diverging views sparked mixed reactions within the community, with many criticizing Coinbase&#8217;s decision.</p>
<p>Marek Olszewski, CEO of Celo&#8217;s developer cLabs, <a href="https://x.com/marek_/status/1861900233460080650">expressed</a> disappointment with Coinbase&#8217;s stance. He <a href="https://x.com/marek_/status/1861900233460080650">questioned</a> whether this decision might deter other Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM)-compatible Layer-1 chains from embracing Ethereum&#8217;s Layer-2 scaling solutions.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the founder of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken&#8217;s</a> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/">Inkchain</a>, Andrew Koller, assured that his exchange would support the migration into an L2. He <a href="https://x.com/ak47ink/status/1861959538137854144">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<span class="css-1jxf684 r-bcqeeo r-1ttztb7 r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">Kraken and Ink [loves]</span><span class="css-1jxf684 r-bcqeeo r-1ttztb7 r-qvutc0 r-poiln3"> the superchain and are fully committed to Ethereum scaling and making Kraken work for Celo users. we&#8217;ve asked the relevant teams to explore this to see if we can hit everything in time for Jan. 16th.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Despite the setback, Olszewski <a href="https://x.com/marek_/status/1861842855599522064">suggested</a> the Celo community could consider renaming its existing Layer-1 chain to &#8220;Celo Gold (CGLD)&#8221; to accommodate Coinbase&#8217;s current support framework. He hinted that this might simplify future adoption if Coinbase supports the Layer-2 upgrade.</p>
<h2>Community urges Coinbase to rethink</h2>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/eigenlayer/">EigenLayer</a> founder Sreeram Kannan <a href="https://x.com/sreeramkannan/status/1861911269818974482">speculated</a> that Coinbase&#8217;s decision could stem from &#8220;an oversight&#8221; rather than outright opposition. He encouraged the exchange to revisit its stance, emphasizing the potential benefits of supporting Celo&#8217;s integration into the OP Stack.</p>
<p>Kannan stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I think this is likely an oversight internally in Coinbase. There is no chance the company building the leading Ethereum L2 in users and a core contributor to OP public goods will choose to discontinue supporting Celo after it becomes an OP stack based L2.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, Nass Eddequiouaq, the CEO of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/a16z/">a16z</a>-funded crypto startup Bastion, highlighted the operational and regulatory complexities exchanges face when adding support for new chains, particularly in the US. He <a href="https://x.com/nassyweazy/status/1861989220031627584">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Exchanges and custodian have usually been waiting to see which branch of the fork picks up the activity before adding support for it and deprecating the other one.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/">Celo&#8217;s token drops as Coinbase skips Layer-2 migration support</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celo-ethereum-layer2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celo-ethereum-layer2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cboe unveils cash-settled spot Bitcoin options tied to ETF index</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cboe-unveils-cash-settled-spot-bitcoin-options-tied-to-etf-index/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/cboe-unveils-cash-settled-spot-bitcoin-options-tied-to-etf-index/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 17:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TradFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cboe Global Markets is set to launch the first cash-settled options tied to the price of spot Bitcoin (BTC), with trading set to begin on Dec. 2, according to a Nov. 22 press release. These options will be based on the Cboe Bitcoin Us ETF Index (CBTX), designed to reflect the performance of spot Bitcoin [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cboe-unveils-cash-settled-spot-bitcoin-options-tied-to-etf-index/">Cboe unveils cash-settled spot Bitcoin options tied to ETF index</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/cboe-global-markets/">Cboe Global Markets</a> is set to launch the first cash-settled options tied to the price of spot Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/?s=Bitcoin">BTC</a>), with trading set to begin on Dec. 2, according to a Nov. 22 <a href="https://ir.cboe.com/news/news-details/2024/Cboe-to-Launch-the-First-Cash-Settled-Options-Product-Related-to-Spot-Bitcoin-Beginning-Monday-December-2/default.aspx">press release</a>.</p>
<p>These options will be based on the Cboe Bitcoin Us ETF Index (CBTX), designed to reflect the performance of spot Bitcoin ETFs listed on US exchanges.</p>
<p>The landmark product aims to provide investors with exposure to spot Bitcoin price movements without directly holding the crypto. The launch comes days after US regulators gave Bitcoin options the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/spot-bitcoin-etf-options-set-to-debut-this-week-following-occ-approval-analysts-predict/">final greenlight</a> earlier this month.</p>
<p>The launch includes standard and mini index options, along with customizable FLEX options, offering a range of tools to capitalize on price movements, manage risk, and express market views.</p>
<h2>Approach to Bitcoin Options</h2>
<p>The Cboe Bitcoin US ETF Index is the first of its kind in the US. It leverages a modified market cap-weighted approach to track the performance of spot Bitcoin ETFs. By mirroring spot Bitcoin price trends, the index offers a representative measure of the asset.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ibit-options-trading-volume-surges-to-446m-in-opening-hours-1-6b-by-mid-day/">options</a> will feature cash settlement, ensuring positions are closed in cash at expiration, removing the complexities of Bitcoin ETF delivery. Additionally, the European-style exercise mechanism allows options to be executed only on the expiration date, minimizing early assignment risks.</p>
<p>Mini options, under the ticker MBTX, will be available at 1/10th the notional value of the standard index options, appealing to portfolios of varying sizes and offering flexibility for smaller traders.</p>
<p>FLEX options will provide customization for exercise prices, styles, and expiration dates, catering to sophisticated trading strategies.</p>
<h2>Expanding into digital assets</h2>
<p>The introduction of these Bitcoin options aligns with Cboe&#8217;s broader strategy to enhance its digital asset derivatives portfolio.</p>
<p>The exchange already supports Bitcoin and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> margin futures on its digital platform. Pending regulatory approval, these futures are expected to transition to the Cboe Futures Exchange in 2025.</p>
<p>Adam Inzirillo, Global Head of Data and Access Solutions at Cboe, said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This launch underscores the strength of Cboe’s ecosystem, integrating data, indices, and innovative products to meet diverse investor needs.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Cboe remains at the forefront of digital asset market evolution, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/leveraged-ethereum-etf-to-debut-on-cboe-before-spot-etf-launches/">listing the majority</a> of US spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cboe-unveils-cash-settled-spot-bitcoin-options-tied-to-etf-index/">Cboe unveils cash-settled spot Bitcoin options tied to ETF index</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/cboe-unveils-cash-settled-spot-bitcoin-options-tied-to-etf-index/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/spot-bitcoin-cboe-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/spot-bitcoin-cboe-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
