<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Research | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/research/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/research/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:20:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Research | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/research/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Massive deleveraging stopped Bitcoin from breaking through $100k</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/massive-deleveraging-stopped-bitcoin-from-breaking-through-100k/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/massive-deleveraging-stopped-bitcoin-from-breaking-through-100k/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 15:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deleveraging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[estimated leverage ratio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spot to derivatives volume]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While a bull rally correction has been anticipated, Bitcoin&#8217;s drop from its all-time high of $99,600 to $92,000 managed to wipe out a good chunk of optimism from the market. The pace of Bitcoin&#8217;s growth since the US presidential elections in November led many to expect BTC to break through the coveted $100,000 mark relatively [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/massive-deleveraging-stopped-bitcoin-from-breaking-through-100k/">Massive deleveraging stopped Bitcoin from breaking through $100k</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">While a bull rally correction has been anticipated, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> drop from its all-time high of $99,600 to $92,000 managed to wipe out a good chunk of optimism from the market. The pace of Bitcoin&#8217;s growth since the US presidential elections in November led many to expect BTC to break through the coveted $100,000 mark relatively quickly and enter into a full-blown bull market by year&#8217;s end.</p>
<p class="p1">Previous CryptoSlate <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sky-high-bitcoin-funding-rates-show-a-leveraged-bullish-market/">research</a> analyzed futures funding rates, exploring how the cost of maintaining positions reflects market sentiment. Consistently high volume-weighted and open interest-weighted funding rates mirrored the market&#8217;s optimism and showed that the rally was mostly driven by derivatives trading.</p>
<p class="p1">However, it also showed a significant danger of the market overheating, as elevated funding rates signal excessive leverage that creates a fragile market environment. Periods of high funding rates often precede sharp corrections, as overextended traders are forced to exit positions.</p>
<p class="p1">The extent of this leverage can be seen through the estimated leverage ratio (ELR). ELR is calculated by dividing the open interest in derivatives markets by Bitcoin&#8217;s total exchange reserves. A rising ELR indicates that more leverage is utilized relative to the available Bitcoin, signaling heightened speculation.</p>
<p class="p1">The ELR also provides a window into how aggressive traders are in taking leveraged positions and how much of the market is driven by derivatives rather than spot activity. Since the beginning of September, the ELR has grown significantly, following Bitcoin&#8217;s rally from $65,000 to $98,000. This shows that traders were riding the bullish momentum and deploying leverage along the way, amplifying the upward price action we&#8217;ve seen in the past three months.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455681" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455681" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455681" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges.png" alt="Bitcoin Estimated Leverage Ratio - All Exchanges" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Estimated-Leverage-Ratio-All-Exchanges-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455681" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s estimated leverage ratio (ELR) from Sep. 1 to Dec. 3, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/market-indicator/estimated-leverage-ratio?exchange=all_exchange&amp;window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">However, in the last few days of November, the ELR began to decline even as Bitcoin&#8217;s price remained near or at its all-time high. This divergence is particularly important when analyzing the market, as it indicates a phase of deleveraging or risk reduction.</p>
<p class="p1">Traders may have started unwinding their leveraged positions to secure profits or avoid liquidation risk in an increasingly volatile environment. The decline in ELR indicates that leveraged activity was scaling back, reducing the speculative pressure that had driven the rally.</p>
<p class="p1">Given the market&#8217;s current sensitivity, this deleveraging couldn&#8217;t go unnoticed, pushing BTC further down to $92,000.</p>
<p class="p1">We know that deleveraging in the derivatives market caused this drop by looking at the ratio between spot and derivatives trading volume. Derivatives have consistently dwarfed spot trading volume, showing just how much speculative activity influences price.</p>
<p class="p1">In November, the trading volume ratio between spot and derivatives markets remained low, signaling that most activity was concentrated in derivatives rather than spot markets. As the price peaked, the derivative trading volume spiked even further, while spot volume showed less dramatic growth. This indicates that the price rally was heavily influenced by leveraged traders rather than organic demand from spot buyers.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455682" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455682" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455682" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative.png" alt="Bitcoin Trading Volume Ratio (Spot VS. Derivative)" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Ratio-Spot-VS.-Derivative-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455682" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s spot-to-derivatives trading volume ratio from Sep. 1 to Dec. 3, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/research/trading-volume-ratio-spot-vs-derivative?window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">In the final days of November and the first two days of December, the derivative volume began to decline sharply, reflected in both the absolute trading volumes and the trading volume ratio. This drop in derivative activity coincided with the decline in ELR, suggesting that traders were scaling back their speculative positions.</p>
<p class="p1">The falling spot-to-derivative volume ratio during the rally and its slight recovery as prices stabilized near $95,000 suggests a temporary pullback in speculative fervor. However, the lower ratio overall signals that derivatives markets remain the primary driver of Bitcoin&#8217;s price movements, even during deleveraging phases.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455683" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455683" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455683" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative.png" alt="Bitcoin Trading Volume (Spot VS. Derivative)" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/Bitcoin-Trading-Volume-Spot-VS.-Derivative-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455683" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s spot and derivatives trading volume from Sep. 1 to Dec. 3, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/research/trading-volume-spot-vs-derivative?window=DAY&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The combination of ELR and trading volume metrics reveals the extent to which speculative activity drives Bitcoin&#8217;s price movements and how leverage can amplify both rallies and corrections. The recent decline in ELR and derivatives volume, coupled with a slight recovery in the spot-to-derivative ratio, suggests that the market is entering a period of consolidation.</p>
<p class="p1">If organic spot activity increases, this may provide a healthier foundation for future price moves.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/massive-deleveraging-stopped-bitcoin-from-breaking-through-100k/">Massive deleveraging stopped Bitcoin from breaking through $100k</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/massive-deleveraging-stopped-bitcoin-from-breaking-through-100k/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bitcoin-deleverage-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bitcoin-deleverage-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US influence over Bitcoin grows with Trump victory</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/us-influence-over-bitcoin-grows-with-trump-victory/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/us-influence-over-bitcoin-grows-with-trump-victory/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 02:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coinbase premium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us entities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[us supply]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USA]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The United States has never been the largest market for Bitcoin or cryptocurrencies in terms of trading volume. Offshore exchanges, particularly in Asia, have consistently dominated global trading activity, with platforms like Binance and Huobi driving liquidity and volatility. However, the US has always held a unique position as the most influential force in the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-influence-over-bitcoin-grows-with-trump-victory/">US influence over Bitcoin grows with Trump victory</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">The United States has never been the largest market for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> or cryptocurrencies in terms of trading volume. Offshore exchanges, particularly in Asia, have consistently dominated global trading activity, with platforms like Binance and Huobi driving liquidity and volatility.</p>
<p class="p1">However, the US has always held a unique position as the most influential force in the crypto industry. It has historically set the tone for the rest of the world, shaping the development and perception of Bitcoin as a legitimate asset class.</p>
<p class="p1">This dominance can be observed through the pricing discrepancies and supply distribution metrics that reflect the behavior of US-based market participants. Two key indicators — the Coinbase Premium and the US to The Rest Reserve Ratio — offer a window into the evolving role of the United States in the global Bitcoin ecosystem.</p>
<p class="p1">These metrics track the premium of US exchanges over offshore platforms and the proportion of Bitcoin held by US entities relative to the rest of the world, illustrating regional demand and supply distribution.</p>
<p class="p1">The Coinbase Premium is a proxy for US demand, reflecting periods when US investors drive Bitcoin&#8217;s price higher than on offshore platforms. Conversely, a negative premium often indicates that offshore markets dominate price discovery.</p>
<p class="p1">Meanwhile, the US to The Rest Reserve Ratio shows accumulation trends of US-based institutions, exchanges, and custodians compared to global counterparts. Together, these metrics reveal the interplay between US and offshore markets and the underlying shifts in sentiment, regulatory influence, and institutional adoption.</p>
<p class="p1">The impact the US presidential elections had on the market is clearly visible in the Coinbase Premium and reserve ratio data. These changes show how regional sentiment responded to the prospect of a more crypto-friendly regulatory environment in the US.</p>
<p class="p1">The Coinbase Premium chart reveals significant volatility in US demand in the past three months. The premium remained negative in early September, suggesting weaker buying pressure from the US, which indicates that offshore exchanges drove Bitcoin&#8217;s price. However, as Bitcoin&#8217;s price began to rise at the end of the month, the premium shifted, occasionally turning positive.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455150" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455150" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455150" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1.png" alt="Bitcoin Coinbase Premium Index" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Coinbase-Premium-Index-1-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455150" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the Coinbase Premium Index from Sep. 1 to Nov. 28, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/market-data/coinbase-premium-index?window=DAY&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The deviation reflects intermittent periods of strong US demand, likely driven by speculation on the outcome of the elections. Bitcoin saw a sharp rally in mid-October, yet the Coinbase Premium turned decisively negative, indicating that offshore entities, particularly in Asia, were the primary drivers of this price increase. The negative premium during this rally also suggests that US-based traders were engaging in arbitrage by taking advantage of lower prices on Coinbase Pro compared to offshore platforms like Binance.</p>
<p class="p1">The US to The Rest Reserve Ratio tells a parallel story of rising institutional accumulation in the US. Despite the negative premium during October&#8217;s price rally, the reserve ratio steadily climbed, indicating that US-based entities added to their Bitcoin holdings.</p>
<p class="p1">By late October, the reserve ratio saw a sharp uptick, coinciding with speculation around the US election and expectations of a pro-crypto administration. Following Trump&#8217;s victory on Nov. 5, the reserve ratio surged even higher, reflecting increased accumulation by US-based institutions and custodians.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455151" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455151" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-455151" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio.png" alt="Bitcoin U.S. to The Rest Reserve Ratio" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-U.S.-to-The-Rest-Reserve-Ratio-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455151" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the US to the rest reserve ratio from Sep. 1 to Nov. 28, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/research/us-to-the-rest-reserve-ratio?window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">Interestingly, the Coinbase Premium turned positive in late November, aligning with a stabilization in the reserve ratio. This shift indicates that US retail traders re-entered the market, causing an uptick in demand on Coinbase Pro. The renewed buying interest from US traders came as Bitcoin&#8217;s price stabilized around $95,000, showing how the announcement of favorable crypto policies boosted sentiment and demand within the US market.</p>
<p class="p1">While offshore exchanges dominated price movements in earlier months, the steady rise in the US reserve ratio demonstrates growing institutional confidence and accumulation within the US This trend was amplified following Trump&#8217;s election and talks of a strategic Bitcoin reserve, which signaled a renewed commitment to positioning the US as a leader in the crypto industry.</p>
<p class="p1">US-based entities&#8217; steady accumulation of Bitcoin suggests a long-term shift toward institutional adoption and regulatory clarity. Trump&#8217;s policy announcements have reinforced this trend, likely accelerating the US&#8217;s position as a dominant force in Bitcoin markets.</p>
<p class="p1">However, the negative Coinbase Premium during key price rallies highlights the ongoing influence of offshore markets, particularly in driving short-term volatility.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-influence-over-bitcoin-grows-with-trump-victory/">US influence over Bitcoin grows with Trump victory</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/us-influence-over-bitcoin-grows-with-trump-victory/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-research-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-research-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short-term holders hit with losses as Bitcoin fell below $93k</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/short-term-holders-face-strain-as-btc-drops-below-93k/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/short-term-holders-face-strain-as-btc-drops-below-93k/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 02:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short-term holders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STH]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STH-MVRV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[STH-SOPR]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454870</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s recent correction to $92,000 came after failing to breach the psychological resistance at $100,000, a critical level expected to mark a new chapter in the ongoing bull market. While corrections of up to -30% are frequent during bull runs, the sharp decline below $93,000 caused a segment of short-term holders (STHs) to realize losses. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/short-term-holders-face-strain-as-btc-drops-below-93k/">Short-term holders hit with losses as Bitcoin fell below $93k</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Bitcoin&#8217;s recent <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoins-sudden-dip-under-95k-incurs-180-million-in-trader-losses-stalls-100k-momentum/">correction</a> to $92,000 came after failing to breach the psychological resistance at $100,000, a critical level expected to mark a new chapter in the ongoing bull market.</p>
<p class="p1">While corrections of up to -30% are frequent during bull runs, the sharp decline below $93,000 caused a segment of short-term holders (STHs) to realize losses.</p>
<p class="p1">The spent output profit ratio (SOPR) measures the profitability of coins moved within a specific timeframe. When applied to short-term holders (STHs), i.e., addresses that have held onto their <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a> for less than six months, the ratio enables us to measure the profitability of coins moved by this particular cohort.</p>
<p class="p1">Short-term holder SOPR is calculated by dividing the value of spent outputs at the time of spending by the value of the same outputs at the time they were created. A value above 1 indicates that coins are being sold at a profit, while a value below 1 signifies realized losses. When STH SOPR trends higher, it signals improving market sentiment and conditions for short-term holders, whereas a declining SOPR reflects deteriorating profitability and potentially weaker sentiment among short-term investors.</p>
<p class="p1">On Nov. 17, as Bitcoin was trading just below $90,000, STH SOPR stood at 1.0117, indicating marginal profitability among STHs. By Nov. 21, when Bitcoin reached an all-time high of $98,430, STH SOPR surged to 1.0966, reflecting widespread profit-taking as prices neared six-figure territory.</p>
<p class="p1">However, as Bitcoin&#8217;s price dropped, STH SOPR declined to 1.0144 on Nov. 25 and fell below 1 on Nov. 26 to 0.9995. This marked a critical shift — short-term holders, on average, started realizing small losses, a stark contrast to the earlier phase of profit-taking.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454889" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454889" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454889" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR.png" alt="Bitcoin Short Term Holder SOPR" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Short-Term-Holder-SOPR-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454889" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the STH SOPR from Oct. 27 to Nov. 26, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/market-indicator/short-term-holder-sopr?window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=log&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The drop in STH SOPR shows the psychological impact of Bitcoin&#8217;s failure to sustain its rally above $100,000. During bull rallies, sustained values above 1 indicate strong market confidence, as STHs are willing to sell at a profit, confident that others will buy higher.</p>
<p class="p1">The dip below 1 suggests increasing hesitancy, potentially driven by panic selling or forced liquidations. This is important to monitor as it often marks the capitulation of weak hands, cleansing the market of excessive leverage and speculative positions.</p>
<p class="p1">Changes in the short-term holder market value to realized value (MVRV) ratio further indicate such capitulation is taking place. MVRV measures the unrealized profit or loss of a group of holders by comparing the market value of their holdings to their realized value. A value above 1 indicates that STHs, on average, hold coins at a profit, while a value below 1 suggests unrealized losses.</p>
<p class="p1">On Nov. 21, STH MVRV reached 1.3447, signaling that short-term holders were sitting on a 34.47% average unrealized profit during Bitcoin&#8217;s rally. However, by Nov.26, the STH MVRV declined to 1.2459, showing reduced profitability after Bitcoin&#8217;s correction. The decline in MVRV aligns with the drop in STH SOPR, confirming that profitability for STHs was eroded as prices fell below $93,000.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454890" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454890" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454890" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator.png" alt="BTC Short-Term Holder MVRV Indicator" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/BTC-Short-Term-Holder-MVRV-Indicator-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454890" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the STH MVRV indicator from Nov. 28, 2019, to Nov. 26, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/analytics/query/65df235c0168b95f8eac8dca?v=65df235c0168b95f8eac8dcc">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">These two ratios reflect the psychological toll rapid price declines have on short-term holders. Realized losses, particularly among STHs, tend to exacerbate negative sentiment and accelerate capitulation.</p>
<p class="p1">However, this phase of capitulation may serve a constructive role in the broader market cycle. By shaking out overleveraged positions and weak hands, the correction could establish a more solid foundation for Bitcoin&#8217;s next leg upward. The recent decline in STH SOPR and MVRV appears to have reset the short-term market, potentially clearing the way for stronger support levels around $92,000 to $93,000.</p>
<p class="p1">However, if the decline in STH SOPR and MVRV persists or accelerates, it may signal deeper underlying weakness in the market. Extended periods of realized losses among STHs <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-could-fall-to-88000-before-making-another-attempt-to-break-100000-glassnode/">could undermine confidence</a>, leading to further sell-offs and a prolonged downturn.</p>
<p class="p1">Additionally, the failure to sustain levels near $100,000 could dampen the enthusiasm of institutional investors and retail participants alike, creating additional resistance to any recovery attempts.</p>
<p class="p1">Ultimately, the correction below $93,000 and the resulting behavior of STHs reflect the natural ebb and flow of a volatile market. While realized losses have shaken out weaker participants, the broader structural narrative remains intact. Bitcoin&#8217;s historical resilience, coupled with a potential reset in leverage and speculative positions, suggests the possibility of a renewed uptrend.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/short-term-holders-face-strain-as-btc-drops-below-93k/">Short-term holders hit with losses as Bitcoin fell below $93k</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/short-term-holders-face-strain-as-btc-drops-below-93k/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-research-analysis.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-research-analysis.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sky-high Bitcoin funding rates show a leveraged yet bullish market</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sky-high-bitcoin-funding-rates-show-a-leveraged-bullish-market/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sky-high-bitcoin-funding-rates-show-a-leveraged-bullish-market/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin funding rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funding rate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perpetual futures funding rate]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s perpetual futures funding rate represents the cost traders incur to maintain long or short positions in the perpetual swaps market, with fees shifting between buyers and sellers based on market conditions. Positive funding rates suggest that long positions dominate, reflecting bullish sentiment, while negative rates indicate bearish sentiment as short positions dominate. Changes in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sky-high-bitcoin-funding-rates-show-a-leveraged-bullish-market/">Sky-high Bitcoin funding rates show a leveraged yet bullish market</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Bitcoin&#8217;s perpetual futures funding rate represents the cost traders incur to maintain long or short positions in the perpetual swaps market, with fees shifting between buyers and sellers based on market conditions.</p>
<p class="p1">Positive funding rates suggest that long positions dominate, reflecting bullish sentiment, while negative rates indicate bearish sentiment as short positions dominate.</p>
<p class="p1">Changes in funding rates provide insight into trader positioning and market risk. Spikes in funding rates often precede corrections, signaling heightened speculation and overleveraging. Conversely, negative or neutral funding rates during consolidations can signal potential entry points for strategic investors.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454560" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454560" style="width: 1405px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454560" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-15.10.06.png" alt="bitcoin funding rate" width="1405" height="239" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-15.10.06.png 1405w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-15.10.06-300x51.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-15.10.06-1024x174.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-15.10.06-768x131.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1405px) 100vw, 1405px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454560" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s funding rate from Nov. 1 to Nov. 25, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/FundingRate">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">Bitcoin&#8217;s current funding rate tracks the strong rally we&#8217;ve seen in November. Since the beginning of the month, both volume-weighted and open interest (OI)-weighted funding rates have remained consistently positive, reaching the highest levels in over a year. This sustained positivity shows the dominance of long positions, with traders paying a premium to maintain these positions.</p>
<p class="p1">The market sentiment has been decisively bullish, as evidenced by traders&#8217; willingness to incur higher funding costs in anticipation of continued price increases. The heightened funding rates show that leveraged long positions have contributed to the rally.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454559" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454559" style="width: 1053px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454559" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.29.png" alt="bitcoin OI-weighted funding rate" width="1053" height="323" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.29.png 1053w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.29-300x92.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.29-1024x314.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.29-768x236.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1053px) 100vw, 1053px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454559" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s open interest-weighted funding rate from May 29 to Nov. 25, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/FundingRate">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The volume-weighted funding rate showed greater volatility than the OI-weighted rate, suggesting that trading volumes had a pronounced impact during these rapid price increases. This volatility reflects speculative activity, with traders aggressively opening positions to capitalize on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> momentum.</p>
<p class="p1">However, earlier in the year, the situation was markedly different. From late June to mid-September, the market saw multiple instances of negative funding rates, particularly in the volume-weighted metric. This reflected bearish sentiment as Bitcoin&#8217;s price struggled to break out of a range-bound phase.</p>
<p class="p1">During these months, traders heavily favored short positions, a cautious outlook that aligned with subdued price action. The shift to consistently positive funding rates in late Q3 marked a turning point, signaling a broader transition to bullish sentiment as Bitcoin&#8217;s price recovered.</p>
<p class="p1">The volume-weighted funding rate demonstrated greater sensitivity to market speculation than the OI-weighted rate. This distinction became particularly apparent during high-activity periods. While the OI-weighted metric, being smoother, reflects broader market leverage trends, the volume-weighted rate captures short-term fluctuations driven by speculative traders.</p>
<p class="p1">The increase in both metrics from late September through October revealed a gradual build-up of bullish sentiment. This trend suggests that Bitcoin&#8217;s rally was not purely driven by spot market activity but also by the growing influence of leverage in derivatives markets. The alignment of positive funding rates with sustained price gains highlights the role of leveraged traders in reinforcing bullish trends.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454557" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454557" style="width: 1053px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-454557 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.36.png" alt="bitcoin volume-weighted funding rate" width="1053" height="323" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.36.png 1053w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.36-300x92.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.36-1024x314.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-25-at-12.33.36-768x236.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1053px) 100vw, 1053px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454557" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s volume-weighted funding rate from May 29 to Nov. 25, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/FundingRate">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">Despite this bullish momentum, the persistently high funding rates in November raises concerns about market overheating. When funding rates remain elevated for extended periods, it often signals excessive leverage, creating a fragile market environment. Overleveraging heightens the risk of cascading liquidations if prices suddenly reverse. Periods of high funding rates often precede sharp corrections as overextended traders are forced to exit positions.</p>
<p class="p1">Conversely, the negative funding rates observed in July and September provided contrarian buy signals. During these periods, excessive bearish sentiment set the stage for price rebounds, highlighting the value of funding rates as a predictive tool.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sky-high-bitcoin-funding-rates-show-a-leveraged-bullish-market/">Sky-high Bitcoin funding rates show a leveraged yet bullish market</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sky-high-bitcoin-funding-rates-show-a-leveraged-bullish-market/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-funding-rate.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-funding-rate.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weak euro fuels Bitcoin&#8217;s standout performance in Eurozone</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/weak-euro-fuels-bitcoins-standout-performance-in-eurozone/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/weak-euro-fuels-bitcoins-standout-performance-in-eurozone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 09:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin fiat trading pairs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[British pound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btceur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[btcgbp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTCUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Euro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Dollar]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BTCUSD, BTCGBP, and BTCEUR are the most traded Bitcoin pairs, each reflecting the interaction between Bitcoin and the specific economic environment of their underlying currencies. Analyzing their respective performances allows us to gain insight into the global Bitcoin market and how local economic conditions influence price action. While this data is limited to a single [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/weak-euro-fuels-bitcoins-standout-performance-in-eurozone/">Weak euro fuels Bitcoin&#8217;s standout performance in Eurozone</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">BTCUSD, BTCGBP, and BTCEUR are the most traded <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> pairs, each reflecting the interaction between Bitcoin and the specific economic environment of their underlying currencies. Analyzing their respective performances allows us to gain insight into the global Bitcoin market and how local economic conditions influence price action. While this data is limited to a single exchange, in this case, Bitstamp, it provides a representative view of broader trends and allows for meaningful conclusions.</p>
<p class="p1">Year-to-date, BTCEUR has delivered the highest returns, with a gain of 130.39%, compared to 122.24% for BTCGBP and 120.85% for BTCUSD. This outperformance can largely be attributed to the euro&#8217;s weakness relative to the dollar and pound. With the Eurozone grappling with low growth and limited monetary policy flexibility, the currency has suffered against a backdrop of dollar strength.</p>
<p class="p1">This depreciation amplifies Bitcoin&#8217;s gains in EUR terms, as it takes more euros to purchase the same amount of BTC. By contrast, the dollar&#8217;s strength—underpinned by strong US economic data, robust Treasury yields, and expectations of higher-for-longer Federal Reserve policy—has dampened BTCUSD&#8217;s apparent gains, as a stronger dollar offsets the upward pressure on Bitcoin&#8217;s price.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454103" style="width: 1226px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454103" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-ytd-performance.png" alt="bitcoin fiat pairs ytd performance" width="1226" height="792" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-ytd-performance.png 1226w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-ytd-performance-300x194.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-ytd-performance-1024x662.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-ytd-performance-768x496.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1226px) 100vw, 1226px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454103" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the YTD performance of BTCUSD, BTCGBP, and BTCEUR (Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/nDPOT2hW/">TradingView</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">In the three-month window, the trends remain consistent, with BTCEUR continuing to outperform BTCGBP and BTCUSD. During this period, euro weakness became even more pronounced, falling to a one-year low against the dollar. This decline reflects a combination of disappointing Eurozone growth metrics, dovish signals from the European Central Bank, and geopolitical uncertainties.</p>
<p class="p1">Meanwhile, BTCGBP has shown a slightly more robust performance than BTCUSD, highlighting the pound&#8217;s relative weakness. The UK&#8217;s persistent economic stagnation and reduced hawkishness from the Bank of England have placed pressure on GBP, even as it maintains marginally more resilience than the euro.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454104" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454104" style="width: 1226px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454104" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-3m-performance.png" alt="bitcoin fiat pairs 3m performance" width="1226" height="792" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-3m-performance.png 1226w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-3m-performance-300x194.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-3m-performance-1024x662.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-3m-performance-768x496.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1226px) 100vw, 1226px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454104" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the three-month performance of BTCUSD, BTCGBP, and BTCEUR (Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/nDPOT2hW/">TradingView</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The price action since the US election shows that Bitcoin&#8217;s performance against these three currencies reflects the most recent macroeconomic and geopolitical developments. BTCUSD gained 42.38%, trailing BTCEUR and BTCGBP, which grew 46.22% and 45.87%, respectively. The dollar&#8217;s persistent strength has been vital in tempering BTCUSD&#8217;s gains. The market&#8217;s response to the US election was aggressive.</p>
<p class="p1">As the upcoming Trump administration&#8217;s policies are expected to boost US growth, the election strengthened the dollar and drove further demand for US assets, weighing on BTCUSD. In contrast, BTCEUR and BTCGBP were relatively unaffected by this political event, and their performances remained largely a function of their respective fiat weaknesses.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454105" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454105" style="width: 1226px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454105" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-1m-performance.png" alt="bitcoin fiat pairs 1m performance" width="1226" height="792" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-1m-performance.png 1226w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-1m-performance-300x194.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-1m-performance-1024x662.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-1m-performance-768x496.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1226px) 100vw, 1226px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454105" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the one-month performance of BTCUSD, BTCGBP, and BTCEUR (Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/nDPOT2hW/">TradingView</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The divergence in Bitcoin&#8217;s performance across these pairs also shows the influence fiat volatility has on perceived returns. The euro and the pound have been far more volatile than the dollar this year, particularly given the contrasting monetary policies and economic prospects of each area.</p>
<p class="p1">This volatility exaggerates Bitcoin&#8217;s price movements in EUR and GBP terms, creating the illusion of greater returns compared to BTCUSD. As the Eurozone continues to face structural growth challenges, Bitcoin&#8217;s outperformance against the euro is likely to persist. While under similar pressure, the pound has shown slightly more resilience due to less severe structural concerns, which aligns with BTCGBP&#8217;s middle-ground performance relative to BTCUSD and BTCEUR.</p>
<figure id="attachment_454106" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-454106" style="width: 1226px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-454106" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-performance-since-us-election.png" alt="bitcoin fiat pairs performance since us election" width="1226" height="792" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-performance-since-us-election.png 1226w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-performance-since-us-election-300x194.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-performance-since-us-election-1024x662.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-fiat-pairs-performance-since-us-election-768x496.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1226px) 100vw, 1226px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-454106" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the performance of BTCUSD, BTCGBP, and BTCEUR from Nov. 4 to Nov. 21, 2024 (Source: TradingView)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The short-term trends observed since the US election on Nov. 5 reveal a rather interesting market state. Despite the USD&#8217;s strength, BTCUSD steadily increased during this period. This suggests that while the dollar&#8217;s strength muted Bitcoin&#8217;s gains compared to BTCEUR and BTCGBP, it did not entirely stifle its price momentum.</p>
<p class="p1">For BTCEUR and BTCGBP, continued EUR and GBP weakness after the election allowed Bitcoin to sustain its relative outperformance. This is particularly relevant given that Eurozone and UK markets increasingly look to Bitcoin as a hedge against depreciating fiat currencies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/weak-euro-fuels-bitcoins-standout-performance-in-eurozone/">Weak euro fuels Bitcoin&#8217;s standout performance in Eurozone</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/weak-euro-fuels-bitcoins-standout-performance-in-eurozone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/digital-euro-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/digital-euro-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin&#8217;s independence from S&#038;P 500, Nasdaq grows post-election</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-independence-from-sp-500-nasdaq-grows-post-election/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-independence-from-sp-500-nasdaq-grows-post-election/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 15:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[correlation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nasdaq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NDQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S&P 500]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453863</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s safe to say that Bitcoin has slowly evolved into a macro asset. As such, its relationship with major traditional indices like the S&#38;P 500 (SPX) and the Nasdaq Composite (NDQ) becomes a significant indicator of investor sentiment and use case evolution. These indices represent vital pillars of the traditional financial system: SPX reflects broader [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-independence-from-sp-500-nasdaq-grows-post-election/">Bitcoin&#8217;s independence from S&#038;P 500, Nasdaq grows post-election</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">It&#8217;s safe to say that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> has slowly evolved into a macro asset. As such, its relationship with major traditional indices like the S&amp;P 500 (SPX) and the Nasdaq Composite (NDQ) becomes a significant indicator of investor sentiment and use case evolution.</p>
<p class="p1">These indices represent vital pillars of the traditional financial system: SPX reflects broader market trends, while Nasdaq is a tech-heavy benchmark closely tied to growth sectors and innovation. By monitoring how Bitcoin interacts with these indices, we can see whether it behaves more as a risk-on asset, correlated to equities, or a hedge, decoupling during times of uncertainty.</p>
<p class="p1">Changes in Bitcoin&#8217;s correlation with traditional assets reveal shifts in market perception. A strong positive correlation suggests Bitcoin is moving in lockstep with equities, possibly as a speculative asset tied to risk-on behavior. A weakening or negative correlation, however, indicates Bitcoin is being treated as a hedge—akin to gold—against macroeconomic uncertainty, inflation, or geopolitical risks. These shifts can provide valuable context for Bitcoin&#8217;s price movements.</p>
<p class="p1">Over the past three months, Bitcoin outperformed both SPX and Nasdaq by a wide margin. Bitcoin gained 58.79%, while SPX rose a modest 5.10% and Nasdaq gained 6.10%. This divergence became particularly pronounced after the US presidential election, when BTC surged to an all-time high of over $93,000, leaving traditional indices far behind.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453914" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453914" style="width: 2168px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-453914 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m.png" alt="bitcoin nasdaq correlation 3m" width="2168" height="1314" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m.png 2168w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m-300x182.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m-1024x621.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m-768x465.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m-1536x931.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-3m-2048x1241.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2168px) 100vw, 2168px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453914" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the 3-month correlation coefficient between Bitcoin&#8217;s price on Coinbase and the Nasdaq Composite Index (NDQ) (Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/nDPOT2hW/">TradingView</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The correlation coefficients between Bitcoin and the indices fluctuated during this period, but both ended in weakly negative territory. Bitcoin&#8217;s correlation with SPX settled at approximately -0.17, while its correlation with Nasdaq hovered around -0.17 as well. Before the election, there were brief periods of positive correlation, likely driven by macroeconomic events affecting all markets. However, the post-election period marked a clear decoupling as Bitcoin&#8217;s hedge appeal and speculative fervor took center stage.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453917" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453917" style="width: 1152px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453917" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-3m.png" alt="btc spx correlation 3m" width="1152" height="792" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-3m.png 1152w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-3m-300x206.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-3m-1024x704.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-3m-768x528.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453917" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the 3-month correlation coefficient between Bitcoin&#8217;s price on Coinbase and the S&amp;P 500 Index (Source: TradingView)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The weakening correlation shows that Bitcoin is increasingly moving independently of traditional equities. While SPX and Nasdaq reacted to earnings, interest rate expectations, and geopolitical concerns, Bitcoin&#8217;s price was driven by narratives of institutional adoption, scarcity, and its role as an inflation hedge.</p>
<p class="p1">The 1-month data paints a similar but more concentrated picture. Bitcoin rose 36.52% in just 30 days, compared to a 0.99% gain for SPX and a 1.72% gain for Nasdaq. The post-election rally was the main driver of Bitcoin&#8217;s outsized performance, as enthusiasm around its long-term potential overshadowed the relatively cautious movements in traditional markets.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453919" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453919" style="width: 2168px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-453919 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m.png" alt="btc nasdaq correlation 1m" width="2168" height="1314" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m.png 2168w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m-300x182.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m-1024x621.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m-768x465.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m-1536x931.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-nasdaq-correlation-1m-2048x1241.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2168px) 100vw, 2168px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453919" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the one-month correlation coefficient between Bitcoin&#8217;s price on Coinbase and the Nasdaq Composite Index (NDQ) (Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/nDPOT2hW/">TradingView</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The correlation coefficient during this period shows an even sharper decoupling. Bitcoin&#8217;s correlation with SPX fell to -0.35, while its correlation with Nasdaq dropped to -0.17. This suggests that while traditional markets reflected mixed investor sentiment—balancing optimism about economic recovery with concerns over geopolitical risks—Bitcoin was seen as a more straightforward bet on future growth and a hedge against uncertainty.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453920" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453920" style="width: 1152px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-453920 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-1m.png" alt="btc spx correlation 1m" width="1152" height="792" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-1m.png 1152w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-1m-300x206.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-1m-1024x704.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/btc-spx-correlation-1m-768x528.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1152px) 100vw, 1152px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453920" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the one-month correlation coefficient between Bitcoin&#8217;s price on Coinbase and the S&amp;P 500 Index (Source: TradingView)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">Interestingly, the correlation with Nasdaq was less negative than with SPX. This could be due to overlapping investor bases between Bitcoin and the tech sector, both of which attract growth-oriented, risk-tolerant capital. However, the overall trend is clear: Bitcoin&#8217;s independence is growing, particularly during high-volatility events like the election.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-independence-from-sp-500-nasdaq-grows-post-election/">Bitcoin&#8217;s independence from S&#038;P 500, Nasdaq grows post-election</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-independence-from-sp-500-nasdaq-grows-post-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-research.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-research.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exchange stablecoin ratio hits record low, fueling Bitcoin surge</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/exchange-stablecoin-ratio-hits-record-low-fueling-bitcoin-surge/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/exchange-stablecoin-ratio-hits-record-low-fueling-bitcoin-surge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 02:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchange stablecoin ratio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liquidity]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The exchange stablecoin ratio (ESR) is an on-chain metric that indicates the balance of liquidity between Bitcoin and stablecoins held on exchanges. The metric is calculated as the ratio of the total Bitcoin reserves to the total stablecoin reserves, essentially showing the market&#8217;s buying power and selling pressure. A low ESR indicates that stablecoin reserves [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/exchange-stablecoin-ratio-hits-record-low-fueling-bitcoin-surge/">Exchange stablecoin ratio hits record low, fueling Bitcoin surge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The exchange stablecoin ratio (ESR) is an on-chain metric that indicates the balance of liquidity between <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> and stablecoins held on exchanges.</p>
<p>The metric is calculated as the ratio of the total Bitcoin reserves to the total stablecoin reserves, essentially showing the market&#8217;s buying power and selling pressure.</p>
<p>A low ESR indicates that stablecoin reserves significantly outweigh Bitcoin reserves, suggesting an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-elections-boosted-bitcoins-liquidity-to-new-highs/">abundance of liquidity</a> ready to flow into BTC. This disparity has historically correlated with bull markets and rallies, as stablecoins have always been preferred for purchasing BTC on exchanges.</p>
<p>Conversely, a high ESR suggests that BTC dominates reserves relative to stablecoins, which usually means limited buying power on exchanges and a potential for significant sell pressure.</p>
<p>While there are many different indicators of bull markets, ESR is particularly valuable as it captures the readiness of capital to move into Bitcoin. Unlike isolated price metrics, the ratio reflects underlying liquidity trends and mirrors investor sentiment.</p>
<p>On Nov. 18, the ESR dropped to an all-time low following a declining trend that intensified in 2024. Since the beginning of the year, the ESR decreased by just over 95%, dropping from 0.0015276 on Jan.1 to an all-time low of 0.00007317 by Nov.18. During the same period, Bitcoin&#8217;s price skyrocketed from $44,200 to $90,500, showing a clear inverse relationship between the ratio and price.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453702" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453702" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453702" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges.png" alt="Bitcoin Exchange Stablecoins Ratio - All Exchanges" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453702" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the exchange stablecoin ratio from Feb. 23, 2022, to Nov. 18, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/flow-indicator/exchange-stablecoins-ratio?exchange=all_exchange&amp;window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The US presidential election on Nov. 5 had a profound impact on the market, acting as a catalyst for Bitcoin&#8217;s surge to its all-time high of $93,000. It triggered record trading volumes in both spot and derivatives markets as institutions and retail investors rushed to capitalize on Bitcoin&#8217;s growing narrative as a hedge and store of value. These heightened trading activities drove Bitcoin&#8217;s price higher while stablecoin reserves accumulated, further compressing the ESR.</p>
<p>The all-time low in ESR paired with Bitcoin trading between $90,000 and $92,000 shows a market in a unique position. A low ESR during a period of price growth shows a robust demand fueled by substantial capital reserves in stablecoins.</p>
<p>Such an environment limits the downside risk for Bitcoin, as the abundance of stablecoins creates a sort of liquidity cushion ready to absorb any selling pressure. At the same time, the limited BTC supply on exchanges exacerbates scarcity, pushing prices higher.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453705" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453705" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453705" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3.png" alt="Bitcoin Exchange Reserve - All Exchanges " width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Reserve-All-Exchanges-3-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453705" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the total amount of BTC held on exchanges from Jan. 1 to Nov. 18 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/exchange-flows/exchange-reserve?exchange=all_exchange&amp;window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Looking at the changes over the year, the sharpest drop in the ESR occurred right after the US elections as Bitcoin entered its most aggressive rally this year. This suggests that the market was accumulating stablecoins during periods of price consolidation earlier in the year and deployed them to purchase BTC as soon as sentiment turned bullish.</p>
<p>The interaction we&#8217;ve seen between stablecoin accumulation and rising prices shows that these reserves have a strategic nature — serving both as a buffer and a growth catalyst.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453708" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453708" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453708" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1.png" alt="Bitcoin Exchange Stablecoins Ratio - All Exchanges " width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Exchange-Stablecoins-Ratio-All-Exchanges-1-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453708" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the exchange stablecoin ratio from Jan. 1 to Nov. 18 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/flow-indicator/exchange-stablecoins-ratio?exchange=all_exchange&amp;window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The implications of this drop in ESR in the coming weeks and months are significant.</p>
<p>If levels continue to remain low or drop even further while Bitcoin&#8217;s price climbs higher, it will mean that the market is heavily capitalized with dry powder. Under such a scenario, we can expect further stable upward movement.</p>
<p>However, we could also see a much more aggressive deployment of stablecoins into BTC. While this would benefit the market in the short term by driving the price higher, it could also leave exchanges with diminished stablecoin reserves — leading to higher volatility in the future.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/exchange-stablecoin-ratio-hits-record-low-fueling-bitcoin-surge/">Exchange stablecoin ratio hits record low, fueling Bitcoin surge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/exchange-stablecoin-ratio-hits-record-low-fueling-bitcoin-surge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/stablecoin-exchange-ratio.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/stablecoin-exchange-ratio.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US elections boosted Bitcoin&#8217;s liquidity to new highs</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/us-elections-boosted-bitcoins-liquidity-to-new-highs/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/us-elections-boosted-bitcoins-liquidity-to-new-highs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 17:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bid ask spread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market depth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s aggregated 2% market depth, a measure of liquidity that combines buy and sell orders within a narrow 2% price range around the market price, has surged to a one-year high of $623.40 million as of Nov. 16. This represents a significant increase from $422 million on Nov.5 — a significant increase in liquidity over [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-elections-boosted-bitcoins-liquidity-to-new-highs/">US elections boosted Bitcoin&#8217;s liquidity to new highs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> aggregated 2% market depth, a measure of liquidity that combines buy and sell orders within a narrow 2% price range around the market price, has surged to a one-year high of $623.40 million as of Nov. 16. This represents a significant increase from $422 million on Nov.5 — a significant increase in liquidity over a short period.</p>
<p class="p1">It suggests growing market confidence, as deeper liquidity typically indicates that traders and institutions are more willing to participate in the market, providing a buffer against price volatility.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453477" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453477" style="width: 1349px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453477" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Aggregated-2-Market-Depth.jpg" alt="Aggregated 2% Market Depth Bitcoin" width="1349" height="821" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Aggregated-2-Market-Depth.jpg 1349w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Aggregated-2-Market-Depth-300x183.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Aggregated-2-Market-Depth-1024x623.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Aggregated-2-Market-Depth-768x467.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1349px) 100vw, 1349px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453477" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the aggregated 2% market depth for Bitcoin from Nov. 20, 2023, to Nov. 18, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dataplus.kaiko.com/asset/liquidity">Kaiko</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">This increase in market depth leading up to and following the US presidential election is not an isolated event but part of a broader shift in macroeconomic and political conditions. Donald Trump&#8217;s election and his administration&#8217;s announced intention to support Bitcoin and the crypto industry through concrete policies have catalyzed increased market activity.</p>
<p class="p1">This newfound political alignment with the crypto space likely signaled to institutional and retail investors that the regulatory environment could become significantly more favorable, reducing perceived risks and encouraging greater participation.</p>
<p class="p1">The market responded enthusiastically to the prospect of a pro-crypto administration, with traders likely interpreting the news as a green light for broader adoption and institutional inflows. This price surge, combined with the increase in aggregated market depth, suggests that market participants were trading in response to the election results and positioning for a sustained bullish trend. The expanded market depth reflects this increased engagement, as deeper liquidity allows larger orders to be executed with minimal slippage—critical in a market experiencing rapid upward price movements.</p>
<p class="p1">The election&#8217;s impact can also be observed in the bid versus ask depth. While the imbalance favoring sell orders at $341.81 million over $281.59 million in buy orders suggests some profit-taking, it is important to note that this activity did not trigger a significant price correction. Instead, the market absorbed sell-side pressure efficiently, indicating robust buyer demand even as Bitcoin crossed $93,000.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453478" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453478" style="width: 1349px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453478" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/2-Bid-vs.-Ask-Depth.jpg" alt="2% Bid vs. Ask Depth bitcoin" width="1349" height="821" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/2-Bid-vs.-Ask-Depth.jpg 1349w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/2-Bid-vs.-Ask-Depth-300x183.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/2-Bid-vs.-Ask-Depth-1024x623.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/2-Bid-vs.-Ask-Depth-768x467.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1349px) 100vw, 1349px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453478" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the values of buy and sell orders within a 2% price range of Bitcoin&#8217;s market price from Oct. 19 to Nov. 18, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dataplus.kaiko.com/asset/liquidity">Kaiko</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">The US market&#8217;s historically dominant share of global market depth appears to have played a significant role in driving this liquidity surge. Although US market share dipped slightly post-election, the broader trend throughout 2024—where the US accounted for over 50% of global depth—suggests that American institutions and traders have been pivotal in shaping market activity.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453479" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453479" style="width: 1349px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453479" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/U.S.-vs.-Global-Market-Share-of-2-Depth.jpg" alt="U.S. vs. Global Market Share of 2% Depth bitcoin" width="1349" height="821" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/U.S.-vs.-Global-Market-Share-of-2-Depth.jpg 1349w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/U.S.-vs.-Global-Market-Share-of-2-Depth-300x183.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/U.S.-vs.-Global-Market-Share-of-2-Depth-1024x623.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/U.S.-vs.-Global-Market-Share-of-2-Depth-768x467.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1349px) 100vw, 1349px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453479" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the proportion of market depth attributed to the US market compared to offshore markets from Aug. 20 to Nov. 18, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dataplus.kaiko.com/asset/liquidity">Kaiko</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p class="p1">On an exchange-specific level, the rise of Bitfinex as the leader in global market depth may reflect its ability to attract liquidity amid these political and market shifts. The exchange&#8217;s 27% share on Nov. 16 coincides with Bitcoin&#8217;s post-election rally, suggesting that Bitfinex successfully captured a significant portion of the increased trading activity.</p>
<p class="p1">In contrast, Binance&#8217;s declining share, hovering between 10% and 15% in November, could be attributed to ongoing regulatory scrutiny, which may have deterred institutional players from utilizing its platform despite the broader market optimism.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453480" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453480" style="width: 1349px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453480" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Market-Share-of-2-Depth.jpg" alt="bitcoin Market Share of 2% Depth" width="1349" height="821" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Market-Share-of-2-Depth.jpg 1349w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Market-Share-of-2-Depth-300x183.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Market-Share-of-2-Depth-1024x623.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Market-Share-of-2-Depth-768x467.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1349px) 100vw, 1349px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453480" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing the market share of aggregated 2% market depth held by a specific exchange from Oct. 19 to Nov. 18, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://dataplus.kaiko.com/asset/liquidity">Kaiko</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-elections-boosted-bitcoins-liquidity-to-new-highs/">US elections boosted Bitcoin&#8217;s liquidity to new highs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/us-elections-boosted-bitcoins-liquidity-to-new-highs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/us-global-btc-trade.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/us-global-btc-trade.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin futures break records with 29% OI surge in November</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-futures-break-records-with-29-percent-open-interest-surge-in-november/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-futures-break-records-with-29-percent-open-interest-surge-in-november/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 03:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[derivatives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[futures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[futures open interest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[futures volume]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s futures open interest grew from $34.68 billion on Oct. 1 to an all-time high (ATH) of $54.85 billion on Nov.14. This increase of over 58% since the start of October and 29% since the beginning of November shows a significant influx of capital and increased trader participation, with much of this growth accelerating after [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-futures-break-records-with-29-percent-open-interest-surge-in-november/">Bitcoin futures break records with 29% OI surge in November</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> futures open interest grew from $34.68 billion on Oct. 1 to an all-time high (ATH) of $54.85 billion on Nov.14.</p>
<p>This increase of over 58% since the start of October and 29% since the beginning of November shows a significant influx of capital and increased trader participation, with much of this growth accelerating after the US election.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453279" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453279" style="width: 1078px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453279" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.26.55.png" alt="btc futures open interest" width="1078" height="375" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.26.55.png 1078w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.26.55-300x104.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.26.55-1024x356.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.26.55-768x267.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1078px) 100vw, 1078px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453279" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin futures open interest from Oct. 1 to Nov. 15, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/BitcoinOpenInterest">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Futures also saw a dramatic increase in trading volume, with daily volume peaking at just over $207 billion on Nov. 13, marking the fourth-largest trading volume ever recorded. The surge in open interest and volume shows a significant increase in speculation and leveraged trading, an inevitable side-effect of a bull rally.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453278" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453278" style="width: 795px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453278" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.25.45.png" alt="bitcoin futures trading volume " width="795" height="372" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.25.45.png 795w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.25.45-300x140.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.25.45-768x359.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 795px) 100vw, 795px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453278" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin futures trading volume from Oct. 1 to Nov. 15, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/pro/futures/Cryptofutures">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>While Bitcoin&#8217;s derivatives are growing steadily, with both old and new exchanges becoming prominent players in the space, half of the market is still dominated by two platforms — CME and Binance. This is why the changes in their market share and growth trajectories often reveal nuances in market sentiment that aren&#8217;t that obvious when looking at the big picture.</p>
<p>In the past 40 days, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-froze-4-2-million-of-xrp-stolen-in-attack-on-ripple-co-founder/">Binance</a> accounted for a substantial portion of the total futures market, with its open interest increasing steadily from $7.47 billion on Oct.1 to a record $10.61 billion on Nov.15.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453280" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453280" style="width: 1078px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453280" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.27.44.png" alt="binance btc futures open interest" width="1078" height="375" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.27.44.png 1078w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.27.44-300x104.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.27.44-1024x356.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.27.44-768x267.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1078px) 100vw, 1078px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453280" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin futures open interest on Binance from Oct. 1 to Nov. 15, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/BitcoinOpenInterest">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/shift-to-contango-bitcoin-futures-premiums-rise-on-cme/">CME</a> exhibited even more aggressive growth, with its open interest rising from $9.93 billion to a peak of $17.94 billion within the same period.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453282" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453282" style="width: 789px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-453282 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.30.49.png" alt="cme btc futures OI" width="789" height="375" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.30.49.png 789w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.30.49-300x143.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-15-at-15.30.49-768x365.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 789px) 100vw, 789px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453282" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin futures open interest on CME from Oct. 1 to Nov. 15, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/pro/futures/OpenInterest">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/understanding-the-differences-in-bitcoin-futures-on-binance-and-cme/">difference between CME and Binance&#8217;s market share</a> shows what the market prefers.</p>
<p>Binance, catering to retail and speculative traders, benefits from its global accessibility, lower fees, and broader altcoin derivative offerings.  In contrast, CME attracts a more risk-averse, regulation-focused cohort, with institutional investors favoring the exchange&#8217;s credibility.</p>
<p>The rise in CME&#8217;s open interest to nearly a third of the total market by Nov. 14 points to institutional capital fueling much of the rally. This institutional participation is a strong bullish signal, as it suggests confidence in Bitcoin&#8217;s medium- to long-term prospects rather than the speculative fervor often associated with retail.</p>
<p>The impact of the US election is evident in the data. Following Trump&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-hits-new-all-time-high-as-trumps-polymarket-odds-hit-97/">win</a> on Nov. 5, Bitcoin&#8217;s price soared from $67,830 to a high of $93,500 by Nov. 12. Futures mirrored this enthusiasm as the $10 billion increase in open interest from Nov. 7 to Nov. 14 is a result of a surge in leveraged positions as traders rushed to capitalize on the bullish sentiment.</p>
<p>However, the drop in trading volume from $207.04 billion on Nov. 13 to $133.02 billion on Nov. 15 suggests some profit-taking and reduced momentum toward the end of this period, potentially hinting at traders consolidating gains.</p>
<p>Several additional observations can be made from this data. First, the sustained growth in Binance&#8217;s open interest indicates robust retail participation despite increased institutional presence in the market.</p>
<p>Second, the correlation between Bitcoin&#8217;s price rise and the dramatic increase in futures volume suggests that the spot market&#8217;s bullish momentum was amplified by speculative derivatives trading.</p>
<p>Lastly, the market&#8217;s preference for CME reflects growing institutional confidence in Bitcoin as a legitimate asset class, a crucial factor for long-term adoption.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-futures-break-records-with-29-percent-open-interest-surge-in-november/">Bitcoin futures break records with 29% OI surge in November</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-futures-break-records-with-29-percent-open-interest-surge-in-november/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/analyzing-derivatives.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/analyzing-derivatives.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Divergence between Bitcoin&#8217;s market and realized caps signals euphoria</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/divergence-between-bitcoins-market-and-realized-caps-signals-euphoria/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/divergence-between-bitcoins-market-and-realized-caps-signals-euphoria/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Andjela Radmilac]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Alpha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market cap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[realized cap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The difference between Bitcoin&#8217;s realized cap and market cap is an underrated indicator of the phases of Bitcoin&#8217;s price cycles. The realized cap shows Bitcoin&#8217;s value based on the last price each coin moved, showing the actual capital invested into the asset. When the market cap, which reflects the value of all existing coins based [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/divergence-between-bitcoins-market-and-realized-caps-signals-euphoria/">Divergence between Bitcoin&#8217;s market and realized caps signals euphoria</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The difference between Bitcoin&#8217;s realized cap and market cap is an underrated indicator of the phases of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> price cycles. The realized cap shows Bitcoin&#8217;s value based on the last price each coin moved, showing the actual capital invested into the asset.</p>
<p>When the market cap, which reflects the value of all existing coins based on the current spot price, significantly diverges from the realized cap, it shows a shift in sentiment. These shifts have historically aligned with phases of either euphoria or fear.</p>
<p>A high market cap relative to the realized cap shows that investors hold unrealized gains. While this is an unambiguous sign of a bullish sentiment in the market, it can also precede potential overextension. Conversely, when the market cap dips below the realized cap, it signals widespread capitulation and undervaluation of the asset.</p>
<p>The current discrepancy between Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap and realized cap reflects the overwhelming bullish sentiment that has dominated the market this month.</p>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s price increase was driven by optimism surrounding the US presidential election. On Nov. 5, President Donald Trump&#8217;s win sparked a rally in the crypto market, as his upcoming administration is expected to introduce <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-bitcoin-reserve-asset-bill-could-pass-in-donald-trumps-first-100-days-senator-cynthia-lummis/">concrete</a>, Bitcoin-focused policies.</p>
<p>The outcome of the election created a bullish momentum, with investors gearing up for a much <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/no-capital-tax-on-us-crypto-bitcoin-reserve-asset-nation-state-adoption-the-biggest-trump-rumors/">more favorable regulatory environment</a> for crypto. This sentiment drove Bitcoin&#8217;s price to over $90,000, establishing a new ATH.</p>
<p>The price spike was mirrored in Bitcoin&#8217;s market cap, which increased from $1.132 trillion at the start of September to $1.789 trillion by mid-November. Most of this increase occurred in the days following the election, indicating heightened buying activity and a rush of capital into the market.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453048" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453048" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453048" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap.png" alt="Bitcoin Market Cap" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Market-Cap-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453048" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s market capitalization from Sep. 1 to Nov. 13, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/market-data/market-cap?window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>While the surge definitely reflects the market&#8217;s enthusiasm and confidence in Bitcoin&#8217;s long-term potential under the Trump administration, the price itself also likely fueled speculative buying. Such rapid growth in market cap, particularly after a major event like a national election, is often a sign of heightened speculation.</p>
<p>While the market cap grew significantly, Bitcoin&#8217;s realized cap grew much slower. Moving from $621.691 billion on Sep. 1 to $679.281 billion on Nov.13, the realized cap&#8217;s rise clearly shows that new capital continues to enter the market.</p>
<p>This upward trend in realized cap shows that Bitcoin is being bought and sold at progressively higher valuations, gradually setting new cost basis levels. The election also seems to have accelerated this growth in the realized cap, with a notable increase from $656.006 billion on Nov.5 to $679.281 billion by Nov. 13.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453050" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453050" style="width: 4000px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453050" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap.png" alt="Bitcoin Realized Cap" width="4000" height="2250" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap.png 4000w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap-300x169.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap-1024x576.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap-768x432.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap-1536x864.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Bitcoin-Realized-Cap-2048x1152.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 4000px) 100vw, 4000px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453050" class="wp-caption-text">Graph showing Bitcoin&#8217;s realized capitalization from Sep. 1 to Nov. 13, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/asset/btc/chart/market-data/realized-cap?window=DAY&amp;sma=0&amp;ema=0&amp;priceScale=log&amp;metricScale=linear&amp;chartStyle=line">CryptoQuant</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>The widening difference between the market and realized cap during this period is particularly telling. In September, the gap between the two stood around $510 billion; by mid-November, it had expanded to approximately $1.1 trillion.</p>
<p>The divergence suggests that Bitcoin&#8217;s current market price is significantly higher than the average price paid by holders, indicating that many investors are now holding substantial unrealized profits. Historically, such a large gap has been associated with market cycles nearing a euphoric phase, where optimism and speculation drive prices well beyond previous levels.</p>
<p>While the realized cap growth signals a steady inflow of capital and continued interest in Bitcoin, the rapid expansion of the market cap relative to the realized cap could indicate an overextended market where the valuation may be somewhat inflated by speculative buying.</p>
<p>This danger is also evident when looking at the crypto fear and greed index, which has dipped well into the extreme greed territory, remaining tied to greed for 28 out of the past 30 days, according to CoinGlass data.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453053" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453053" style="width: 1352px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453053" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-14-at-15.57.19.png" alt="bitcoin fear and greed index" width="1352" height="305" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-14-at-15.57.19.png 1352w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-14-at-15.57.19-300x68.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-14-at-15.57.19-1024x231.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-14-at-15.57.19-768x173.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1352px) 100vw, 1352px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453053" class="wp-caption-text">Screengrab showing the crypto fear and greed index on Nov. 14, 2024 (Source: <a href="https://www.coinglass.com/pro/i/FearGreedIndex">CoinGlass</a>)</figcaption></figure>
<p>This pattern of divergence often precedes periods of consolidation or correction. Bitcoin&#8217;s stint at <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-breaks-yet-another-all-time-high-now-testing-92000/">above $92,000</a> was relatively short-lived and was immediately followed by a correction to around $87,500 on Nov. 13.</p>
<p>The price has since rubberbanded between roughly $87,000 and $91,500 as of press time. Short, aggressive corrections like these can be expected in the coming weeks as the divergence between the market cap and realized cap persists.</p>
<p>If realized cap growth slows or reverses in the coming weeks, it could indicate that long-term holders are beginning to distribute their holdings in response to persistently high prices. This could put additional pressure on price growth, and we could see another, more extended correction below $90,000.</p>
<p>However, the steady increase in the realized cap so far shows that long-term holders remain confident, adding strength to this rally even as the market cap increases.</p>
<p>It will be important to monitor changes in the positions of large institutional holders, with a particular focus on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/blackrock-etf-brings-in-over-3-billion-in-5-days-after-new-230-million-inflow/">ETFs</a> and derivatives. The size of these positions will likely propel movement from retail investors and change sentiment in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/divergence-between-bitcoins-market-and-realized-caps-signals-euphoria/">Divergence between Bitcoin&#8217;s market and realized caps signals euphoria</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/divergence-between-bitcoins-market-and-realized-caps-signals-euphoria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-market-cap.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-market-cap.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
