<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Crypto Lending News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/lending-borrowing/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/lending-borrowing/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:14:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Crypto Lending News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/lending-borrowing/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Ledn&#8217;s retail loans surge 225% amid rising digital asset demand</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ledns-retail-loans-surge-225-amid-rising-digital-asset-demand/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ledns-retail-loans-surge-225-amid-rising-digital-asset-demand/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 16:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ledn]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crypto lender Ledn said it processed $506 million in loan transactions during the third quarter, according to an Oct. 21 statement shared with CryptoSlate. According to the firm, $437.7 million in loans were issued to institutional clients, while loans to retail clients climbed 225% year-over-year to $68.9 million. This surge in retail loans is credited [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ledns-retail-loans-surge-225-amid-rising-digital-asset-demand/">Ledn&#8217;s retail loans surge 225% amid rising digital asset demand</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crypto lender <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ledn/">Ledn</a> said it processed $506 million in loan transactions during the third quarter, according to an Oct. 21 statement shared with <em>CryptoSlate</em>.</p>
<p>According to the firm, $437.7 million in loans were issued to institutional clients, while loans to retail clients climbed 225% year-over-year to $68.9 million. This surge in retail loans is credited to the Celsius refinancing program, the launch of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-etfs-see-over-500-million-inflows-in-past-2-days/">crypto ETFs</a>, and a period of reduced market volatility.</p>
<p>Ledn has processed $1.67 billion in loans year-to-date, comprising $258.7 million for retail users and $1.41 billion for institutions.</p>
<p>Since its founding in 2018, Ledn has facilitated over $6.5 billion in loans across both retail and institutional markets.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">What is driving demand?</span></p>
<p>Ledn attributed the rising demand for its services to the growing need for digital asset-backed lending as more significant players explore alternative financing options. This increase is influenced by tighter monetary policies and fierce competition for dollar-based funding.</p>
<p>Ledn also noted that the third quarter&#8217;s growth followed strong momentum in the second quarter, which saw increased demand driven by notable market events. These included <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-cuts-production-sinks-revenues-for-top-miners/">April&#8217;s Bitcoin halving</a>, which cut mining rewards from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC, and the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kongs-bitcoin-and-ethereum-etfs-launch-with-lower-than-expected-trading-volumes/">introduction of Ethereum ETFs in Asia</a>.</p>
<p>The company further emphasized that macroeconomic conditions such as rising inflation, economic uncertainty, and the need for portfolio diversification contributed to the surge in demand.</p>
<p>Ledn CIO John Glover highlighted that institutional demand spiked in July. Notably, this was around when the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) approved <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-etfs-face-rocky-start-but-hold-growth-promise-bitwise-ceo-says/">Ethereum ETFs</a> for trading in the US.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Glover pointed out that the market is still searching for the next catalyst to push <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> price to a new all-time high. He suggested that the upcoming US elections could potentially be that trigger.</p>
<p>He stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It seems like a lot of hope is being placed on the November elections to be this catalyst. Institutional borrowing demand has also been fairly consistent with the overall ETF demand, where there was a similar jump in July.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ledns-retail-loans-surge-225-amid-rising-digital-asset-demand/">Ledn&#8217;s retail loans surge 225% amid rising digital asset demand</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ledns-retail-loans-surge-225-amid-rising-digital-asset-demand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/ledn.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/ledn.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liquidium&#8217;s $2.75M seed round aims to bring Aave-like experience to Bitcoin</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/liquidiums-2-75m-seed-round-aims-to-bring-aave-like-experience-to-bitcoin/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/liquidiums-2-75m-seed-round-aims-to-bring-aave-like-experience-to-bitcoin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 12:01:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aave]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liquidium]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=433938</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Liquidium, a lending platform, has raised $2.75 million in a seed round to establish itself as a leading DeFi hub in the Bitcoin ecosystem. Investors in the round include Wise 3 Ventures, Portal Ventures, Asymmetric Capital, AGE Fund, NGC Ventures, CMS Holdings, Newman Capital, VidenVC, and DeGods. The round also included angel investors like Dingaling, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/liquidiums-2-75m-seed-round-aims-to-bring-aave-like-experience-to-bitcoin/">Liquidium&#8217;s $2.75M seed round aims to bring Aave-like experience to Bitcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Liquidium, a lending platform, has raised $2.75 million in a seed round to establish itself as a leading DeFi hub in the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> ecosystem.</p>
<p>Investors in the round include Wise 3 Ventures, Portal Ventures, Asymmetric Capital, AGE Fund, NGC Ventures, CMS Holdings, Newman Capital, VidenVC, and DeGods. The round also included angel investors like Dingaling, Frank DeGods, Beanie, Cirrus, ThreadGuy, FAR (Co-Founder of Taproot Wizards), Anthony Newman, Dr. Jingle, NFTboi, <em>CryptoSlate</em> CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/nate-whitehill/">Nate Whitehill</a> and Kraken&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/dan-held/">Dan Held</a>.</p>
<h2>Aave-like experience</h2>
<p>Robin Obermaier, Liquidium&#8217;s CEO, said the funding would help the platform achieve his vision of providing an Aave-like experience on Bitcoin. He stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I envision Liquidium to be the DeFi lending hub on Bitcoin with fully fledged liquidity pools to offer experiences like Aave, but on native Bitcoin.</p>
<p>This funding round brings us closer to realizing a platform where users can seamlessly supply liquidity to earn passive income or borrow assets in a secure, overcollateralized manner. We have the team, the investors, and the guts to execute on that vision.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>According to DeFillama data, AAVE is the largest Ethereum lending protocol, with over $13 billion worth of assets under its management.</p>
<p>So, the seed funding aims to support Liquidium&#8217;s growth as a top Bitcoin lending protocol. This aligns with the recent launch of its Rune borrowing and lending services, showcasing its commitment to continuous improvement and industry leadership.</p>
<p>Liquidium has already established itself as the premier DeFi platform for peer-to-peer Bitcoin lending. It enables users to borrow or lend Bitcoin using Bitcoin-based assets like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/ordinals/">Ordinals</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-runes-made-up-57-percent-of-transactions-on-halving-day/">Runes</a> as collateral. The process utilizes Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (PSBTs) and Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) on the Layer 1 Bitcoin network.</p>
<p>Notably, the protocol has integrated compatibility with Unisat and Leather wallets and plans to incorporate BRC-20 assets and additional wallets like OKX and Phantom in the future. According to the firm, these moves will further enhance accessibility and expand the Bitcoin ecosystem to new markets.</p>
<p><i data-stringify-type="italic">Disclosure: CryptoSlate CEO Nate Whitehill is an angel investor in Liquidium.</i></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/liquidiums-2-75m-seed-round-aims-to-bring-aave-like-experience-to-bitcoin/">Liquidium&#8217;s $2.75M seed round aims to bring Aave-like experience to Bitcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/liquidiums-2-75m-seed-round-aims-to-bring-aave-like-experience-to-bitcoin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/bitcoin-defi.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/bitcoin-defi.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NYAG completes settlement with Gemini over Earn program, recovers remaining $50 million for impacted users</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/nyag-completes-settlement-with-gemini-over-earn-program-recovers-remaining-50-million-for-impacted-users/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/nyag-completes-settlement-with-gemini-over-earn-program-recovers-remaining-50-million-for-impacted-users/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 20:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=426110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The New York Attorney General&#8217;s (NYAG) office announced the completion of its settlement with Gemini and the recovery of $50 million for users of the defunct Gemini Earn program on June 14. Users will receive the crypto in their accounts without having to take any further action. The settlement resolves the legal charges filed by [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nyag-completes-settlement-with-gemini-over-earn-program-recovers-remaining-50-million-for-impacted-users/">NYAG completes settlement with Gemini over Earn program, recovers remaining $50 million for impacted users</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York Attorney General&#8217;s (NYAG) office announced the completion of its settlement with Gemini and the recovery of $50 million for users of the defunct Gemini Earn program on June 14.</p>
<p>Users will receive the crypto in their accounts without having to take any further action.</p>
<p>The settlement resolves the legal charges filed by the NYAG against Gemini and bars the exchange from operating crypto lending programs in New York.</p>
<p>It also requires Gemini to cooperate in the NYAG&#8217;s investigations of Genesis parent <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/digital-currency-group/">Digital Currency Group</a> (DCG), DCG CEO Barry Silbert, and former Genesis CEO Soichiro Moro.</p>
<p>The NYAG said Gemini &#8220;allegedly misled thousands of investors on the risks&#8221; by offering the Gemini Earn program with <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/genesis/">Genesis Global Capital</a>. Gemini Earn&#8217;s failure reportedly impacted over 230,000 users, including at least 29,000 residents of New York.</p>
<p>New York Attorney General <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/letitia-james/">Letitia James</a> said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Gemini marketed its Earn program as a way for investors to grow their money, but actually lied and locked investors out of their accounts.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Final distribution within a week</h2>
<p>Gemini confirmed the settlement the same day and said it would make the <a href="https://www.gemini.com/earn">final distribution of funds</a> available to users within seven days. The action will return the final 3% of crypto the exchange owed users when the Earn program was suspended.</p>
<p>The company confirmed the conclusion of the NYAG&#8217;s lawsuit, stating:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We are also pleased to announce that &#8230; Gemini has entered into an agreement with the New York Attorney General (NYAG) to settle the lawsuit the NYAG brought against Gemini on October 19, 2023.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Gemini returned more than $2 billion in crypto to customer accounts on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gemini-earn-returns-over-2-billion-in-crypto-triggering-concerns-of-sell-pressure/">May 29</a>, completing the return of 97% of the funds it owed to customers. It made the distributions in-kind, meaning that users who lent one <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> to the program received one Bitcoin back.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nyag-completes-settlement-with-gemini-over-earn-program-recovers-remaining-50-million-for-impacted-users/">NYAG completes settlement with Gemini over Earn program, recovers remaining $50 million for impacted users</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/nyag-completes-settlement-with-gemini-over-earn-program-recovers-remaining-50-million-for-impacted-users/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/letitia-james.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/letitia-james.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOJ charges three Cred execs over $783 million in customer fund losses</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/doj-charges-three-cred-execs-over-783-million-in-customer-fund-losses/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/doj-charges-three-cred-execs-over-783-million-in-customer-fund-losses/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 01:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=416943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>On May 3, the US DOJ announced charges against former executives of Cred, a bankrupt crypto lending and investing firm. Authorities alleged that the three accused individuals — Cred co-owner and former CEO Daniel Schatt, former CFO Joseph Podulka, and former CCO James Alexander — took part in a scheme that caused customers to lose [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/doj-charges-three-cred-execs-over-783-million-in-customer-fund-losses/">DOJ charges three Cred execs over $783 million in customer fund losses</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On <a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-ndca/pr/former-ceo-cfo-and-cco-cred-llc-charged-alleged-multi-million-dollar-cryptocurrency">May 3</a>, the US DOJ announced charges against former executives of Cred, a bankrupt crypto lending and investing firm.</p>
<p>Authorities alleged that the three accused individuals — Cred co-owner and former CEO Daniel Schatt, former CFO Joseph Podulka, and former CCO James Alexander — took part in a scheme that caused customers to lose crypto holdings now worth more than $783 million.</p>
<p>IRS Criminal Investigation Acting Special Agent in Charge Mark Mosley called the defendants&#8217; suspected activities at Cred a &#8220;predatory, deceptive scheme.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Allegedly false statements</h2>
<p>Cred offered loans in US dollars to customers who deposited crypto as collateral. It secondarily promised yield or interest to customers who deposited their crypto.</p>
<p>However, no later than March 2020, the former executives allegedly made numerous false statements, claiming that Cred only engaged in collateralized and guaranteed lending, utilized hedged crypto investments, and had all-weather protection against volatility.</p>
<p>Marketing materials allegedly falsely advertised Cred was a licensed lender with comprehensive insurance. Furthermore, executives allegedly portrayed Cred as solvent after a 2020 flash crash and promised that insurance would make customers whole.</p>
<p>Even as Cred&#8217;s General Counsel admitted potential insolvency, executives allegedly sought new customer funds instead of revealing details of the firm&#8217;s financial situation.</p>
<p>The executives also allegedly failed to disclose that customer yields were almost entirely produced by a single company that made micro-loans to Chinese gamers.</p>
<h2>Long maximum sentence</h2>
<p>A federal grand jury charged each of the three individuals with varying counts of conspiracy, wire fraud, and money laundering. The various charges combined carry maximum sentences amounting to decades in prison plus millions of dollars in fines.</p>
<p>Schatt and Podulka made their first court appearance on May 2 and will return on May 8, including to enter a plea. Alexander&#8217;s first court appearance is pending.</p>
<p>The case is proceeding in the Northern District of California, which also announced a guilty plea from BTC-e operator Alexander Vinnik on the same day.</p>
<p>The DOJ has recently announced two other cases: one against Bitcoin proponent <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/roger-ver-arrested-in-spain-after-doj-files-tax-fraud-charges-in-the-us/">Roger Ver</a> for alleged tax evasion in the Central District of California and one against the founders of the privacy-enabled crypto wallet <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/samourai-wallet-execs-arrested-over-money-laundering-charges-in-2-billion-doj-case-website-seized/">Samourai Wallet</a> in the Southern District of New York.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/doj-charges-three-cred-execs-over-783-million-in-customer-fund-losses/">DOJ charges three Cred execs over $783 million in customer fund losses</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/doj-charges-three-cred-execs-over-783-million-in-customer-fund-losses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/doj-justice.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/doj-justice.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starknet-based zkLend announces ZEND token, reveals ambitious 2024 roadmap</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-based-zklend-announces-zend-token-reveals-ambitious-2024-roadmap/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-based-zklend-announces-zend-token-reveals-ambitious-2024-roadmap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 15:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StarkNet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zklend]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=395160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>zkLend, a money market protocol built on the Ethereum layer2 network Starknet, is preparing to launch its native ZEND token this year to enhance its platform&#8217;s utility. In a Feb. 7 statement shared with CryptoSlate, the platform explained that the token would be airdropped at an undisclosed time to the platform&#8217;s users, who are currently [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-based-zklend-announces-zend-token-reveals-ambitious-2024-roadmap/">Starknet-based zkLend announces ZEND token, reveals ambitious 2024 roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>zkLend, a money market protocol built on the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/glossary/layer-2/">layer2</a> network Starknet, is preparing to launch its native ZEND token this year to enhance its platform&#8217;s utility.</p>
<p>In a Feb. 7 statement shared with <em>CryptoSlate</em>, the platform explained that the token would be airdropped at an undisclosed time to the platform&#8217;s users, who are currently contributing to the platform&#8217;s growth and adoption.</p>
<p>Notably, the project has not disclosed the eligibility criteria or taken a snapshot for the airdrop yet.</p>
<h2>Ambitious roadmap</h2>
<p>The token launch aligns with ZKLend&#8217;s ambitious 2024 roadmap, including critical features like isolated markets, a transaction builder interface, vault strategies, and an upgraded V2 protocol version.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<span class="s5">These features will unlock more ways for users to compose, modularise, and leverage their assets with seamless UX to offer a product that is not only innovative and creative but also enjoyable to use,&#8221; the statement added.</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Brian Fu, ZKLend&#8217;s co-founder, expressed enthusiasm about ZKLend&#8217;s roadmap, saying it was designed &#8220;to capture and provide the most value for our users as the ecosystem grows.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Having established ourselves as the native money market on Starknet, we look forward to supporting the continuous development of Starknet, including and beyond the scope of zkLend’s operations,&#8221; Fu added.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="https://defillama.com/protocol/zklend?usdInflows=true">Data</a> from DeFillama shows that ZKLend is among the top five decentralized finance (DeFi) projects on the Starknet. Per the dashboard, the total value of assets locked on the protocol stands at $6.25 million, and it is also one of the most <a href="https://starkscan.co/top-contracts">active contrac</a>ts on the Starknet blockchain, boasting over 8 million transactions as of press time.</p>
<p>Beyond its technical achievements, ZKLend&#8217;s team actively contributes to the Starknet ecosystem. Co-founders Jonathan Lei and Jane Ma play important roles in different committees for the layer2 network, including being core contributors to open-source projects.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-foundation-confirms-strk-token-airdrop-but-denies-authenticity-of-circulating-screenshots/">Starknet</a> is an Ethereum Layer 2 scaling solution developed by StarkWare. The network uses the ZK-Rollup technology to significantly enhance Ethereum&#8217;s transaction throughput by up to tenfold while substantially reducing transaction fees.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: The CryptoSlate founders are invested in zkLend.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-based-zklend-announces-zend-token-reveals-ambitious-2024-roadmap/">Starknet-based zkLend announces ZEND token, reveals ambitious 2024 roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-based-zklend-announces-zend-token-reveals-ambitious-2024-roadmap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/zklend.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/zklend.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nexo demands $3 billion in damages over canceled Bulgarian investigation</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/nexo-demands-3-billion-in-damages-over-cancelled-bulgarian-investigation/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/nexo-demands-3-billion-in-damages-over-cancelled-bulgarian-investigation/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 20:27:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=391712</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nexo, a crypto lending firm, said on Jan. 24 that it aims to obtain $3 billion in damages from Bulgaria over a cancelled criminal investigation. The company said in a statement: &#8220;[Nexo has] filed an over $3 billion ICSID arbitration claim against the Republic of Bulgaria for damages and lost opportunities caused by the country’s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nexo-demands-3-billion-in-damages-over-cancelled-bulgarian-investigation/">Nexo demands $3 billion in damages over canceled Bulgarian investigation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/nexo/">Nexo</a>, a crypto lending firm, said on <a href="https://nexo.com/media-center/nexo-sues-bulgaria-for-over-3-billion">Jan. 24</a> that it aims to obtain $3 billion in damages from Bulgaria over a cancelled criminal investigation.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;[Nexo has] filed an over $3 billion ICSID arbitration claim against the Republic of Bulgaria for damages and lost opportunities caused by the country’s wrongful and politically motivated actions &#8230; involving unjustified and oppressive criminal investigations, subsequently dismissed for lack of merit.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Bulgarian prosecutors initially launched an investigation into Nexo AG over one year ago in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nexo-offices-raided-on-allegations-of-financial-crimes/">January 2023</a>. At that time, authorities raided the firm&#8217;s offices and charged four Bulgarian individuals with money laundering, tax fraud, and computer fraud. Authorities also alleged violations of Russian sanctions.</p>
<p>In its current <a href="https://nexo.com/media-center/nexo-sues-bulgaria-for-over-3-billion">press release</a>, Nexo said that the company and its management were cleared of all wrongdoing on Dec. 21, 2023. Nevertheless, it said that the charges damaged its brand and reputation, harmed its investments in Bulgaria, and resulted in the loss of several planned business opportunities.</p>
<p>The company has filed an arbitration claim with the World Bank&#8217;s International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes (ICSID). Records from ICSID <a href="https://icsid.worldbank.org/cases/case-database/case-detail?CaseNo=ARB/24/2">indicate that</a> Nexo filed the claim on Jan. 18 but provide few other details.</p>
<p>According to separate reports from <a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/crypto-lender-nexo-seeks-3-bln-damages-bulgaria-over-aborted-investigation-2024-01-24/">Reuters</a>, Bulgaria&#8217;s finance ministry confirmed that it has received the arbitration request from ICSID and said that the request will next be reviewed by an inter-department committee. However, Bulgaria&#8217;s finance ministry stated that its acknowledgement of the request does not mean it admits to Nexo&#8217;s claims or has accepted any arbitration jurisdiction.</p>
<h2>Nexo&#8217;s growth has been impacted</h2>
<p>Nexo&#8217;s co-founder, Antoni Trenchev, affirmed that the company can continue operations but said that the firm will experience reduced growth.</p>
<p>Nexo noted that it had been working with three major U.S. investment banks on a funding round and IPO that could have created a valuation of up to $12 billion. It said this effort was impacted by charges and had to be abandoned.</p>
<p>Nexo also said that the charges arrived days before it planned to sign a multi-year partnership with a European football club, including a club-branded payment card. Though Nexo did not identify the club involved in the partnership, a potential partnership between Nexo and FC Barcelona was reported in October 2022, months before the investigation began.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nexo-demands-3-billion-in-damages-over-cancelled-bulgarian-investigation/">Nexo demands $3 billion in damages over canceled Bulgarian investigation</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/nexo-demands-3-billion-in-damages-over-cancelled-bulgarian-investigation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/nexo-2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/nexo-2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liquidium secures $1.25M pre-seed funding for Bitcoin Ordinal lending</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/liquidium-secures-1-25m-pre-seed-funding-for-bitcoin-ordinal-lending/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/liquidium-secures-1-25m-pre-seed-funding-for-bitcoin-ordinal-lending/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[News Desk]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFTs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ordinals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=380729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a significant leap for Bitcoin&#8217;s lending sector, Liquidium, a burgeoning startup, has successfully raised $1.25 million in a pre-seed funding round. This capital injection marks a pivotal moment for the company as it sets its sights on pioneering a novel lending framework utilizing Bitcoin&#8217;s ordinal technology. The successful funding round was bolstered by the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/liquidium-secures-1-25m-pre-seed-funding-for-bitcoin-ordinal-lending/">Liquidium secures $1.25M pre-seed funding for Bitcoin Ordinal lending</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In a significant leap for Bitcoin&#8217;s lending sector, <a href="https://www.liquidium.fi/">Liquidium</a>, a burgeoning startup, has successfully raised $1.25 million in a pre-seed funding round. This capital injection marks a pivotal moment for the company as it sets its sights on pioneering a novel lending framework utilizing Bitcoin&#8217;s ordinal technology.</p>
<p>The successful funding round was bolstered by the backing of prominent investors, including Bitcoin Frontier Fund, Side Door Ventures, Actai Ventures, Sora Ventures, Spicy Capital, UTXO Management, and a group of strategic angel investors, all contributing significantly to reaching this pivotal achievement.</p>
<p>Bitcoin ordinals are created by embedding non-fungible tokens (NFTs) directly onto individual satoshis, the smallest unit of Bitcoin. This groundbreaking approach effectively transforms each satoshi into a unique digital artifact capable of carrying distinct data or digital assets.</p>
<p>Liquidium&#8217;s innovative model leverages this technology to create a lending platform where <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/ordinals">Bitcoin ordinals</a> act as collateral. This venture not only diversifies the utility of Bitcoin but also introduces a fresh dynamic to the digital lending space.</p>
<p>The $1.25 million pre-seed funding round, spearheaded by a consortium of investors, provides Liquidium with crucial resources to develop and refine its platform.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/jason-fang/">Jason Fang</a>, Managing Partner of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/sora-ventures/">Sora Ventures</a>, said:</p>
<blockquote><p><span class="notion-enable-hover" data-token-index="0">“Liquidium is filling a huge market gap by introducing additional utility on ordinals, a core element to further boosting the value of ordinals use case. Given that fungible tokens are also in the form of ordinals, it will be very interesting to see how Liquidium can leverage this standard to grow their adoption.”</span><!-- notionvc: 630c4b2b-ea70-4884-90e9-593d5cc9e419 --></p></blockquote>
<p>Liquidium aims to embark on extensive research and development with fresh capital. The team&#8217;s primary focus will be on deploying a secure, user-friendly platform that harnesses the unique properties of Bitcoin ordinals to facilitate lending.</p>
<p>The long-term vision involves pioneering in this niche and expanding the boundaries of what&#8217;s possible in the broader lending ecosystem.</p>
<p>Liquidium&#8217;s successful funding round marks a significant step forward in integrating novel technologies like Bitcoin ordinals into practical financial applications.</p>
<p>As the company advances toward realizing its vision, it stands as a testament to the ever-evolving and innovative nature of the cryptocurrency sector.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: One of Liquidium&#8217;s investors, Sora Ventures, is an investor in CryptoSlate.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/liquidium-secures-1-25m-pre-seed-funding-for-bitcoin-ordinal-lending/">Liquidium secures $1.25M pre-seed funding for Bitcoin Ordinal lending</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/liquidium-secures-1-25m-pre-seed-funding-for-bitcoin-ordinal-lending/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bitcoin-ocean.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bitcoin-ocean.jpg" length="1792" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celsius cleared to exit bankruptcy and enact recovery plan</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-cleared-to-exit-bankruptcy-and-enact-recovery-plan/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-cleared-to-exit-bankruptcy-and-enact-recovery-plan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 21:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=372616</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The failed crypto lending firm Celsius Network has been cleared to exit bankruptcy and enact its recovery plan, Bloomberg reported on Nov. 9. That report indicates that the company won approval in bankruptcy court to convert its business into a creditor-owned Bitcoin (BTC) mining firm. The plan will also see the company compensate users whose [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-cleared-to-exit-bankruptcy-and-enact-recovery-plan/">Celsius cleared to exit bankruptcy and enact recovery plan</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The failed crypto lending firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/celsius-network/">Celsius Network</a> has been cleared to exit bankruptcy and enact its recovery plan, <em>Bloomberg</em> reported on <a href="https://www.bnnbloomberg.ca/failed-crypto-lender-celsius-network-cleared-to-exit-bankruptcy-1.1996462">Nov. 9</a>.</p>
<p>That report indicates that the company won approval in bankruptcy court to convert its business into a creditor-owned Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) mining firm.</p>
<p>The plan will also see the company compensate users whose account balances were previously frozen. Those users will receive both cryptocurrency and stock in the new company. Celsius expects to begin distributing those assets in early 2024.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://cases.stretto.com/public/x191/11749/PLEADINGS/1174911092380000000128.pdf">court documents</a>, the settlement will distribute Celsius&#8217; CEL token at a value of $0.25. Earlier developments in the case saw various customers and creditors object to a CEL distribution because of the token&#8217;s reduced value. However, Celsius and its unsecured creditors committee argued for this approach, and U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Martin Glenn ultimately ruled that a distribution using the CEL token is reasonable.</p>
<p>Though the plan has been approved in bankruptcy court, the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) must also approve it. Otherwise, Celsius may need to liquidate its assets instead. Judge Glenn has asked the SEC to reach a decision quickly.</p>
<h2>Celsius faces far-reaching regulatory action</h2>
<p>Celsius halted withdrawals and entered bankruptcy in mid-2022 amidst a broader liquidity crisis among crypto companies engaged in lending.</p>
<p>Though the bankruptcy trial has largely concluded, this does not mark the end of the company&#8217;s challenges. The Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) and SEC filed parallel actions against Celsius as well as its former CEO, Alex Mashinsky, in July 2023. The company also <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2023/07/ftc-reaches-settlement-crypto-platform-celsius-network-charges-former-executives-duping-consumers">reached a settlement</a> with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) at that time, which will permanently bar it from handling customer assets.</p>
<p>In July 2023, the U.S. Department of Justice filed various criminal charges related to fraud against Mashinsky. The DOJ issued its charges in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/alex-mashinsky-out-on-40m-bail-vehemently-denies-fraud-charges/">July 2023</a>; recent reports indicate that Mashinsky&#8217;s criminal trial will take place in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/alex-mashinskys-criminal-trial-set-for-september-2024/">September 2024</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-cleared-to-exit-bankruptcy-and-enact-recovery-plan/">Celsius cleared to exit bankruptcy and enact recovery plan</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-cleared-to-exit-bankruptcy-and-enact-recovery-plan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/DALL·E-2023-11-09-15.19.08-Photorealistic-image-of-an-old-timey-glass-thermometer-with-mercury-rising-indicating-a-transition-from-cold-to-warm-temperatures-on-the-Celsius-scal.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/DALL·E-2023-11-09-15.19.08-Photorealistic-image-of-an-old-timey-glass-thermometer-with-mercury-rising-indicating-a-transition-from-cold-to-warm-temperatures-on-the-Celsius-scal.jpg" length="1792" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlockFi emerges from bankruptcy; will pay loan and interest users in early 2024</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-emerges-from-bankruptcy-will-pay-loan-and-interest-users-in-early-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-emerges-from-bankruptcy-will-pay-loan-and-interest-users-in-early-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 19:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BlockFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=367700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>BlockFi announced on Oct. 24 that it has emerged from bankruptcy and can now enact the various parts of its bankruptcy plan, including a wind-down. BlockFi said that it will continue to distribute client assets. It noted that wallet customers can currently request withdrawals and will be able to do so until the withdrawal window [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-emerges-from-bankruptcy-will-pay-loan-and-interest-users-in-early-2024/">BlockFi emerges from bankruptcy; will pay loan and interest users in early 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blockfi/">BlockFi</a> announced on Oct. 24 that it has emerged from bankruptcy and can now enact the various parts of its bankruptcy plan, including a wind-down.</p>
<p>BlockFi said that it will continue to distribute client assets. It noted that wallet customers can currently request withdrawals and will be able to do so until the withdrawal window closes on Dec. 31. That withdrawal period originally opened in <a href="https://twitter.com/BlockFi/status/1692187283133473055">August</a>.</p>
<p>The company added that it intends to allow BlockFi Interest Account (BIA) and Retail Loan customers to make withdrawals available through a separate process starting in early 2024. BlockFi said it will send updates on this part of the process in the coming months. BlockFi also noted that it anticipates multiple waves of distributions and said that the assets in this category will come from its wind-down process.</p>
<p>BlockFi added that it will continue its claims reconciliation process to ensure that claims are accurate and that clients receive a fair amount of funds.</p>
<p>Finally, BlockFi said that the enactment of its recovery plan allows it to recover assets that it says are owed by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/three-arrows-capital/">Three Arrow Capital</a> (3AC), and other companies. BlockFi said that successful litigation could increase payouts for claimants. Some parties have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-ftx-and-three-arrows-capital-contest-blockfis-bankruptcy-plans/">contested BlockFi&#8217;s claims</a>, and the merit of BlockFi&#8217;s case is unclear.</p>
<h2>BlockFi filed for bankruptcy last November.</h2>
<p>BlockFi initially halted withdrawals and filed for bankruptcy in Nov. 2022. At that time, the company cited issues around the FTX empire — which would later result in FTX&#8217;s bankruptcy — as its reason for halting its services.</p>
<p>BlockFi maintained an extensive lending relationship with FTX. BlockFi&#8217;s bankruptcy claim suggested that it owed $275 million to FTX. However, <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2023/01/24/blockfi-secret-financials-show-1point2-billion-tie-to-ftx-and-alameda.html">later developments</a> indicated that BlockFi had $1.2 billion of assets and loans with FTX and Alameda. BlockFi CEO Zac Prince testified regarding the mutual lending arrangement in the criminal case of former FTX CEO Sam-Bankman on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-ceo-zac-prince-testifies-to-lending-relationship-with-alameda-research/">Oct. 14</a>.</p>
<p>BlockFi&#8217;s bankruptcy filings otherwise indicate that it owes as much as $10 billion to at least 100,000 creditors and former customers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-emerges-from-bankruptcy-will-pay-loan-and-interest-users-in-early-2024/">BlockFi emerges from bankruptcy; will pay loan and interest users in early 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-emerges-from-bankruptcy-will-pay-loan-and-interest-users-in-early-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/blockfi.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/blockfi.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BlockFi CEO Zac Prince testifies to lending relationship with Alameda Research before its collapse</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-ceo-zac-prince-testifies-to-lending-relationship-with-alameda-research/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-ceo-zac-prince-testifies-to-lending-relationship-with-alameda-research/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mike Dalton]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 23:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lending]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=364709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Zac Prince, the CEO of BlockFi, continued to provide testimony in the criminal trial of former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried on Oct. 13. In the previous day&#8217;s testimony, Prince described his firm&#8217;s lending relationship with Alameda Research. In current testimony, he described how Alameda began to dominate BlockFi lending activities and noted that he spoke [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-ceo-zac-prince-testifies-to-lending-relationship-with-alameda-research/">BlockFi CEO Zac Prince testifies to lending relationship with Alameda Research before its collapse</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/zac-prince/">Zac Prince</a>, the CEO of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blockfi/">BlockFi</a>, continued to provide testimony in the criminal trial of former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried on <a href="https://twitter.com/innercitypress/status/1712830044828053867">Oct. 13</a>.</p>
<p>In the previous day&#8217;s testimony, Prince <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sbf-trial-day-7-audio-recordings-reveal-ellison-told-alameda-employees-about-misuse-of-customer-funds-days-before-collapse/">described his firm&#8217;s lending relationship</a> with Alameda Research. In current testimony, he described how Alameda began to dominate BlockFi lending activities and noted that he spoke to FTX and Alameda as loans grew larger.</p>
<blockquote><p><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Prosecutors: &#8220;Did you talk with Sam Bankman-Fried?&#8221;<br />
Prince: &#8220;Yes, a CEO to CEO was suggested. So we did a call.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Prince said that BlockFi had at one point lent out $5 billion to $10 billion to its clients overall. <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/alameda-research/">Alameda Research</a> had initially borrowed $10 million circa early 2021, but that amount eventually rose to $50 million in May 2021 and to $1.1 billion in May 2022.</p>
<p>The BlockFi executive noted that his firm was also affected by other industry events, including the collapse of Luna and TerraUSD (which was followed by Three Arrows Capital&#8217;s default on its loan to BlockFi) as well as the bankruptcy of Celsius and Voyager.</p>
<p>Prince said that BlockFi, at one point, attempted to have FTX acquire it, as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-gives-blockfi-400m-credit-facility-has-buy-option-for-up-to-240-million/">reported in mid-2022</a>. Though the acquisition never occurred, Prince admitted that the arrangement with FTX influenced BlockFi&#8217;s decision to lend money to Alameda as a &#8220;data point.&#8221; He did not admit that BlockFi loaned to Alameda wholly because of that arrangement.</p>
<h2>BlockFi was unaware of FTX&#8217;s wrongdoing</h2>
<p>Prosecutors then presented Prince with Alameda&#8217;s Q2 2022 balance sheet. Though Prince was familiar with it, he said that he was told the loans detailed on the sheet were from other crypto lenders, as opposed to loans between FTX and Alameda.</p>
<p>Prince said that if he had known of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX&#8217;s</a> multibillion-dollar loans to Alameda, BlockFi would not have lent money to Alameda as it &#8220;would have been insolvent.&#8221; He added that if he had known that Alameda was using money that belonged to FTX customers, BlockFi would not have lent money as that practice is &#8220;not appropriate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Furthermore, Prince said that if he had known of Alameda&#8217;s loans to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-bankman-fried/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a>, BlockFi would have been &#8220;concerned.&#8221; Early bankruptcy reports <a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/mattdurot/2022/11/17/sam-bankman-fried-and-three-ftx-executives-received-41-billion-of-loans-from-alameda-research-where-did-the-money-come-from-and-where-did-it-go/?sh=2710feda79c7">suggest that</a> Bankman-Fried personally borrowed at least $1 billion from Alameda.</p>
<p>Prince also testified that when the price of FTX&#8217;s FTT token fell around the time of the companies&#8217; collapses, BlockFi attempted to call certain loans.</p>
<p>Prince said that, at the time of the collapse, $650 million of loaned funds were still outstanding and said that BlockFi had $350 million on FTX, leaving $1.1 billion affected. He testified that Alameda and FTX led to BlockFi&#8217;s own bankruptcy.</p>
<h2>Cross-examination addresses finer points</h2>
<p>During cross-examination, Bankman-Fried&#8217;s lawyer seemingly attempted to draw attention to the fact that both BlockFi and FTX lent out customer assets. Prince emphasized that BlockFi lent customer funds &#8220;if they agreed to.&#8221;</p>
<p>Also during that period, Cohen asked Prince whether BlockFi&#8217;s team had advised against increasing exposure to FTT tokens. Prince replied that the entire team had not advised this and said that BlockFi had made more loans when it required more collateral.</p>
<p>Earlier, Prince had noted BlockFi had received Grayscale Trust and Robinhood shares as collateral. Cohen asked whether Prince was aware of who owned those Robinhood shares. Prince replied that he &#8220;wasn&#8217;t aware of the nuances.&#8221; Robinhood <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/robinhood-strikes-deal-with-u-s-marshal-service-to-buy-back-sam-bankman-frieds-seized-shares/">recently purchased</a> those shares from the U.S. government after they were seized from Bankman-Fried. In late 2022, BlockFi had <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-attempts-to-maintain-ownership-of-robinhood-shares-in-court/">attempted to lay claim</a> to the shares itself.</p>
<p>Finally, Cohen asked whether Prince was ever concerned about whether BlockFi might go bankrupt. Prince answered that a CEO &#8220;must think of possibilities.&#8221;</p>
<p>Cohen&#8217;s cross-examination concluded at that point. The trial will continue next week, with FTX associates Nishad Singh and Ramnik Arora providing testimony.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-ceo-zac-prince-testifies-to-lending-relationship-with-alameda-research/">BlockFi CEO Zac Prince testifies to lending relationship with Alameda Research before its collapse</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/blockfi-ceo-zac-prince-testifies-to-lending-relationship-with-alameda-research/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/blockfi-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/blockfi-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
