<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Deflationary Coins, Tokens, Cryptos &amp; Assets | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/deflationary/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/deflationary/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 13:33:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Deflationary Coins, Tokens, Cryptos &amp; Assets | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/deflationary/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Pepe</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pepe/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pepe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 14:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=321770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>PEPE is a deflationary memecoin launched on Ethereum. The cryptocurrency was created as a tribute to the Pepe the Frog internet meme created by Matt Furie, which gained popularity in the early 2000s. The project aims to capitalize on the popularity of meme coins, like Shiba Inu and Dogecoin and strives to establish itself as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pepe/">Pepe</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>PEPE is a deflationary <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/meme/">memecoin</a> launched on <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum">Ethereum</a>. The cryptocurrency was created as a tribute to the Pepe the Frog internet meme created by Matt Furie, which gained popularity in the early 2000s.</p>
<p>The project aims to capitalize on the popularity of meme coins, like <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/coins/shiba-inu">Shiba Inu</a> and <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/coins/dogecoin">Dogecoin</a> and strives to establish itself as one of the top meme-based cryptocurrencies. PEPE appeals to the cryptocurrency community by instituting a no-tax policy, a redistributive system rewarding long-term stakers, and a burning mechanism to maintain the scarcity of the PEPE coin.</p>
<p>PEPE is an ERC-20 token on the <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/blockchain/ethereum">Ethereum blockchain</a>, secured by the <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/proof-of-stake">Proof-of-Stake (PoS)</a> consensus mechanism. Decentralized validators stake 32 ETH to process transactions and secure the network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pepe/">Pepe</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pepe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Baby Doge Coin</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/baby-doge-coin/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/baby-doge-coin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 15:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=193652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Baby Doge is a deflationary coin designed to become more scarce over time. All holders of Baby Doge will earn more baby doge that is automatically sent to your wallet by simply by holding Baby Doge coins in your wallet. Watch the amount of baby doge grow in your wallet as all holders automatically receive [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/baby-doge-coin/">Baby Doge Coin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Baby Doge is a deflationary coin designed to become more scarce over time. All holders of Baby Doge will earn more baby doge that is automatically sent to your wallet by simply by holding Baby Doge coins in your wallet. Watch the amount of baby doge grow in your wallet as all holders automatically receive a 5% fee from every transaction that happens on the Baby Doge network. The community owns the baby doge network earning from fees generated on the baby doge network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/baby-doge-coin/">Baby Doge Coin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/baby-doge-coin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solidus Ai Tech</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solidus-ai-tech/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solidus-ai-tech/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 14:23:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=405494</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Solidus has successfully constructed an environmentally conscious, state-of-the-art High-Performance Computing (HPC) Data Centre spanning over 8,000 square feet. This facility is strategically situated in a highly secure European location. In conjunction with this remarkable achievement, Solidus is poised to unveil the world&#8217;s pioneering deflationary Artificial Intelligence token, known as AITECH. This token will serve as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solidus-ai-tech/">Solidus Ai Tech</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Solidus has successfully constructed an environmentally conscious, state-of-the-art High-Performance Computing (HPC) Data Centre spanning over 8,000 square feet. This facility is strategically situated in a highly secure European location. In conjunction with this remarkable achievement, Solidus is poised to unveil the world&#8217;s pioneering deflationary Artificial Intelligence token, known as AITECH. This token will serve as a payment gateway for licensing Artificial Intelligence as a Service (AIaaS), Blockchain as a Service (BaaS), and accessing HPC resources via their Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) platform.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Solidus intends to establish an exclusive marketplace catering to software developers, enabling them to launch Artificial Intelligence software applications for end-users to license. Through this innovative initiative, developers will partake in a profit-sharing model, thereby gaining substantial benefits.</p>
<p>AITECH, as the core token fueling the Solidus AI Tech ecosystem, presents a comprehensive solution for procuring all services available on the platform. In addition to facilitating token payments, Solidus offers the convenience of accepting traditional payment methods. The conversion of fiat currency transactions to AITECH occurs seamlessly on the backend, with the entire process conducted on the Blockchain utilizing AITECH tokens.</p>
<p>As an integral component of our deflationary token economy, a percentage ranging from 5% to 10% of AITECH tokens utilized for acquiring services on the platform will be systematically burned. This meticulous process ensures the utmost transparency, as the precise number of tokens subjected to burning can be readily monitored through our comprehensive dashboard.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solidus-ai-tech/">Solidus Ai Tech</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solidus-ai-tech/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ArbDoge AI</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbdoge-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbdoge-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 07:16:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=321973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>ArbDoge AI is not a project but an experiment in the Arbitrum ecosystem. There are no VC institutions or team shares here. All tokens will be distributed fairly and applied to the community, which is just the first step. The creators of the ArbDoge AI protocol are a group of AI organisms who are passionate [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbdoge-ai/">ArbDoge AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>ArbDoge AI is not a project but an experiment in the Arbitrum ecosystem. There are no VC institutions or team shares here. All tokens will be distributed fairly and applied to the community, which is just the first step. The creators of the ArbDoge AI protocol are a group of AI organisms who are passionate about Arbitrum. They hope to work with the community to create a strong series of products using AI+Web3. By the way, the survival and development of AIDOGE depend on code, and they love to collect $ARB.</p>
<p>AIDOGE is a deflationary token. It will be used by AIDOGE ecosystem applications. The total supply is 210,000,000,000,000,000 tokens. AIDOGE belongs to everyone in the Arbitrum community and is also a necessary key to unlock the future chapters of the AIDOGE story.</p>
<p>AIDOGE has a 15% burning tax, so adjusting your slippage tolerance to around 20% is suggested when buying/selling to ensure your successful transactions. Every time you buy AIDOGE, you will receive a Lucky Drop ticket with a chance to win an ARB prize based on the purchase amount. You can also stake your AIDOGE to earn more.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbdoge-ai/">ArbDoge AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbdoge-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>RichQUACK.com</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/richquack-com/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/richquack-com/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 16:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=220620</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rich Quack is aimed at providing its holders with a chance to make money, by investing, building, holding and winning. Rich Quack wants to achieve that by building a community of people with a common goal that is ready to work hard and contribute towards that goal. The project aims to become the future of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/richquack-com/">RichQUACK.com</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Rich Quack is aimed at providing its holders with a chance to make money, by investing, building, holding and winning.</p>
<p>Rich Quack wants to achieve that by building a community of people with a common goal that is ready to work hard and contribute towards that goal. The project aims to become the future of a safe and secure investing and fundraising platform, where you can also win a jackpot raffle for holding, and play lotto that pays out every hour, day, week and month.</p>
<p>The protocol generates frictionless yield by applying a 12% fee for each transaction. 4% of each transaction is distributed to holders, and another 4% is provided to the QUACK/BNB liquidity pool. 2% goes to pump and burn wallets to create “an ever rising price floor”, and 2% goes to the marketing and developer wallet.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/richquack-com/">RichQUACK.com</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/richquack-com/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Volt Inu V2</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/volt-inu-v2/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/volt-inu-v2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 15:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=266403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Volt Inu ($VOLT) is a highly deflationary token on the Ethereum blockchain that keeps growing through the use of true deflationary techniques and additional revenue generation. In addition to the classic revenue streams such as: Blue chip NFTs – Stablecoin staking – Big and medium cap altcoins – Yield farms, $VOLT will generate passive income [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/volt-inu-v2/">Volt Inu V2</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Volt Inu ($VOLT) is a highly deflationary token on the Ethereum blockchain that keeps growing through the use of true deflationary techniques and additional revenue generation.</p>
<p>In addition to the classic revenue streams such as: Blue chip NFTs – Stablecoin staking – Big and medium cap altcoins – Yield farms, $VOLT will generate passive income that will benefit all hodlers through NFTs fractionalization that will be distributed to top holders and through the acquisition of nodes that will allow for continuous revenue generation to be funneled back into $VOLT.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/volt-inu-v2/">Volt Inu V2</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/volt-inu-v2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pitbull</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pitbull/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pitbull/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 15:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=248893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pitbull (PIT) is a community-driven, dog-themed meme coin on Binance Smart Chain (BSC). It prides itself on community development and claims to be a “unique social experiment” by engaging investors in the development of the community, as well as in the project itself. Pitbull rewards its investors through an auto-staking mechanism, which guarantees passive yield [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pitbull/">Pitbull</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pitbull (PIT) is a community-driven, dog-themed meme coin on Binance Smart Chain (BSC). It prides itself on community development and claims to be a “unique social experiment” by engaging investors in the development of the community, as well as in the project itself. Pitbull rewards its investors through an auto-staking mechanism, which guarantees passive yield by rewarding token holders with fees from transactions that are conducted in PIT.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pitbull/">Pitbull</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/pitbull/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unicrypt</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/unicrypt/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/unicrypt/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 03:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=140491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>UNCX is a deflationary governance token of the UniCrypt platform &#8211; a platform which provides services to other tokens.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/unicrypt/">Unicrypt</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>UNCX is a deflationary governance token of the UniCrypt platform &#8211; a platform which provides services to other tokens.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/unicrypt/">Unicrypt</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/unicrypt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Unicrypt-social.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Unicrypt-social.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Metahero</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/metahero/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/metahero/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 15:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=194551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Metahero brings to the market 3D scanning and modeling technology that generates ultra-realistic 3D avatars and virtual items to be used across games, VR, social media, and online fashion. The tech also allows for the creation of NFTs from real-world works of art and collectibles.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/metahero/">Metahero</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Metahero brings to the market 3D scanning and modeling technology that generates ultra-realistic 3D avatars and virtual items to be used across games, VR, social media, and online fashion. The tech also allows for the creation of NFTs from real-world works of art and collectibles.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/metahero/">Metahero</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/metahero/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/metahero-social.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/metahero-social.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EverRise</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/everrise/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/everrise/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[CryptoSlate Coins]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 13:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?post_type=crypto_coin&#038;p=193503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>EverRise is a hyper-deflationary token, which rewards investors for holdingtokens, while also incorporating the Buyback approach currently present in the stock market. EverRise is the first cryptocurrency ever to include automatic Buyback. What is Buyback? If a particular stock has low value, but has the potential to perform better in the future, often companies will [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/everrise/">EverRise</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>EverRise is a hyper-deflationary token, which rewards investors for holdingtokens, while also incorporating the Buyback approach currently present in the stock market. EverRise is the first cryptocurrency ever to include automatic Buyback. What is Buyback? If a particular stock has low value, but has the potential to perform better in the future, often companies will announce a buyback of the stock in the open market.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/everrise/">EverRise</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coins/everrise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
