<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Bankruptcy News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/bankruptcy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bankruptcy/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:18:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Bankruptcy News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bankruptcy/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Celsius initiates second payout of $127 million, enhancing creditor returns to 60.4%</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-initiates-second-payout-of-127-million-enhancing-creditor-returns-to-60-4/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-initiates-second-payout-of-127-million-enhancing-creditor-returns-to-60-4/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celsius]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto lender Celsius has announced the second round of payments to creditors. According to a Nov. 27 court filing, this phase involves the distribution of $127 million in assets that will cover 2.75% of total creditor claims. The payout follows an earlier round in August, which returned $2.53 billion to 251,000 creditors, representing 57.65% [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-initiates-second-payout-of-127-million-enhancing-creditor-returns-to-60-4/">Celsius initiates second payout of $127 million, enhancing creditor returns to 60.4%</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto lender <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/celsius-network/">Celsius</a> has announced the second round of payments to creditors<span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">According to a Nov. 27 <a href="https://cases.stretto.com/public/x191/11749/PLEADINGS/1174911272480000000219.pdf">court filing</a>, this phase involves the distribution of $127 million in assets that will cover 2.75% of total creditor claims</span>.</p>
<p>The payout follows an earlier round in August, which <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-distributes-2-53-billion-some-creditors-leave-funds-unclaimed/">returned $2.53 billion to 251,000 creditors</a>, representing 57.65% of claims.</p>
<p>With this new distribution, the total payout reaches 60.4% of eligible claims. The firm stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;As a result of the Second Distribution, each Eligible Creditor will receive a cumulative distribution in Cash or Liquid Cryptocurrency equal to approximately 60.4% of the value of such creditor’s Claims as of the Petition Date.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Distribution details</h2>
<p>According to the court filing, creditors will receive their payments in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> or US dollar cash based on their eligibility.</p>
<p>Those who previously received crypto payments will continue to accept Bitcoin, while cash recipients will be paid similarly. Celsius plans to use the same distribution agents as before whenever possible to streamline the process.</p>
<p>The company specified that creditors wishing to receive Bitcoin must have a verified <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> account linked to their Celsius records. It stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;As per the Coinbase Agreement, after Nov 9, 2024, non-corporate creditors who still have not received their Celsius distribution via Coinbase will automatically be rerouted to a US dollar (USD) distribution partner instead.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, Bitcoin payouts will depend on its market value. If the price falls below $95,836, creditors may receive less than 2.75% of their claims, while a higher price will result in increased payouts.</p>
<p>A Celsius-focused account on X <a href="https://x.com/CelsiusFacts/status/1861904109831365042">explained</a> that creditors unable to accept crypto will have their Bitcoin equivalent sold at market rates, with proceeds delivered as US Dollars through various payment methods, including wire transfers, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/paypal/">PayPal</a>, and Venmo.</p>
<p class="s3">This development arrives as former Celsius CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/alex-mashinsky/">Alex Mashinsky</a> is scheduled to face trial on Jan. 28, 2025, with a pre-trial hearing set for Jan. 16. Notably, a federal court recently denied his request to dismiss fraud charges related to the company&#8217;s collapse.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-initiates-second-payout-of-127-million-enhancing-creditor-returns-to-60-4/">Celsius initiates second payout of $127 million, enhancing creditor returns to 60.4%</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/celsius-initiates-second-payout-of-127-million-enhancing-creditor-returns-to-60-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celsius-creditors.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celsius-creditors.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX on track to rollout repayment plan in January 2025</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-on-track-to-rollout-repayment-plan-in-january-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-on-track-to-rollout-repayment-plan-in-january-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 02:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FTX and its affiliated debtors announced they are on track to implement their Chapter 11 Plan of Reorganization by Jan. 2025, which will set distributions for creditors and customers.  According to the timeline shared in the firm&#8217;s announcement, the final arrangements with specialized distribution agents will be completed in December, allowing customers in supported jurisdictions [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-on-track-to-rollout-repayment-plan-in-january-2025/">FTX on track to rollout repayment plan in January 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> and its affiliated debtors</span> <strong><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/ftx-provides-update-on-upcoming-timeline-for-creditor-and-customer-distributions-302313274.html">announced</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> they are on track to implement their Chapter 11 Plan of Reorganization by Jan. 2025, which will set distributions for creditors and customers. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the timeline shared in the firm&#8217;s announcement, the final arrangements with specialized distribution agents will be completed in December, allowing customers in supported jurisdictions to establish accounts through FTX&#8217;s customer portal.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, the firm will reveal the exact date for reimbursements during the same month once it has secured court approval for the Disputed Claims Reserve Amount.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The first round of distributions will start in January 2025, targeting holders in the Convenience Classes, and will be scheduled within 60 days of the effective date.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FTX CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/john-j-ray-iii/">John J. Ray III</a> stated:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;We are pleased to announce that we will begin distributing proceeds in early 2025. The timeline laid out reflects the experience and continued work of the team of professionals supporting the Debtors, who already have recovered billions of dollars on behalf of FTX&#8217;s creditors and customers.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">US Bankruptcy Judge John Dorsey</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/court-greenlights-ftxs-16-5-billion-bankruptcy-plan-to-repay-defrauded-customers/">approved the $16.5 billion recovery plan</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> during a hearing in Wilmington, Delaware, on Oct. 7. The customer repayments rely on settlements made with FTX customers, creditors, US government agencies, and international liquidators.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The approved plan prioritizes FTX customers, enabling the exchange to repay their claims first, ahead of competing claims from government regulators. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The total value recovered could be as high as $16.5 billion, subject to falling to $14.7 billion after its cash conversion. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The FTX collapsed in Nov. 2022 after its founder, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-bankman-fried/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a>, and other executives mismanaged customers&#8217; funds and used them in other ventures. Authorities estimate the FTX collapse left around 9 million customers and investors facing substantial financial losses.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Reimbursement requirements</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">FTX emphasized that customers must establish approved accounts with distribution agents, complete Know Your Customer (KYC) verification, and submit tax forms before the distribution record date to qualify for the initial payout.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Claims traders were also cautioned that transfers made within 45 days of the distribution record date might not be reflected in the claims register in time, potentially redirecting distributions to the original claim holders.  </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-on-track-to-rollout-repayment-plan-in-january-2025/">FTX on track to rollout repayment plan in January 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-on-track-to-rollout-repayment-plan-in-january-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DOJ targets $16 million in Binance account tied to Sam Bankman-Fried foreign bribery case</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/doj-targets-16-million-in-binance-account-tied-to-sam-bankman-fried-bribery-case/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/doj-targets-16-million-in-binance-account-tied-to-sam-bankman-fried-bribery-case/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452759</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US Department of Justice (DOJ) filed a civil forfeiture complaint to seize approximately $16 million in assets from a Binance account connected to an FTX bribery case, according to a Nov. 12 court filing. The Binance account, created in November 2023, contains various digital assets, including Internet Computer (ICP), Avalanche (AVAX), Ripple (XRP), Cardano [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/doj-targets-16-million-in-binance-account-tied-to-sam-bankman-fried-bribery-case/">DOJ targets $16 million in Binance account tied to Sam Bankman-Fried foreign bribery case</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The US Department of Justice (DOJ) filed a civil forfeiture complaint to seize approximately $16 million in assets from a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> account connected to an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> bribery case, according to a Nov. 12 court <a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.nysd.631459/gov.uscourts.nysd.631459.1.0.pdf">filing</a>.</p>
<p>The Binance account, created in November 2023, contains various digital assets, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/internet-computer/">Internet Computer</a> (ICP), <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/avalanche/">Avalanche</a> (AVAX), Ripple (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a>), <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/cardano/">Cardano</a> (ADA), and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a> (SOL).</p>
<p>The account reportedly received deposits in stablecoins and Bitcoin almost daily, which were swiftly converted to other assets.</p>
<h2>Chinese bribe</h2>
<p>According to the DOJ, former FTX CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-bankman-fried/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a> allegedly approved a $40 million bribe to Chinese officials in November 2021.</p>
<p>This bribe aimed to unfreeze <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/alameda-research/">Alameda Research&#8217;s</a> crypto trading accounts on two exchanges in China, which law enforcement authorities had frozen. The filing stated that these accounts held an estimated $1 billion in crypto.</p>
<p>Once the accounts were unfrozen, Bankman-Fried authorized &#8220;tens of millions of dollars in crypto&#8221; payments to finalize the bribe. The funds were then laundered through multiple private wallets to obscure the payments&#8217; origins and intentions.</p>
<p>Investigators eventually traced these funds from private wallets to the implicated Binance account.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the bribery allegations, originally part of Bankman-Fried&#8217;s indictment, formed one of thirteen, charging him with conspiracy to violate the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act. That charge was later separated from the main trial that led to his conviction.</p>
<h2>Over $3 billion in recovery efforts</h2>
<p>This DOJ filing marks another chapter in the pursuit to recover over $3 billion in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bankrupt-ftx-targets-crypto-com-in-11-million-lawsuit-amid-recovery-effort/">assets linked to FTX-related criminal activity.</a></p>
<p>In recent weeks, FTX has initiated several lawsuits to accelerate its fund recovery mission. The firm filed actions against <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-binance-and-changpeng-zhao-for-1-8-billion-over-alleged-financial-sabotage/">Binance and Changpeng Zhao for $1.8 billion</a> and against Waves founder Aleksandr Ivanov for $90 million.</p>
<p>Further, another of the exchange suits targets the creators of Storybook Brawl, a video game that Bankman-Fried supported. FTX further pursued a significant clawback action against Nawaaz Mohammad Meerun, known as &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/compound-finance-faces-scrutiny-over-24million-treasury-allocation/">Humpy the Whale</a>,&#8221; alleging that he caused over $1 billion in market manipulation-related losses.</p>
<p>Other cases target FTX&#8217;s political donations and public figures, including former White House official Anthony Scaramucci and famous marketer Neil Patel.</p>
<p>Combined, these legal actions represent claims exceeding $3 billion. However, an advocate for FTX creditors, known as Mr. Purple on X, expressed <a href="https://x.com/MrPurple_DJ/status/1856623801628610989">skepticism</a> about full recovery.</p>
<p>He noted that the defunct firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-eyes-21-million-asset-recovery-through-settlements-with-bank-and-charity-organization/">often settles for a fraction</a> of the claim amount—typically 10% to 20%— and suggested it would be surprising if recoveries reached even $0.5 billion from these efforts.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/doj-targets-16-million-in-binance-account-tied-to-sam-bankman-fried-bribery-case/">DOJ targets $16 million in Binance account tied to Sam Bankman-Fried foreign bribery case</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/doj-targets-16-million-in-binance-account-tied-to-sam-bankman-fried-bribery-case/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-binance.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-binance.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX sues Binance and Changpeng Zhao for $1.8 billion over alleged financial sabotage</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-binance-and-changpeng-zhao-for-1-8-billion-over-alleged-financial-sabotage/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-binance-and-changpeng-zhao-for-1-8-billion-over-alleged-financial-sabotage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 10:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto exchange FTX has filed a lawsuit against Binance and its former CEO, Changpeng Zhao, seeking to reclaim approximately $1.8 billion. According to a Nov. 10 court filing, FTX alleges a complex series of actions that contributed to its financial downfall, placing Binance&#8217;s early involvement and Zhao&#8217;s actions in the spotlight. So, through this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-binance-and-changpeng-zhao-for-1-8-billion-over-alleged-financial-sabotage/">FTX sues Binance and Changpeng Zhao for $1.8 billion over alleged financial sabotage</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> has filed a lawsuit against <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> and its former CEO, Changpeng Zhao, seeking to reclaim approximately $1.8 billion.</p>
<p>According to a Nov. 10 court filing, FTX alleges a complex series of actions that contributed to its financial downfall, placing Binance&#8217;s early involvement and Zhao&#8217;s actions in the spotlight.</p>
<p>So, through this lawsuit, FTX aims to hold Binance and Zhao accountable for what it describes as actions that decimated its financial stability, resulting in significant losses for its stakeholders</p>
<h2>FTX and Binance&#8217;s early relationship</h2>
<p>In November 2019, Binance acquired a 20% stake in FTX, then a new exchange launched by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/sam-bankman-fried/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a>. Binance made this purchase using 1,002,739 BNB tokens, strengthening its position as one of the exchange&#8217;s key stakeholders.</p>
<p>By 2020, Binance expanded its investment by purchasing an 18.4% stake in FTX&#8217;s US affiliate, West Realm Shires (WRS), for $2, marking a deepening partnership between the two exchanges.</p>
<p>However, by 2021, personal tensions between Zhao and Bankman-Fried reportedly drove Binance to exit its investment in FTX and WRS.</p>
<p>The filing revealed that FTX agreed to buy back Binance&#8217;s shares through its affiliate <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/alameda-research/">Alameda Research</a>. The transaction was funded with FTX&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ftx-token/">FTT</a> token, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bnb/">BNB</a>, and Binance&#8217;s stablecoin, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/binance-usd/">BUSD</a>. This share repurchase was valued at around $1.76 billion.</p>
<p>FTX now contends that Alameda was insolvent at the time of the transaction and should not have funded the buyback. The exchange cited testimony from the trading firm&#8217;s former CEO, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/caroline-ellison/">Caroline Ellison</a>, who testified that she warned Bankman-Fried about the lack of funds to support the buyback.</p>
<p>Despite these concerns, Bankman-Fried reportedly insisted on completing the transaction, emphasizing its strategic importance even if it required using depositor funds. Ellison claims Alameda ultimately financed the buyback with approximately $1 billion from FTX&#8217;s depositor base.</p>
<p>According to the exchange:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The FTX Trading shares acquired through the share repurchase were actually worthless based on a proper accounting of FTX Trading’s assets and liabilities.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Blames Zhao for collapse</h2>
<p>After Binance&#8217;s exit, FTX alleged that Zhao <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-fully-acquire-ftx/">engaged in actions</a> designed to harm its market position.</p>
<p>The bankrupt firm stated that Zhao&#8217;s tweets following reports about Alameda&#8217;s financial condition sparked fears around FTX&#8217;s stability and led to a sharp increase in customer withdrawals.</p>
<p>Furthermore, FTX alleges that Zhao&#8217;s continued tweets obstructed FTX&#8217;s efforts to secure emergency funding to stem the withdrawal surge.</p>
<p>In conclusion, the firm stated that these public statements created a liquidity crisis that ultimately led to its collapse.</p>
<p>FTX alleged:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Collectively and individually, these false public statements destroyed value that would have otherwise been recoverable by FTX’s stakeholders.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-binance-and-changpeng-zhao-for-1-8-billion-over-alleged-financial-sabotage/">FTX sues Binance and Changpeng Zhao for $1.8 billion over alleged financial sabotage</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-binance-and-changpeng-zhao-for-1-8-billion-over-alleged-financial-sabotage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/binance-ftx-psd.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/binance-ftx-psd.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bankrupt FTX targets Crypto.com in $11 million lawsuit amid recovery effort</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bankrupt-ftx-targets-crypto-com-in-11-million-lawsuit-amid-recovery-effort/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bankrupt-ftx-targets-crypto-com-in-11-million-lawsuit-amid-recovery-effort/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 13:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alameda Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt FTX has filed a lawsuit to recover at least $11 million held in a Crypto.com account linked to its sister company, Alameda Research, according to a Nov. 8 filing. FTX alleges that before filing for bankruptcy, Alameda held an account at Crypto.com registered under the name Ka Yu Tin, also known as Nicole Tin. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bankrupt-ftx-targets-crypto-com-in-11-million-lawsuit-amid-recovery-effort/">Bankrupt FTX targets Crypto.com in $11 million lawsuit amid recovery effort</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> has filed a lawsuit to recover at least $11 million held in a Crypto.com account linked to its sister company, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/alameda-research/">Alameda Research</a>, according to a Nov. 8 filing.</p>
<p>FTX alleges that before filing for bankruptcy, Alameda held an account at <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/crypto-com/">Crypto.com</a> registered under the name Ka Yu Tin, also known as Nicole Tin.</p>
<p>According to the firm, this practice was typical for Alameda, which often opened accounts under shell companies or employees&#8217; names to mask its trading activities. However, FTX claims Alameda funded and controlled the account in question.</p>
<p>After Alameda declared bankruptcy, Crypto.com reportedly locked the account and denied FTX administrators&#8217; requests to access the funds despite repeated attempts.</p>
<p>FTX further claims that Crypto.com&#8217;s refusal is based on a mismatch between the account holder&#8217;s names and those seeking to recover the funds. The defunct firm asserts that it has clarified the complexities of the case to Crypto.com and has provided court-approved documentation, yet Crypto.com reportedly remains unresponsive.</p>
<p>To strengthen its case, FTX submitted an affidavit from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/caroline-ellison/">Caroline Ellison</a>, former CEO of Alameda Research, who stated that the Crypto.com accounts were indeed under Alameda affiliates or associated individuals. Ellison affirmed that Alameda had always considered the assets within these accounts belonging to the firm.</p>
<p>FTX concluded:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The assets in the Alameda Account, valued at approximately $11.4 million as of the Petition Date, are not of inconsequential value or benefit to the estate and must be returned to the Debtors.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>FTX holds Crypto.com&#8217;s assets</h2>
<p>FTX administrators are now attempting to leverage claims from companies affiliated with Crypto.com&#8217;s parent entities, Foris MT and Iron Block. These companies have filed claims against the failed exchange for $18.4 million and $237,800, which were held in FTX.com accounts before the exchange&#8217;s collapse.</p>
<p>Considering this, FTX requests that Crypto.com&#8217;s claims be deferred until the exchange releases the Alameda assets in its possession. The bankrupt exchange is also seeking recovery of the assets, legal costs, and additional relief.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bankrupt-ftx-targets-crypto-com-in-11-million-lawsuit-amid-recovery-effort/">Bankrupt FTX targets Crypto.com in $11 million lawsuit amid recovery effort</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bankrupt-ftx-targets-crypto-com-in-11-million-lawsuit-amid-recovery-effort/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-lawsuit-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-lawsuit-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fallen FTX sues Ryan Salame for $98.8 million over alleged fraud</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/fallen-ftx-sues-ryan-salame-for-98-8-million-over-alleged-fraudulence/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/fallen-ftx-sues-ryan-salame-for-98-8-million-over-alleged-fraudulence/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 11:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ryan Salame]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451684</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The bankrupt FTX exchange has filed a lawsuit against Ryan Salame, the former co-CEO of its Bahamian subsidiary, seeking to recover approximately $98.8 million in cash and crypto, according to a Nov. 4 court filing. The failed firm accuses Salame of knowingly assisting other executives—most notably, founder Sam Bankman-Fried—in breaching fiduciary duties and misappropriating customer [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fallen-ftx-sues-ryan-salame-for-98-8-million-over-alleged-fraudulence/">Fallen FTX sues Ryan Salame for $98.8 million over alleged fraud</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The bankrupt <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> exchange has filed a lawsuit against <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/ryan-salame/">Ryan Salame</a>, the former co-CEO of its Bahamian subsidiary, seeking to recover approximately $98.8 million in cash and crypto, according to a Nov. 4 court filing.</p>
<p>The failed firm accuses Salame of knowingly assisting other executives—most notably, founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sam-bankman-frieds-fraud-trial-key-points-to-understand/">Sam Bankman-Fried</a>—in breaching fiduciary duties and misappropriating customer assets.</p>
<p>According to FTX:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Despite Salame’s concerted efforts to obscure his receipt and expenditure of misappropriated Debtor assets, it is evident that Salame reaped substantial benefits from his role in &#8216;perpetrating aspects of the interrelated frauds that Bankman-Fried carried out at both companies.'&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The exchange contends Salame personally gained from his involvement and received significant compensation between November 2020 and November 2022. FTX alleges that during this period, Salame received $52.9 million in wire transfers, $29.8 million in cash and crypto withdrawals, and over $7.7 million in salary and bonuses.</p>
<p>He reportedly acquired nine million <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ftx-token/">FTT</a> tokens, sold 1.1 million for $24 million, and invested the proceeds in assets like luxury cars, businesses, and a $2.3 million stake in RedBird Capital Partners Fund IV.</p>
<p>The FTX lawsuit also draws attention to Salame&#8217;s guilty plea. During her unsuccessful Congressional campaign, he admitted to conspiring to make false statements to banks as part of an unlicensed money-transmitting business and making an excessive political donation to his former partner, Michelle Bond.</p>
<p>The exchange continued that Salame misused estate funds by withdrawing $5 million from his FTX.com account on Nov. 7, 2022. These funds, they allege, went toward personal expenses, including a public relations firm and a $20,000 personal charge at Restoration Hardware.</p>
<p>FTX has asked the court to disallow Salame&#8217;s claims in the exchange&#8217;s Chapter 11 proceedings until he returns all assets acquired through these transfers. This includes cash, crypto, and real estate spanning multiple locations—Connecticut, Miami, Portugal, Hong Kong, and Bali—obtained with the allegedly misappropriated funds.</p>
<p>In October, Salame began a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftxs-ryan-salame-to-serve-7-5-years-in-prison/">90-month prison sentence</a> following his guilty plea to conspiracy charges related to illegal political contributions and fraud against the Federal Election Commission. Alongside his prison term, Salame agreed to forfeit $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>Additionally, he received a three-year supervised release order and must pay over $6 million in forfeiture and $5 million in restitution.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fallen-ftx-sues-ryan-salame-for-98-8-million-over-alleged-fraudulence/">Fallen FTX sues Ryan Salame for $98.8 million over alleged fraud</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/fallen-ftx-sues-ryan-salame-for-98-8-million-over-alleged-fraudulence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-lawsuit.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-lawsuit.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mt. Gox moves $2 billion in Bitcoin, sparking speculation of additional repayments</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/mt-gox-moves-2-billion-in-bitcoin-sparking-speculation-of-additional-repayments/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/mt-gox-moves-2-billion-in-bitcoin-sparking-speculation-of-additional-repayments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 10:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mt. Gox]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Mt. Gox, the defunct crypto exchange, has transferred more than $2 billion worth of Bitcoin into two newly created wallets, according to data from Arkham Intelligence. Data from the blockchain analytics platform shows that Mt. Gox executed this transaction on Nov. 4 at 23:38 UTC. Most of these funds, totaling 30,371 BTC, were directed to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/mt-gox-moves-2-billion-in-bitcoin-sparking-speculation-of-additional-repayments/">Mt. Gox moves $2 billion in Bitcoin, sparking speculation of additional repayments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/mt-gox/">Mt. Gox</a>, the defunct crypto exchange, has transferred more than $2 billion worth of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> into two newly created wallets, according to <a href="https://platform.arkhamintelligence.com/explorer/entity/mt-gox">data</a> from Arkham Intelligence.</p>
<p>Data from the blockchain analytics platform shows that Mt. Gox executed this transaction on Nov. 4 at 23:38 UTC. Most of these funds, totaling 30,371 BTC, were directed to an unknown wallet address labeled &#8220;1FG2C.&#8221; About an hour later, around 2000 BTC was transferred to the address &#8220;15gNR.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite these transfers, Mt Gox still holds about 44,378 BTC, valued at $3.04 billion as of press time, according to Arkham Intelligence.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, SpotOnChain, another blockchain analytics firm, <a href="https://x.com/spotonchain/status/1853615753137914110">highlighted</a> that the Mt. Gox wallet has been particularly active recently. Within the past four days, it has moved 32,871 BTC, valued at approximately $2.22 billion, into various blockchain wallets.</p>
<p>Of this amount, a small segment—296 BTC, worth about $20.13 million—went to wallets connected to two prominent crypto exchanges, OKX and B2C2.</p>
<p>This substantial transfer has sparked widespread speculation about Mt. Gox&#8217;s schedule for its remaining assets and the potential impact on the crypto market.</p>
<p>Over recent months, Mt. Gox has continued distributing Bitcoin and Bitcoin Cash to creditors who suffered losses during the infamous 2014 hack. The hack saw the disappearance of up to 950,000 BTC, now worth over $58 billion.</p>
<p>These repayments are <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitgo-moves-2-billion-in-bitcoin-marking-progress-in-mt-gox-repayments/">processed through several major platforms</a>, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitstamp/">Bitstamp</a>, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitgo/">BitGo</a>. Notably, Mt. Gox recently <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/mt-gox-extends-creditor-repayment-deadline-to-2025/">extended its repayment deadline</a> by a year—from Oct. 31, 2024, to Oct. 31, 2025—to ensure it can complete reimbursements for all creditors.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/mt-gox-moves-2-billion-in-bitcoin-sparking-speculation-of-additional-repayments/">Mt. Gox moves $2 billion in Bitcoin, sparking speculation of additional repayments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/mt-gox-moves-2-billion-in-bitcoin-sparking-speculation-of-additional-repayments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/mt-gox-bitcoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/mt-gox-bitcoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX eyes $21 million asset recovery through settlements with bank and charity organization</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-eyes-21-million-asset-recovery-through-settlements-with-bank-and-charity-organization/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-eyes-21-million-asset-recovery-through-settlements-with-bank-and-charity-organization/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 11:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftx]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto exchange FTX has reached settlement agreements with Evolve Bank and Silicon Valley Community Foundation (SVCF) that could enable it to recover up to $21 million in assets. According to Oct. 30 court filings, these settlements still require court approval, with a hearing set for Nov. 20. Evolve Bank settlement Before FTX&#8217;s collapse in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-eyes-21-million-asset-recovery-through-settlements-with-bank-and-charity-organization/">FTX eyes $21 million asset recovery through settlements with bank and charity organization</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> has reached settlement agreements with Evolve Bank and Silicon Valley Community Foundation (SVCF) that could enable it to recover up to $21 million in assets.</p>
<p>According to Oct. 30 court filings, these settlements still require court approval, with a hearing set for Nov. 20.</p>
<h2>Evolve Bank settlement</h2>
<p>Before <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-volume-in-loss-hit-highest-level-since-ftx-collapse/">FTX&#8217;s collapse</a> in 2022, Evolve Bank maintained three accounts for West Realm Shires Services Inc., an FTX affiliate, under a Master Bank Services Agreement (MBSA). These accounts held more than $13 million in deposits on behalf of the FTX affiliate.</p>
<p>Initially, Evolve Bank filed a non-customer Proof of Claim for the full balance, citing indemnity and potential legal fees associated with the MBSA. However, the bank did not initially quantify these expenses.</p>
<p>After extensive negotiations, FTX and Evolve Bank agreed on a stipulation whereby the financial institution will promptly return approximately $12.77 million to the defunct firm while retaining $462,698.65 as indemnification expenses.</p>
<p>Additionally, Evolve Bank will waive all current and potential claims against FTX, including indemnity and expense claims under the MBSA.</p>
<p>FTX filed this settlement with the US Bankruptcy Court for the District of Delaware to expedite asset recovery and avoid prolonged litigation.</p>
<h2>Silicon Valley Community Foundation settlement</h2>
<p>Similarly, FTX has negotiated a settlement with SVCF to recover at least $8,574,674.07 and 34,208.70 <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ftx-token/">FTT</a> without entering litigation.</p>
<p>According to the court filing, former FTX executives <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/judge-grants-leniency-to-nishad-singh-in-ftx-scandal-for-crucial-cooperation/">Nishad Singh</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/caroline-ellison/">Caroline Ellison</a> donated 434,500 FTT tokens to the Foundation in December 2021.</p>
<p>Between January and November 2022, SVCF sold part of these tokens for $13,625,161, of which $5 million was allocated to external grants. This leaves the organization with a balance of at least $8,574,674.07 and 34,208.70 FTT.</p>
<p>FTX&#8217;s bankruptcy team contends that it has valid grounds to reclaim the assets transferred by Singh and Ellison.</p>
<p>So, the Foundation agreed with the failed exchange to return the $8.57 million and the remaining FTT tokens—less administrative fees and costs—to sidestep the need for litigation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-eyes-21-million-asset-recovery-through-settlements-with-bank-and-charity-organization/">FTX eyes $21 million asset recovery through settlements with bank and charity organization</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-eyes-21-million-asset-recovery-through-settlements-with-bank-and-charity-organization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/ftx-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX CEO appeals for Nishad Singh&#8217;s freedom to aid recovery efforts</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-ceo-appeals-for-nishad-singhs-freedom-to-aid-recovery-efforts/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-ceo-appeals-for-nishad-singhs-freedom-to-aid-recovery-efforts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 18:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=450808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FTX CEO John J. Ray III urged the court to keep former engineering director Nishad Singh out of prison, arguing that his continued freedom would help maximize asset recovery for the exchange&#8217;s creditors. Ray emphasized Singh&#8217;s cooperation as essential to FTX&#8217;s ongoing bankruptcy proceedings, where he has already assisted in asset recovery and provided critical [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-ceo-appeals-for-nishad-singhs-freedom-to-aid-recovery-efforts/">FTX CEO appeals for Nishad Singh&#8217;s freedom to aid recovery efforts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/john-j-ray-iii/">John J. Ray III</a> urged the court to keep former engineering director <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/nishad-singh/">Nishad Singh</a> out of prison, arguing that his continued freedom would help maximize asset recovery for the exchange&#8217;s creditors.</p>
<p>Ray emphasized Singh&#8217;s cooperation as essential to FTX&#8217;s ongoing bankruptcy proceedings, where he has already assisted in asset recovery and provided critical information about company operations.</p>
<p>In an Oct. 30 letter filed with the US District Court for the Southern District of New York, Ray highlighted Singh’s insider knowledge and technical expertise as crucial assets in tracking down funds.</p>
<p>Ray cited Singh&#8217;s assistance in retrieving property in the Bahamas purchased with company funds and sharing key documents with FTX debtors. He suggested Singh could offer further support by testifying in court and locating additional assets.</p>
<p>According to Ray:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Nishad Singh&#8217;s cooperation remains critical for FTX creditors.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Singh previously pleaded guilty to charges of financial misconduct and campaign finance violations linked to FTX&#8217;s downfall, making him one of the first insiders to admit guilt.</p>
<p>Prosecutors acknowledged Singh&#8217;s cooperation in their case against FTX&#8217;s former CEO, Sam Bankman-Fried, describing it as &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/us-prosecutors-recommend-leniency-for-former-ftx-executive-nishad-singh-following-substantial-assistance/">substantial assistance</a>&#8221; that contributed to his conviction.</p>
<p>Singh, one of the first FTX insiders to plead guilty, admitted to charges of financial misconduct and campaign finance violations tied to FTX&#8217;s collapse. His legal team <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ex-ftx-exec-nishad-singh-seeks-leniency-for-minor-role-in-collapse/">argued for time served</a>, stressing that Singh&#8217;s assistance had been instrumental in clarifying complex financial transactions at the exchange.</p>
<p>Judge Lewis Kaplan will weigh Singh&#8217;s cooperation as he considers sentencing, which is scheduled for later today.</p>
<p>Since filing for Chapter 11 in November 2022, FTX has undertaken an extensive recovery effort to reimburse its creditors. Ray&#8217;s leadership has steered these efforts, focusing on tracing assets across jurisdictions and untangling the network of transactions between FTX and Alameda Research.</p>
<p>FTX&#8217;s team has already recouped a portion of assets from real estate and liquid assets linked to the company&#8217;s former executives, but Ray suggested that Singh&#8217;s ongoing cooperation would enhance the chances of maximizing creditor recovery.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-ceo-appeals-for-nishad-singhs-freedom-to-aid-recovery-efforts/">FTX CEO appeals for Nishad Singh&#8217;s freedom to aid recovery efforts</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-ceo-appeals-for-nishad-singhs-freedom-to-aid-recovery-efforts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/ftx-john-ray.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/ftx-john-ray.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FTX sues KuCoin to recover $50 million in withheld assets</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-kucoin-to-recover-50-million-in-withheld-assets/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-kucoin-to-recover-50-million-in-withheld-assets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 13:20:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bankruptcy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ftx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kucoin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=450492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto exchange FTX has filed a lawsuit to recover over $50 million in assets allegedly withheld by KuCoin, according to court documents filed on Oct. 28. The assets were reportedly held in a KuCoin account belonging to the now-defunct Alameda Research, which filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy in November 2022. FTX&#8217;s allegation In its [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-kucoin-to-recover-50-million-in-withheld-assets/">FTX sues KuCoin to recover $50 million in withheld assets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bankrupt crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ftx/">FTX</a> has filed a lawsuit to recover over $50 million in assets allegedly withheld by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kucoin/">KuCoin</a>, according to court documents filed on Oct. 28.</p>
<p>The assets were reportedly held in a KuCoin account belonging to the now-defunct Alameda Research, which filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy in November 2022.</p>
<h2>FTX&#8217;s allegation</h2>
<p>In its lawsuit, FTX claimed that KuCoin locked access to these unnamed assets shortly after the bankruptcy proceedings began. At the time, the account held assets valued at around $30 million, rendering the bankrupt firm&#8217;s management team unable to access them.</p>
<p>Despite repeated requests—including direct communications with KuCoin&#8217;s CEO and legal representatives—FTX noted that KuCoin has refused to release the assets.</p>
<p>FTX stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Notwithstanding further follow-ups to KuCoin and its in-house and outside legal teams, KuCoin has continued to refuse to turn over the Debtors’ assets or even to meaningfully engage with the Debtors regarding their requests.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>FTX claimed that the value of the locked assets has since grown to over $50 million. This claim is unsurprising, considering the sharp rise in crypto prices since 2022. For example, Bitcoin, which traded at under $20,000 in 2022, recently surpassed the $70,000 mark.</p>
<p>So, through this legal process, FTX aims to secure the return of these assets as part of its larger goal of supporting asset recovery for creditors and users.</p>
<p>This development follows FTX&#8217;s recent <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-reaches-228-million-settlement-with-bybit-amid-bankruptcy-efforts/">$228 million settlement</a> with the crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bybit/">Bybit</a> and its affiliates. Additionally, FTX&#8217;s efforts align with its ongoing strategy to wind down operations and distribute assets. Earlier this month, FTX received court approval for a reorganization plan aimed at returning at least $12.6 billion to customers with frozen digital assets on the platform.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-kucoin-to-recover-50-million-in-withheld-assets/">FTX sues KuCoin to recover $50 million in withheld assets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ftx-sues-kucoin-to-recover-50-million-in-withheld-assets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kucoin-lawsuit.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kucoin-lawsuit.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
