<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Investments News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/investments/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/investments/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:21:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Investments News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/investments/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>XRP enters corporate treasury reserves with Worksport and BC Bud Co investments</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-enters-corporate-treasury-reserves-with-worksport-and-bc-bud-co-investments/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-enters-corporate-treasury-reserves-with-worksport-and-bc-bud-co-investments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 11:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workspot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>XRP&#8217;s recent price surge has sparked growing interest from institutional players, with Worksport and The BC Bud Co. announcing plans to include the token in their treasury strategies. Traditionally, corporate crypto investments have centered on Bitcoin, a trend set by companies like MicroStrategy. However, XRP&#8217;s impressive 300% rally over the past month has propelled it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-enters-corporate-treasury-reserves-with-worksport-and-bc-bud-co-investments/">XRP enters corporate treasury reserves with Worksport and BC Bud Co investments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP&#8217;s</a> recent price surge has sparked growing interest from institutional players, with Worksport and The BC Bud Co. announcing plans to include the token in their treasury strategies.</p>
<p>Traditionally, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/rising-bitcoin-tides-lift-small-cap-companies-to-bold-reserve-strategies/">corporate crypto investments</a> have centered on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a>, a trend set by companies like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microstrategy/">MicroStrategy</a>. However, XRP&#8217;s impressive 300% rally over the past month has propelled it into the top three digital assets by market capitalization.</p>
<p>Market observers suggest that this rally has encouraged smaller firms to explore XRP, aiming to benefit from the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-xrp-price-surge-comapres-it-to-americas-top-100-companies-by-market-cap/">growing momentum around the token</a>.</p>
<h2>Workspot eyes $5 million Bitcoin and XRP allocation</h2>
<p>On Dec. 5, Worksport, a Nasdaq-listed truck cover manufacturer, unveiled plans to diversify its treasury by investing up to $5 million in Bitcoin and XRP.</p>
<p>According to its statement, the company intends to allocate 10% of its surplus operational cash to these digital assets to hedge against inflation and enhance its financial strategy.</p>
<p>Additionally, Worksport plans to accept crypto payments on its e-commerce platform, anticipating transaction cost reductions of up to 37%. The company also aims to reinvest interest earned from money market accounts into Bitcoin and XRP while considering future capital allocations to build long-term crypto reserves.</p>
<p>Steven Rossi, CEO of Worksport, described Bitcoin and XRP as resilient assets well-suited for a modern treasury approach. He emphasized their potential to preserve value and serve as tools for financial innovation.</p>
<h2>BC Bud Co. invests in XRP.</h2>
<p>Canadian cannabis company The BC Bud Co. <a href="https://www.theglobeandmail.com/investing/markets/stocks/BCBC-CN/pressreleases/29870055/the-bc-bud-co-diversifies-treasury-with-250000-xrp-purchase-to-enhance-shareholder-value/">announced</a> a CAD 250,000 (equivalent to $178,000) investment in XRP using cash reserves held in Canadian accounts. This move reflects the company&#8217;s strategy to maximize shareholder value through exposure to emerging financial assets.</p>
<p>CEO Brayden Sutton noted XRP&#8217;s recent legal and market advancements as evidence of why it is a compelling investment choice for his company. He pointed to global interest in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/">XRP exchange-traded funds (ETFs)</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trump-confirms-nomination-of-paul-atkins-as-the-new-sec-chair/">pro-crypto sentiment</a> in the political landscape as factors bolstering the asset&#8217;s appeal.</p>
<p>Sutton also highlighted XRP&#8217;s potential to align with evolving financial trends while driving long-term returns for shareholders.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-enters-corporate-treasury-reserves-with-worksport-and-bc-bud-co-investments/">XRP enters corporate treasury reserves with Worksport and BC Bud Co investments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-enters-corporate-treasury-reserves-with-worksport-and-bc-bud-co-investments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-treasury.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-treasury.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korea&#8217;s crypto volumes spike as Woori eyes over $300 million Upbit exit</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Deals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UPbit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455916</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Woori Technology, a South Korean venture capital firm, is reportedly considering selling its stake in Dunamu, the parent company of the Upbit crypto exchange. Upbit is the largest crypto trading platform in the East Asian country. According to local media reports, Woori invested 5.5 billion KRW in Dunamu in 2015, acquiring an undisclosed company share. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/">South Korea&#8217;s crypto volumes spike as Woori eyes over $300 million Upbit exit</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Woori Technology, a South Korean venture capital firm, is reportedly considering selling its stake in Dunamu, the parent company of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/upbit/">Upbit</a> crypto exchange.</p>
<p>Upbit is the largest crypto trading platform in the East Asian country.</p>
<p>According to local media <a href="https://www.bloter.net/news/articleView.html?idxno=627498">reports</a>, Woori invested 5.5 billion KRW in Dunamu in 2015, acquiring an undisclosed company share. Nearly nine years later, the firm holds a 7.22% stake, which reportedly has a current over-the-counter (OTC) value of around 425.3 billion KRW, or $300.7 million.</p>
<p>While the exact sale price remains unclear, reports suggest that it could exceed the current OTC market value, with a return potentially surpassing 100 times the original investment.</p>
<p>Speculation indicates that Woori is seeking international buyers after struggling to raise funds from domestic investors. The transaction will likely occur through a block deal, allowing large shareholders to transfer stocks after hours and preventing market manipulation.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, this deal comes at an interesting time when South Korean authorities investigate the crypto trading platform for multiple issues, including potential <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-investigates-upbits-kyc-violations-amid-market-dominance-concerns/">Know-Your-Customer (KYC) violations</a> and concerns over its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-investigates-upbit-over-market-dominance-concerns/">local market dominance</a>.</p>
<h2>Ripping volume</h2>
<p>Woori&#8217;s potential sale comes as South Korea&#8217;s crypto market is experiencing a surge in trading volumes, coinciding with political unrest in the country.</p>
<p>On Dec. 3, President Yoon Suk Yeol declared an emergency martial law but reversed his decision six hours later.</p>
<p>This declaration significantly impacted the local crypto market, with blockchain analytical platform Kaiko pointing out that the president&#8217;s move resulted in 18 billion KRW worth of selling on Bitcoin in the first thirty minutes. It <a href="https://x.com/KaikoData/status/1864307350745629074">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;While the selling pressure abated for $BTC it remained for other assets, most notably there was significant $XRP selling throughout the day on Bithumb.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Unsurprisingly, the vast selling activity translated into heavy trading activities on local platforms in the country. Onchain data shows that Upbit saw a 44.7% rise in trading volume, reaching nearly $28 billion in the past 24 hours. Other exchanges, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bithumb/">Bithumb</a>, Coinone, Korbit, and Gopax, also reported substantial upticks in trading activity.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/">South Korea&#8217;s crypto volumes spike as Woori eyes over $300 million Upbit exit</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/south-koreas-crypto-volumes-spike-as-woori-eyes-over-300-million-upbit-exit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum and XRP soar with $270 million inflow as investors flock to altcoins</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital asset investment products experienced their second-lowest weekly inflows in the past eight weeks, totaling $270 million, according to CoinShares&#8216; latest fund flow report. This brings the total year-to-date inflow to $37.3 billion. James Butterfill, Head of Research at CoinShares, highlighted an unusual contrast in the flows across different assets within the class. He noted [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/">Ethereum and XRP soar with $270 million inflow as investors flock to altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital asset investment products experienced their second-lowest weekly inflows in the past eight weeks, totaling $270 million, according to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinshares/">CoinShares</a>&#8216; latest fund flow <a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-211-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-2b8c701cfe06">report</a>. This brings the total year-to-date inflow to $37.3 billion.</p>
<p>James Butterfill, Head of Research at CoinShares, highlighted an unusual contrast in the flows across different assets within the class. He noted that the minimal inflow was partly due to the impact of newly launched options on products.</p>
<p>Despite their high initial volumes, options on US ETFs have not driven a comparable rise in ETP volumes, which dropped from $34 billion the previous week to $22 billion.</p>
<h2>Ethereum, XRP outperforms Bitcoin.</h2>
<p>While <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> has been the market&#8217;s standout performer over the past year, large-cap alternative digital currencies like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> and XRP outperformed the flagship digital asset last week.</p>
<p>According to the CoinShares report, Bitcoin faced its first significant outflow since early September, with $457 million flowing out. This outflow likely reflects profit-taking amid <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-predicted-to-hit-100k-by-inauguration-day-amid-record-pre-market-equities-trading/">Bitcoin&#8217;s recent rally toward $100,000.</a></p>
<p>In contrast, Ethereum has experienced a strong turnaround, attracting $634 million in inflows. This boosted its year-to-date inflow to $2.2 billion, surpassing the $2 billion it received in 2021.</p>
<p>XRP also saw a record inflow of $95 million, driven by growing optimism around the asset and expectations of a potential <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/">XRP ETF launch in the US</a>. Notably, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">XRP&#8217;s price reached a seven-year high</a> after it surpassed $2, and its market capitalization hit a new peak of over $150 billion.</p>
<h2>US, Hong Kong lead flows.</h2>
<p>Regionally, the US led with $266 million in inflows, followed by Germany with $12.3 million. Switzerland and Canada experienced small outflows totaling $26 million and $10 million, respectively.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, crypto ETPs saw a notable $39 million in inflows, driven by the strong performance of Bitcoin ETFs.</p>
<p>According to SoSo Value <a href="https://sosovalue.com/assets/etf/hk-btc-spot">data</a>, the three Hong Kong Bitcoin spot ETFs are nearing $500 million in net assets. The ChinaAMC Bitcoin ETF leads with $277.48 million, followed by the Bosera Hashkey Bitcoin ETF with $153 million. The Harvest Bitcoin Spot ETF holds around $40 million in assets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/">Ethereum and XRP soar with $270 million inflow as investors flock to altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ethereum-inflow.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ethereum-inflow.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sora Ventures launches $150 million fund to emulate MicroStrategy&#8217;s Bitcoin strategy across Asia</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sora-ventures-launches-150-million-fund-to-emulate-microstrategys-bitcoin-strategy-across-asia/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sora-ventures-launches-150-million-fund-to-emulate-microstrategys-bitcoin-strategy-across-asia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 12:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sora Ventures has launched a $150 million fund aimed at advancing Bitcoin-focused treasury strategies among listed companies across Asia. The fund seeks to replicate the MicroStrategy model, leveraging Bitcoin as a primary reserve asset to optimize financial strategies and enhance stakeholder value. The fund will target companies listed on major stock exchanges in Japan, Hong [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sora-ventures-launches-150-million-fund-to-emulate-microstrategys-bitcoin-strategy-across-asia/">Sora Ventures launches $150 million fund to emulate MicroStrategy&#8217;s Bitcoin strategy across Asia</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sora Ventures has launched a $150 million fund aimed at advancing Bitcoin-focused treasury strategies among listed companies across Asia.</p>
<p>The fund seeks to replicate the MicroStrategy model, leveraging Bitcoin as a primary reserve asset to optimize financial strategies and enhance stakeholder value. The fund will target companies listed on major stock exchanges in Japan, Hong Kong, Thailand, Taiwan, and South Korea, per the announcement.</p>
<p>The first success of this strategy is evident in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/metaplanet-continues-to-emulate-microstrategy-with-planned-62m-bitcoin-expansion/">Metaplanet</a>, a Tokyo Stock Exchange-listed firm, which partnered with Sora Ventures to implement the MicroStrategy model.</p>
<p>The results were pronounced as Metaplanet&#8217;s stock <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/metaplanets-bitcoin-strategy-earns-116-yield-for-shareholders/">surged</a> over 1,000% in 2024, making it the top-performing stock on the Tokyo Stock Exchange. This achievement highlights the viability of Sora Ventures&#8217; approach, which integrates traditional financial expertise with Bitcoin&#8217;s transformative potential.</p>
<p>According to a note shared with <em>CryptoSlate</em>, the fund aims to identify and collaborate with companies that can benefit from Bitcoin-centric treasury management. This involves structuring strategies tailored to each country&#8217;s regulatory and market environments. For instance, Japan&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/japan-to-ease-crypto-taxation-under-new-stimulus-package/">taxation</a> on unrealized Bitcoin gains presents unique challenges that can be mitigated through strategic corporate frameworks.</p>
<p>Jason Fang, Managing Partner at Sora Ventures, emphasized the scalability of the MicroStrategy model. He disclosed plans to expand the initiative to additional companies, including a prospective partnership with a Hong Kong Stock Exchange-listed firm and ongoing discussions with a candidate on the Stock Exchange of Thailand.</p>
<p>Fang highlighted the synergistic benefits achievable through a networked approach, where companies adopting Bitcoin treasuries can collectively enhance their operational and financial positions.</p>
<p>The fund&#8217;s broader mission extends beyond corporate adoption. Sora Ventures has invested in over 25 companies within the <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> ecosystem, focusing on layer 1 infrastructure and applications to expand Bitcoin&#8217;s utility. Additionally, the firm has supported educational initiatives, including hosting the largest Bitcoin utility conference in Taipei, underscoring its commitment to driving adoption and market confidence.</p>
<p>The MicroStrategy model&#8217;s success, characterized by a reported 400% increase in MicroStrategy&#8217;s share price driven by Bitcoin&#8217;s value, serves as a benchmark for Sora Ventures&#8217; ambitions. Metaplanet&#8217;s more pronounced premium—approximately five times its Bitcoin holdings—further validates the economic impact of this strategy.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: Sora Ventures is a strategic investor in CryptoSlate.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sora-ventures-launches-150-million-fund-to-emulate-microstrategys-bitcoin-strategy-across-asia/">Sora Ventures launches $150 million fund to emulate MicroStrategy&#8217;s Bitcoin strategy across Asia</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sora-ventures-launches-150-million-fund-to-emulate-microstrategys-bitcoin-strategy-across-asia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/sora-bitcoin-fund.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/sora-bitcoin-fund.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump&#8217;s company will receive at least $15 million after Justin Sun’s investment into World Liberty tokens</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-company-will-receive-at-least-15-million-after-justin-suns-investment-into-world-liberty-tokens/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-company-will-receive-at-least-15-million-after-justin-suns-investment-into-world-liberty-tokens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monika Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Justin Sun&#8217;s TRON purchased $30 million worth of World Liberty Financial tokens earlier this week, and the investment enabled President-elect Donald Trump and his sons, Eric, Don Jr., and Barron, to get paid. World Liberty listed Trump as its &#8220;Chief Crypto Advocate,&#8221; and his sons as &#8220;Web3 Ambassadors.” Trump and his family have been promoting [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-company-will-receive-at-least-15-million-after-justin-suns-investment-into-world-liberty-tokens/">Trump&#8217;s company will receive at least $15 million after Justin Sun’s investment into World Liberty tokens</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Justin Sun&#8217;s TRON purchased $30 million worth of World Liberty Financial tokens <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/justin-suns-tron-network-invests-30-million-in-trump-family-backed-world-liberty-financial/">earlier this week</a>, and the investment enabled President-elect <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump">Donald Trump</a> and his sons, Eric, Don Jr., and Barron, to get paid.</p>
<p>World Liberty listed Trump as its &#8220;Chief Crypto Advocate,&#8221; and his sons as &#8220;Web3 Ambassadors.” Trump and his family have been promoting World Liberty Financial for months, claiming that it can &#8220;make finance great again.&#8221;</p>
<p>World Liberty set out to sell $300 million worth of tokens to raise funding but until Sun&#8217;s investment, it was failing. It had sold only $21 million worth of tokens, achieving merely 7% of its target until Sun tipped the scales.</p>
<p>Now, since the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/donald-trumps-world-liberty-will-limit-token-sales-in-the-us-to-30-million/">threshold of $30 million</a> has crossed, the Trumps collectively stand to receive at least $15 million, according to World Liberty&#8217;s &#8220;Gold Paper.&#8221;</p>
<p>Despite the poor reception of World Liberty by the crypto community at large, Trump&#8217;s company DT Marks DEFI LLC will receive 75% of all proceeds, as per terms laid out in the <a href="https://static.worldlibertyfinancial.com/docs/intl/gold-paper.pdf">Gold Paper</a>.</p>
<p>Upon Sun&#8217;s investment, World Liberty Financial named him as an adviser and paved the way for him to be in business with the Trumps. Sun&#8217;s latest investment can be seen as a move to curry favor with the next U.S. President, who has promised to replace SEC chief <a href="http://cryptoslate.com/people/gary-gensler">Gary Gensler</a> with a crypto-friendly candidate.</p>
<p>Jeff Hauser, executive director of the Revolving Door Project, a nonprofit that monitors executive branch appointees, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-29/trump-s-crypto-project-was-a-bust-until-justin-sun-stepped-in?srnd=phx-crypto">told</a> Bloomberg:</p>
<blockquote>
<p class="col-body mb-4 text-lg md:leading-8 break-words min-w-0">“Foreign countries and rogue business people would have never thought to be as brash in cultivating an American president as what we are witnessing in the orbit around Trump.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>While Sun has never met with any of the Trumps, he is expected to meet with Eric Trump at a Bitcoin conference in Abu Dhabi next month. Sun has said that he does not expect any favors from Trump in exchange for his investment.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-company-will-receive-at-least-15-million-after-justin-suns-investment-into-world-liberty-tokens/">Trump&#8217;s company will receive at least $15 million after Justin Sun’s investment into World Liberty tokens</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/trumps-company-will-receive-at-least-15-million-after-justin-suns-investment-into-world-liberty-tokens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/justin-sun-trump.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/justin-sun-trump.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Institutions using Bitcoin to support pension funds, adding BTC to loans</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/institutions-using-bitcoin-to-support-pension-funds-adding-btc-to-loans/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/institutions-using-bitcoin-to-support-pension-funds-adding-btc-to-loans/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Newmarket Capital has completed a loan that combines traditional real estate financing with Bitcoin collateral, introducing a novel approach to lending reported on CNBC&#8217;s &#8220;Squawk Box&#8221; on Nov. 22. The loan refinances a 63-unit multifamily property in Philadelphia and incorporates 20 Bitcoin into the collateral package. The transaction allows the property&#8217;s sponsor to repay the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/institutions-using-bitcoin-to-support-pension-funds-adding-btc-to-loans/">Institutions using Bitcoin to support pension funds, adding BTC to loans</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Newmarket Capital has completed a loan that combines traditional real estate financing with Bitcoin collateral, introducing a novel approach to lending <a href="https://x.com/FieldNas/status/1859953035029651571">reported</a> on CNBC&#8217;s &#8220;Squawk Box&#8221; on Nov. 22. The loan refinances a 63-unit multifamily property in Philadelphia and incorporates 20 Bitcoin into the collateral package.</p>
<p>The transaction allows the property&#8217;s sponsor to repay the existing mortgage, fund capital improvements, and add Bitcoin to the loan&#8217;s collateral. Andrew Hohns, founder of Newmarket Capital, explained that this fusion of assets provides better protection for lenders compared to traditional loans backed solely by real estate. &#8220;By combining the Bitcoin with credit, we can express a medium-term view on Bitcoin while enhancing the loan&#8217;s security,&#8221; Hohns said on CNBC.</p>
<p>The loan has a term of ten years, with the Bitcoin held in escrow for a minimum of four years. Borrowers can repay the loan at any time without penalty, a feature uncommon in commercial financing. If repaid before four years, the property is released, but the Bitcoin remains as collateral until the minimum hold period ends.</p>
<p>Hohns highlighted that this structure could benefit pension funds facing asset-liability mismatches. &#8220;Pensions have been reaching for risk in high-yield, leveraged, or niche strategies,&#8221; he noted.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;By fusing high-quality credit with Bitcoin, we offer an attractive return per unit of risk without relying on traditional high-risk investments.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The approach assumes a long-term positive trajectory for Bitcoin, mitigating concerns about its short-term volatility. Historical data suggests that over four-year periods, Bitcoin&#8217;s returns have been consistently positive. &#8220;For a four-year hold period, the worst-ever return has been just over 23%,&#8221; Hohns stated. This potential growth can help close funding gaps in pension portfolios when combined with stable credit assets.</p>
<p>The loan&#8217;s structure also addresses fiduciaries&#8217; challenges with inflation and asset diversification. By integrating <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a>, the loan offers exposure to an asset class that may outpace inflation over time. This could provide a hedge against the eroding purchasing power that affects traditional fixed-income investments.</p>
<p>Per CNBC, this fusion of assets represents a shift in how traditional finance views and utilizes cryptocurrencies. It signals a growing acceptance of Bitcoin as a viable component in complex financial transactions, potentially influencing future lending practices.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/institutions-using-bitcoin-to-support-pension-funds-adding-btc-to-loans/">Institutions using Bitcoin to support pension funds, adding BTC to loans</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/institutions-using-bitcoin-to-support-pension-funds-adding-btc-to-loans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/institutional-adoption-bitcoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/institutional-adoption-bitcoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto funds see $2.2 billion inflow, pushing 2024 total to $33.5 billion</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-funds-see-2-2-billion-inflows-pushing-2024-total-to-33-5-billion/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-funds-see-2-2-billion-inflows-pushing-2024-total-to-33-5-billion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blackrock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinshares]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, digital asset investment products saw $2.2 billion in inflows, reflecting a broader market uptrend driven by Donald Trump&#8217;s recent victory at the just-concluded US presidential election. In the first half of the week, inflows peaked at $3 billion, lifting total assets under management (AUM) to an all-time high of $138 billion. However, Bitcoin&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-funds-see-2-2-billion-inflows-pushing-2024-total-to-33-5-billion/">Crypto funds see $2.2 billion inflow, pushing 2024 total to $33.5 billion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week, digital asset investment products saw $2.2 billion in inflows, reflecting a broader market uptrend driven by Donald Trump&#8217;s recent victory at the just-concluded US presidential election.</p>
<p>In the first half of the week, inflows peaked at $3 billion, lifting total assets under management (AUM) to an all-time high of $138 billion. However, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> record price performance during the period prompted an outflow of around $866 million, resulting in a net inflow of $2.2 billion.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-209-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-da70460ee4f3">CoinShares</a>, this inflow pushed the totals since the September interest rate cut to $11.7 billion, bringing the year-to-date total to $33.5 billion.</p>
<p>James Butterfill, Head of Research at CoinShares, explained that:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;This recent surge in activity appears to be driven by a combination of looser monetary policy and the Republican party’s clean sweep in the recent US elections.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>US-Bitcoin ETFs continue to dominate</h2>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s dominance remained strong, with $1.48 billion in inflows. The substantial flows can be linked to the impressive performance of the US-based spot exchange-traded fund (ETF) products, which continue to attract significant attention from retail and institutional traders.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453499" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453499" style="width: 856px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453499" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154152.jpg" alt="Bitcoin ETFs Flows" width="856" height="517" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154152.jpg 856w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154152-300x181.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154152-768x464.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 856px) 100vw, 856px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453499" class="wp-caption-text">Flows by Asset Management Firms (Source: CoinShares)</figcaption></figure>
<p>According to CoinShares data, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/blackrock-etf-brings-in-over-3-billion-in-5-days-after-new-230-million-inflow/">BlackRock&#8217;s IBIT</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/fidelity-wise-origin-bitcoin-trust/">Fidelity&#8217;s FBTC</a> saw inflows of $2.1 billion and $4 million, respectively. On the other hand, outflows of $153 million from the Ark 21 Shares fund outstripped those of Grayscale, which stood at $108 million for the week.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bitcoin&#8217;s record-breaking price performance above the $90,000 mark has attracted bearish traders, who invested $49 million in short Bitcoin products.</p>
<p>Moreover, the bullish market sentiment appeared to influence interest in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a>, which also attracted significant inflows of $646 million (equivalent to 5% of its AUM). Butterfill linked this inflow to election results and a proposed <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereums-beam-chain-proposal-promises-streamlined-staking-and-enhanced-security/">Beam Chain network upgrade</a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_453497" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-453497" style="width: 912px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-453497" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154021.jpg" alt="Crypto Asset Flows" width="912" height="607" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154021.jpg 912w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154021-300x200.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-18-154021-768x511.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 912px) 100vw, 912px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-453497" class="wp-caption-text">Crypto Asset Flows. (Source: CoinShares)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Other assets, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a>, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/cardano/">Cardano</a>, saw more modest inflows of $24 million, $4.3 million, and $3.4 million, respectively.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-funds-see-2-2-billion-inflows-pushing-2024-total-to-33-5-billion/">Crypto funds see $2.2 billion inflow, pushing 2024 total to $33.5 billion</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-funds-see-2-2-billion-inflows-pushing-2024-total-to-33-5-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcon-inflow-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcon-inflow-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VanEck introduces SUI ETN to European investors as token hits all-time high</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-introduces-sui-etn-to-european-investors-as-token-hits-all-time-high/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-introduces-sui-etn-to-european-investors-as-token-hits-all-time-high/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sui]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VanEck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452802</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>VanEck, a global asset management firm and US spot Bitcoin ETF issuer has launched a new exchange-traded note (ETN) tied to the SUI token from the Sui blockchain network, according to a Nov. 13 statement. The ETN, now available on Euronext Amsterdam and Euronext Paris, allows European investors in over 15 countries to gain exposure [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-introduces-sui-etn-to-european-investors-as-token-hits-all-time-high/">VanEck introduces SUI ETN to European investors as token hits all-time high</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vaneck/">VanEck</a>, a global asset management firm and US spot Bitcoin ETF issuer has launched a new exchange-traded note (ETN) tied to the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/sui/">SUI</a> token from the Sui blockchain network, according to a Nov. 13 <a href="https://www.vaneck.com/globalassets/home/media/managedassets/etf-europe/news-and-media/press-room/en_vaneck_pm_vsui.pdf">statement</a>.</p>
<p>The ETN, now available on Euronext Amsterdam and Euronext Paris, allows European investors in over 15 countries to gain exposure to SUI without directly holding the asset.</p>
<p>The product tracks the MarketVector Sui Network VWAP Close Index and is fully backed by SUI tokens held with Liechtenstein&#8217;s Bank Frick. It has a total expense ratio of 1.5%.</p>
<p>VanEck&#8217;s SUI ETN comes as the digital asset has experienced increasing massive adoption that has pushed its value to a new all-time high of $3.31, according to <em>CryptoSlate&#8217;s</em> data.</p>
<h2>Why SUI?</h2>
<p>VanEck explained that it selected Sui for its ETN due to the blockchain&#8217;s high performance and user-friendly design.</p>
<p>Sui, a decentralized smart contract platform, aims to process transactions quickly and efficiently. Unlike older blockchains like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a>, which process transactions sequentially and often incur delays and high costs, Sui can handle multiple transactions simultaneously. This capability makes Sui ideal for applications requiring real-time transactions, such as financial services and gaming.</p>
<p>In an earlier November <a href="https://www.vaneck.com/se/en/blog/digital-assets/exploring-sui-the-layer-1-ready-for-mass-adoption/">report</a>, VanEck stated that Sui provides a familiar user experience to most internet users because it is &#8220;fast, user-friendly, and affordable as platforms like Facebook, Twitter, and Robinhood.&#8221;</p>
<p>Menno Martens, Crypto Product Manager at VanEck Europe, emphasized Sui&#8217;s scalability and cost-effectiveness. He added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;In our view, this network has strong growth potential, because its consistently low transaction costs make it a real alternative to older blockchains. The VanEck Sui ETN gives investors the opportunity to participate in the development of this promising blockchain network in an exchange-traded and comparatively simple way.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, the Sui ETN expands VanEck&#8217;s crypto product portfolio, which already includes Bitcoin, Ethereum, Polkadot, and Solana offerings. These products are designed to provide straightforward access to the fast-evolving crypto market.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-introduces-sui-etn-to-european-investors-as-token-hits-all-time-high/">VanEck introduces SUI ETN to European investors as token hits all-time high</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-introduces-sui-etn-to-european-investors-as-token-hits-all-time-high/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/sui-eu-etn-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/sui-eu-etn-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital asset funds hit record $31.3B inflows as Bitcoin leads the charge</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/digital-asset-funds-hit-record-31-3b-inflows-as-bitcoin-leads-the-charge/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/digital-asset-funds-hit-record-31-3b-inflows-as-bitcoin-leads-the-charge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 16:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452452</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital asset funds saw inflows of $1.2 billion last week, marking a fifth straight week of positive momentum, according to crypto asset manager CoinShares. The increase pushed year-to-date inflows to an unprecedented $31.3 billion, bringing global assets under management to a record $116 billion. CoinShares&#8217; head of research, James Butterfill, highlighted that trading volumes for [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/digital-asset-funds-hit-record-31-3b-inflows-as-bitcoin-leads-the-charge/">Digital asset funds hit record $31.3B inflows as Bitcoin leads the charge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital asset funds saw inflows of $1.2 billion last week, marking a fifth straight week of positive momentum, according to crypto asset manager CoinShares.</p>
<p>The increase pushed year-to-date inflows to an unprecedented $31.3 billion, bringing global assets under management to a record $116 billion.</p>
<p>CoinShares&#8217; head of research, James Butterfill, highlighted that trading volumes for exchange-traded products (ETPs) jumped to $20 billion during this period—their highest level since April.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin and US lead inflows</h2>
<p>CoinShares reported that Bitcoin captured $1.8 billion in inflows last week, contributing to a $9 billion influx since the Federal Reserve&#8217;s interest rate cut in September.</p>
<p>Butterfill attributed this momentum to favorable macroeconomic conditions and significant changes in the US political landscape that bolstered investors&#8217; confidence in the market. He <a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-208-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-20c547f8f8ef">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;A combination of a supportive macro environment and seismic shifts in the US political system being the likely reason for such supportive investor sentiment.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Notably, US-based funds accounted for $1.95 billion of the $1.98 billion in inflows, followed by Switzerland at $23 million and Germany at $20 million.</p>
<p>Notably, the US Bitcoin ETF sector remained especially active, with <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blackrock/">BlackRock&#8217;s</a> IBIT fund drawing in roughly $1.3 billion, while outflows from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/grayscale-investments/">Grayscale&#8217;s</a> products continued to decline.</p>
<p>Market observers noted that the strong inflows into IBIT indicate a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/blackrock-bitcoin-etf-surpassed-ytd-flows-of-3000-us-etfs-in-a-single-day-becomes-top-3-etf/">growing interest in Bitcoin-backed financial products</a>. In addition, these flows also point to the broader trend of digital assets gaining traction within mainstream investment portfolios.</p>
<h2>Ethereum and altcoins show renewed interest</h2>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> also experienced a surge in inflows, drawing $157 million, its highest weekly figure since exchange-traded funds launched in July. This uptick signals a renewed interest in ETH among institutional investors.</p>
<p>Other altcoins saw modest gains as well. <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a>, Uniswap, and TRON posted inflows of $3.9 million, $1 million, and $0.5 million, respectively.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, blockchain equities attracted an additional $61 million, underscoring rising demand across the digital asset space.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/digital-asset-funds-hit-record-31-3b-inflows-as-bitcoin-leads-the-charge/">Digital asset funds hit record $31.3B inflows as Bitcoin leads the charge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/digital-asset-funds-hit-record-31-3b-inflows-as-bitcoin-leads-the-charge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-etp-aum.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-etp-aum.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto venture funding hits $860 million in October, highest in over 6 months</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-venture-funding-hits-860-million-in-october-highest-in-over-6-months/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-venture-funding-hits-860-million-in-october-highest-in-over-6-months/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451628</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Venture capital (VC) funds invested $860 million in crypto startups last month, a 30% leap from the amount registered in September and the highest since April&#8217;s $954 million earlier in the year, according to DefiLlama data. Investments in the blockchain gaming sector surpassed $110 million, growing for the third consecutive month by showing a significant 75% [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-venture-funding-hits-860-million-in-october-highest-in-over-6-months/">Crypto venture funding hits $860 million in October, highest in over 6 months</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Venture capital (VC) funds invested $860 million in crypto startups last month, a 30% leap from the amount registered in September and the highest since April&#8217;s $954 million earlier in the year, according to </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">DefiLlama</span> <strong><a href="https://defillama.com/raises">data</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investments in the blockchain gaming sector surpassed $110 million, growing for the third consecutive month by showing a significant 75% leap between September and October. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The mobile gaming studio Azra Games conducted the largest funding round in this sector, receiving $42.7 million from <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/pantera-capital/">Pantera Capital</a>, a16z Crypto, and NFX.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Infrastructure dominance</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Infrastructure solutions secured the most prominent VC investments, with $609 million in venture money pouring into the sector, up 33% from September.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin-focused infrastructure provider <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blockstream/">Blockstream</a> received $210 million from Fulgur Ventures, the largest funding round in this sector by a substantial margin.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yellow Card, a startup building on and off-ramping solutions for African users, received the second largest investment among infrastructure startups, with $33 million captured in a Series C round.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Glow Labs, a firm using blockchain to create a community-powered platform to drive solar energy adoption, secured $30 million in the third largest infrastructure-related funding round.</span></p>
<h2><strong>DeFi recovers</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The DeFi sector saw a recovery in funding after experiencing a </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-startups-secure-691-million-in-venture-capital-during-september/">55% decline</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in funding between August and September, securing $98 million in funding for the month.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Solv, a platform for Bitcoin staking, raised $11 million from Laser Digital, Blockchain Capital, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/okx/">OKX</a> Ventures in October&#8217;s most significant DeFi funding round. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Variational raised a similar amount to build its decentralized derivatives platform, with Bain Capital Crypto and Peak XV Partners allocating $10.3 million in a seed round.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-venture-funding-hits-860-million-in-october-highest-in-over-6-months/">Crypto venture funding hits $860 million in October, highest in over 6 months</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-venture-funding-hits-860-million-in-october-highest-in-over-6-months/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/money-abstract.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/money-abstract.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
