<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Stablecoins News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoins/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoins/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:41:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Stablecoins News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoins/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Hong Kong races ahead with new stablecoin regulatory framework</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456302</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has moved closer to formalizing its stablecoin regulations by publishing a bill in its gazette on Dec. 6 that establishes a clear framework for issuers and marketers. Stablecoins have become useful tools for cross-border transactions, with Standard Chartered recently calling them the crypto industry&#8217;s &#8220;killer app.&#8221; Under the new bill, stablecoin issuers and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/">Hong Kong races ahead with new stablecoin regulatory framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has moved closer to formalizing its stablecoin regulations by publishing a bill in its <a href="https://www.info.gov.hk/gia/general/202412/06/P2024120500406.htm">gazette</a> on Dec. 6 that establishes a clear framework for issuers and marketers.</p>
<p>Stablecoins have become useful tools for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/">cross-border</a> transactions, with Standard Chartered recently calling them the crypto industry&#8217;s &#8220;killer app.&#8221;</p>
<p>Under the new <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-eyes-stablecoin-licensing-regime-to-bolster-crypto-stability/">bill</a>, stablecoin issuers and marketers must secure licenses from the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA). This requirement extends to stablecoins pegged to the Hong Kong dollar. Issuers must keep reserve assets in local banks, although the HKMA may occasionally allow foreign custody arrangements.</p>
<p>The legislation outlines strict compliance measures, including a minimum paid-up capital of HK$25 million (more than $3 million). Issuers must also demonstrate strong financial health, liquidity, and risk management capabilities. Activities like misrepresentation to promote stablecoins are prohibited to ensure consumer protection and market integrity.</p>
<p>Additionally, the HKMA will gain enhanced powers to oversee, investigate, and enforce compliance under this framework.</p>
<p>The initiative reflects Hong Kong&#8217;s commitment to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-adds-bybit-to-its-list-of-suspicious-crypto-exchanges/">addressing financial risks</a> while fostering innovation. Officials have emphasized that the framework aligns with international standards and embodies a principle of applying consistent regulation to similar activities and risks.</p>
<p>Christopher Hui, Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury, pointed out that the proposal aligns with the &#8220;same activity, same risks, same regulation&#8221; principle. This ensures the framework meets global standards and reinforces Hong Kong&#8217;s position as a leading financial hub.</p>
<p>Eddie Yue, Chief Executive of the HKMA, highlighted that the bill incorporates feedback from industry consultations and aims to foster sustainable growth within the stablecoin ecosystem.</p>
<p>The bill is set for a first reading in the Legislative Council on Dec. 18. If passed, Hong Kong will join early movers like the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/european-stablecoin-market-declines-under-newly-imposed-mica-rules/">European Union</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dmm-crypto-explores-stablecoin-launch-under-japans-regulations/">Japan</a> in regulating stablecoins while outpacing other jurisdictions like the US, which has yet to implement similar frameworks.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/">Hong Kong races ahead with new stablecoin regulatory framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/hongkong-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/hongkong-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Circle balances compliance in Canada with operational efficiency through staff layoffs</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Circle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Circle has become the first stablecoin issuer to meet Canada&#8217;s new listing requirements for its USD Coin (USDC), marking a significant milestone amid ongoing reports of layoffs within the company. In a Dec. 4 post on X, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire announced that USDC is the first of the top dollar-backed stablecoins to comply with [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/">Circle balances compliance in Canada with operational efficiency through staff layoffs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/circle/">Circle</a> has become the first stablecoin issuer to meet Canada&#8217;s new listing requirements for its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/usd-coin/">USD Coin (USDC)</a>, marking a significant milestone amid ongoing reports of layoffs within the company.</p>
<p>In a Dec. 4 <a href="https://x.com/jerallaire/status/1864391925312139351">post</a> on X, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire announced that USDC is the first of the top dollar-backed stablecoins to comply with Canada&#8217;s updated regulations for digital assets.</p>
<p>The rules, set by the Ontario Securities Commission (OSC) and the Canadian Securities Administrators (CSA), cover Value-Referenced Crypto Assets (VRCA).</p>
<p>The compliance means USDC will remain available on registered crypto exchanges and trading platforms in Canada. These platforms must meet the new VRCA standards by Dec. 31, and non-compliant stablecoins will be delisted.</p>
<p>Several notable crypto firms, including <span style="color: #333333;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gemini-to-exit-canadian-market-by-end-of-2024-amid-regulatory-shifts/">Gemini</a>, </span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binance</a>,<span style="color: #333333;"> and </span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/paxos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paxos</a>, have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/paxos-becomes-latest-crypto-company-to-end-services-in-canada/">exited the Canadian market</a> in the past year, citing regulatory challenges. These departures followed the Canadian government&#8217;s introduction of stricter rules for the crypto industry.</p>
<p>However, Circle&#8217;s Head of Global Policy, Dante Disparte, highlighted that USDC&#8217;s continued presence in Canada demonstrates the company&#8217;s commitment to global regulatory standards.</p>
<p>He emphasized that Canada&#8217;s forward-thinking approach to regulation enhances the integrity of digital asset markets while supporting USDC&#8217;s use within the country&#8217;s growing ecosystem.</p>
<h2>Workforce reduction</h2>
<p>At the same time, Circle&#8217;s regulatory success coincides with reports of a 6% workforce reduction within the company, Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-05/usdc-stablecoin-issuer-circle-makes-layoffs-seeks-ai-led-boost?embedded-checkout=true">reported</a>.</p>
<p>A Circle spokesperson reportedly clarified that the layoffs were part of routine operational reviews to optimize investments and manage expenses. The spokesperson added that the firm continues to invest in critical teams and infrastructure while slightly scaling back on certain roles in other areas.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the company remains focused on expanding its geographic footprint, particularly in areas like Artificial Intelligence.</p>
<p>These moves coincide with USDC&#8217;s continued dominance as the second-largest stablecoin in the crypto market. According to <em>CryptoSlate&#8217;s</em> data, the digital asset controls 20% of the market with its $40 billion supply.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/">Circle balances compliance in Canada with operational efficiency through staff layoffs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/circle-canada.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/circle-canada.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple addresses RLUSD New York delay, as XRP&#8217;s growth fuels ecosystem hype</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-addresses-rlusd-nydfs-delay-as-xrps-growth-fuels-ecosystem-hype/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-addresses-rlusd-nydfs-delay-as-xrps-growth-fuels-ecosystem-hype/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RLUSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ripple has announced a delay in the launch of its RLUSD stablecoin due to regulatory issues with the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS). In a Dec. 4 statement on X (formerly Twitter), the platform stated: &#8220;Despite some speculation, $RLUSD isn’t launching today. We’re in lockstep with the NYDFS on final approval and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-addresses-rlusd-nydfs-delay-as-xrps-growth-fuels-ecosystem-hype/">Ripple addresses RLUSD New York delay, as XRP&#8217;s growth fuels ecosystem hype</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ripple/">Ripple</a> has announced a delay in the launch of its RLUSD stablecoin due to regulatory issues with the New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS).</p>
<p>In a Dec. 4 statement on X (formerly Twitter), the platform <a href="https://x.com/Ripple/status/1864396884800098354?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1864396884800098354%7Ctwgr%5E45e267797fc22799ef0cea76eabf082e061909a6%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fcrypto.news%2Fripples-rlusd-delay-pushes-xrp-4th-in-crypto-rankings%2F">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Despite some speculation, $RLUSD isn’t launching today. We’re in lockstep with the NYDFS on final approval and will share updates as soon as possible.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Further, Ripple emphasized its commitment to regulatory compliance, reassuring RLUSD would only be launched after securing the necessary approvals from NYDFS.</p>
<p>Fox Business journalist Eleanor Terret noted that her earlier report about the NYDFS&#8217;s nearing approval for RLUSD was confirmed by Ripple&#8217;s post. She added that while two sources had <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/">pointed to Dec. 4</a> as the potential launch date, unexpected developments have led to the current delay.</p>
<p>New York&#8217;s stringent crypto regulations require companies serving state residents to obtain a BitLicense or a limited-purpose trust company charter from the NYDFS. <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">According to the regulator&#8217;s <a href="https://www.dfs.ny.gov/virtual_currency_businesses#regulated-entities">website</a>, only 33 firms have secured these licenses, including Ripple and its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-acquires-nydfs-regulated-custodian-standard-custody/">subsidiary Standard Custody</a></span>.</p>
<h2>Interest in XRP&#8217;s ecosystem soars</h2>
<p>Ripple&#8217;s delay of RLUSD comes at a period of heightened <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-warns-of-deepfake-scams-amid-xrp-price-surge/">interest in XRP&#8217;s ecosystem</a>.</p>
<p>Over the past month, the digital asset recorded a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/">400% price growth,</a> pushing its value into the top three cryptocurrencies by market cap.</p>
<p>However, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a> dropped by around 10% in the last 24 hours, falling to $2.2 before recovering to $2.4 as of press time. This price performance wiped out over $55 million from crypto speculators, according to Coinglass data.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, interest in the token and other projects within its ecosystem is at a record level. For context, <a href="https://xrpscan.com/metrics">data</a> from XRPScan shows that the number of active accounts on the XRP Ledger (XRPL) has crossed 100,000 for the first time.</p>
<p>Additionally, Dexscreener <a href="https://dexscreener.com/xrpl?rankBy=trendingScoreH24&amp;order=desc">data</a> shows that there has been a steady increase in decentralized exchange trading activity during the past month, thanks to the proliferation of memecoins on the blockchain network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-addresses-rlusd-nydfs-delay-as-xrps-growth-fuels-ecosystem-hype/">Ripple addresses RLUSD New York delay, as XRP&#8217;s growth fuels ecosystem hype</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-addresses-rlusd-nydfs-delay-as-xrps-growth-fuels-ecosystem-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ripple-rlusd.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ripple-rlusd.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Australia&#8217;s ASIC explores stablecoins, wrapped tokens in new crypto framework</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/australias-asic-explores-stablecoins-wrapped-tokens-in-new-crypto-framework/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/australias-asic-explores-stablecoins-wrapped-tokens-in-new-crypto-framework/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ASIC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC) is inviting public feedback on proposed changes to its crypto regulation framework, as outlined in a Dec. 4 announcement. According to the statement: &#8220;ASIC’s position continues to be that many digital assets are financial products under the current law. [This feedback request] is aligned to and supportive of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australias-asic-explores-stablecoins-wrapped-tokens-in-new-crypto-framework/">Australia&#8217;s ASIC explores stablecoins, wrapped tokens in new crypto framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Securities and Investments Commission (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australias-asic-shuts-down-615-crypto-scam-sites-amid-1-3-billion-fraud-surge/">ASIC</a>) is inviting public feedback on proposed changes to its crypto regulation framework, as outlined in a Dec. 4 <a href="https://asic.gov.au/about-asic/news-centre/find-a-media-release/2024-releases/24-266mr-asic-invites-feedback-on-proposed-updates-to-digital-asset-guidance/?altTemplate=betanewsroom">announcement</a>.</p>
<p>According to the statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;ASIC’s position continues to be that many digital assets are financial products under the current law. [This feedback request] is aligned to and supportive of the Government’s broader work in relation to the proposed payment services reform and digital asset facility reforms.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>So, ASIC&#8217;s proposed updates aim to clarify the classification of digital assets under current law, providing practical examples of assets that qualify as financial products. These examples include exchange tokens, NFTs, memecoins, and tokenized assets.</p>
<p>The regulator is also exploring whether to add <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/stablecoin/">stablecoins</a> and wrapped tokens to the list of classified financial products. ASIC said it seeks input on the issues arising from the potential transition to the government’s proposed digital asset platform and payment stablecoins regimes.</p>
<p>In addition, ASIC is reviewing the Australian Financial Services (AFS) <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australia-moves-to-license-crypto-firms-to-bolster-market-security/">licensing system</a> and considering new requirements for digital asset businesses. This could include the need for multiple licenses. The regulator also contemplates a &#8220;no action&#8221; stance for businesses already applying for an AFS license.</p>
<p>Feedback is due by 5 P.M. on Feb. 28, 2025. ASIC plans to release the final version of the updated framework in mid-2025.</p>
<p>ASIC Commissioner Alan Kirkland emphasized the commission&#8217;s goal of fostering financial innovation while prioritizing consumer protection. He noted that a well-regulated financial system would enhance consumer confidence, market integrity, and healthy competition.</p>
<p>Kirkland commented:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Australia’s financial services regulatory regime is broad and technology neutral. Many digital assets and related products are financial products under the current law. Stakeholders have been calling for greater clarity and in response, we are releasing our draft updated guidance.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This request follows the recent update to Information Sheet 225 (INFO 225), which provides new guidance for those offering digital asset products and services. The update also clarifies ASIC&#8217;s stance on classifying digital assets as financial products and outlines the criteria needed to obtain an ASIC license for financial services.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australias-asic-explores-stablecoins-wrapped-tokens-in-new-crypto-framework/">Australia&#8217;s ASIC explores stablecoins, wrapped tokens in new crypto framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/australias-asic-explores-stablecoins-wrapped-tokens-in-new-crypto-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/crypto-australia.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/crypto-australia.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demand for high yield makes Ethena&#8217;s USDe third largest stablecoin</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/demand-for-high-yield-propels-makes-ethenas-usde-third-largest-stablecoin/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/demand-for-high-yield-propels-makes-ethenas-usde-third-largest-stablecoin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 01:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethena&#8217;s synthetic USDe dollar has emerged as the fastest-growing USD-pegged stablecoin over the past 30 days after its market capitalization skyrocketed 73% to an all-time high of $4.77 billion. The surge has propelled USDe to become the third-largest stablecoin, surpassing DAI&#8217;s $4.7 billion market cap. However, USDe still lags behind Tether&#8217;s USDT at $135 billion [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/demand-for-high-yield-propels-makes-ethenas-usde-third-largest-stablecoin/">Demand for high yield makes Ethena&#8217;s USDe third largest stablecoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethena/">Ethena&#8217;s</a> synthetic <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethena-usde/">USDe</a> dollar has emerged as the fastest-growing USD-pegged stablecoin over the past 30 days after its market capitalization skyrocketed 73% to an all-time high of $4.77 billion.</p>
<p>The surge <span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px">has propelled USDe to become the third-largest stablecoin, surpassing DAI&#8217;s $4.7 billion market cap. However, USDe still lags behind Tether&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tether/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDT</a> at $135 billion and Circle&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/usd-coin/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">USDC</a></span> at $40 billion.</p>
<p>Ethena Labs co-founder and CEO Guy Young <a href="https://x.com/leptokurtic_/status/1863574657594778090">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We are beginning to now see the effects as USDe blackholes every stablecoin in DeFi while warping lending markets to a new base rate However it has become evident that DeFi is insufficiently sized at the moment to close the arb entirely and larger pools of capital are required The next step for Ethena is plugging directly to $100b-1tn+ asset managers who can provide the capital required.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, the rapid growth mirrors the momentum seen earlier this year when USDe&#8217;s market cap hit the $3 billion mark just four months after its public launch in February.</p>
<h2>What is driving USDe&#8217;s growth</h2>
<p>Market observers pointed out that USDe&#8217;s surge reflects strong dynamics fueled by bullish sentiment and demand for alternative yield-bearing assets.</p>
<p>Unlike USDT and USDC, which are widely used for transactions, the majority of USDe tokens are held to earn rewards. This suggests that users primarily view USDe as a yield-generating asset rather than a medium of exchange.</p>
<p>Indeed, USDe offers particularly attractive yields generated through <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> staking rewards hedged against short funding rates for ETH. According to Ethena&#8217;s <a href="https://ethena.fi/">website</a>, sUSDe holders can earn an annual percentage yield (APY) of 29%.</p>
<p>Notably, some critics have drawn parallels between Ethena&#8217;s model and the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/terra-collapse-sparked-explosive-growth-in-long-term-bitcoin-supply/">ill-fated Terra-Luna project</a>. In May 2022, Terra&#8217;s algorithmic stablecoin collapsed after its aggressive growth strategy became unsustainable, leading to a significant downturn in the cryptocurrency market.</p>
<p><span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px"><span style="color: #333333">Nevertheless, demand remains high, evidenced by the fact that its supply and borrow APR rates significantly outpace those of USDT and USDC on </span><a href="https://app.aave.com/markets/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aave</a><span style="color: #333333">.</span> </span></p>
<p><span style="margin: 0px;padding: 0px"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/aave/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Aave</a> is the largest DeFi lending protocol in the crypto ecosystem, boasting a total value locked (TVL) of around $30 billion.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/demand-for-high-yield-propels-makes-ethenas-usde-third-largest-stablecoin/">Demand for high yield makes Ethena&#8217;s USDe third largest stablecoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/demand-for-high-yield-propels-makes-ethenas-usde-third-largest-stablecoin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ethena-usde.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ethena-usde.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Former Diem co-founder says Meta’s stablecoin project was a &#8216;political kill&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/former-diem-co-founder-says-metas-stablecoin-project-was-a-political-kill/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/former-diem-co-founder-says-metas-stablecoin-project-was-a-political-kill/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 19:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Meta&#8217;s former stablecoin project, Diem, which initially launched as Libra in 2019, ended after facing significant political and regulatory obstacles in the US, according to Diem&#8217;s co-founder, David Marcus. Marcus made the revelations in a recent social media post, where he described the challenges leading to the project&#8217;s termination as heavily influenced by political considerations. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/former-diem-co-founder-says-metas-stablecoin-project-was-a-political-kill/">Former Diem co-founder says Meta’s stablecoin project was a &#8216;political kill&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/meta/">Meta&#8217;s</a> former stablecoin project, Diem, which initially launched as Libra in 2019, ended after facing significant political and regulatory obstacles in the US, according to Diem&#8217;s co-founder, David Marcus.</p>
<p>Marcus made the revelations in a recent <a href="https://x.com/davidmarcus/status/1862654506774810641">social media post</a>, where he described the challenges leading to the project&#8217;s termination as heavily influenced by political considerations.</p>
<h2>Regulatory and political pushback</h2>
<p>Libra was initially envisioned as a global payment network supported by a basket of international currencies. The project garnered early support from major financial firms like Visa, MasterCard, and PayPal.</p>
<p>However, its announcement triggered scrutiny from US lawmakers and regulators, who raised concerns about its potential impact on monetary sovereignty, financial stability, and Meta&#8217;s broader influence in the global financial system.</p>
<p>Shortly after its introduction, Meta executives, including Marcus, testified before Congress to address concerns about the project. Lawmakers pointed to risks to sovereign currencies and cited Meta&#8217;s history of privacy controversies as additional challenges to public trust. These concerns led to the withdrawal of key early supporters and prompted Meta to rebrand the project as Diem in 2020.</p>
<p>Despite rebranding and efforts to scale back its ambitions, including shifting focus to a US dollar-backed stablecoin and relocating operations to the US, regulatory challenges persisted. Marcus revealed that while early discussions with Federal Reserve officials suggested the potential for limited approval, subsequent political conditions made progress difficult.</p>
<p>According to Marcus:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There was no legal or regulatory angle left for the government or regulators to kill the project. It was 100% a political kill — one that was executed through intimidation of captive banking institutions.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Attempts to pivot and conclusion</h2>
<p>The Diem Association partnered with Silvergate Capital to launch a dollar-denominated stablecoin. However, in late 2021, a letter from US Senators urged Meta to halt its Novi digital wallet pilot program, citing unresolved concerns about regulation and consumer protection.</p>
<p>In January 2022, the Diem Association announced the sale of its assets to Silvergate, marking the end of the project. Stuart Levey, then CEO of Diem, attributed the decision to the inability to overcome regulatory challenges despite significant efforts to address compliance and security risks.</p>
<p>Following the closure of Diem, many team members transitioned to other blockchain initiatives, including Aptos and Sui. Marcus has since focused on Lightspark, a company exploring the use of Bitcoin&#8217;s Lightning Network for payments.</p>
<p>Reflecting on Diem&#8217;s journey, Marcus emphasized the importance of neutrality and decentralization in building future blockchain projects. The firm&#8217;s history illustrates the interplay between innovation, policy, and regulation in the crypto industry.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/former-diem-co-founder-says-metas-stablecoin-project-was-a-political-kill/">Former Diem co-founder says Meta’s stablecoin project was a &#8216;political kill&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/former-diem-co-founder-says-metas-stablecoin-project-was-a-political-kill/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/politics-regulation-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/politics-regulation-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple’s stablecoin RLUSD expected to launch on Dec. 4 with NYDFS approval</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monika Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 18:20:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ripple Lab&#8217;s new stablecoin Ripple USD (RLUSD) is set to receive approval from the New York Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) and may be ready for launch by Dec. 4, Fox Business reported citing people familiar with the matter. Once Ripple Labs receives the approval, it will be able to legally offer RLUSD—an overcollateralized dollar-pegged [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/">Ripple’s stablecoin RLUSD expected to launch on Dec. 4 with NYDFS approval</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ripple Lab&#8217;s new stablecoin Ripple USD (RLUSD) is set to receive approval from the New York Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) and may be ready for launch by Dec. 4, Fox Business <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/markets/ripple-poised-new-york-approval-stablecoin-set-enter-regulated-us-crypto-market">reported</a> citing people familiar with the matter.</p>
<p>Once Ripple Labs receives the approval, it will be able to legally offer RLUSD—an overcollateralized dollar-pegged stablecoin.</p>
<p>The launch of RLUSD is set to come at a time when Ripple is embroiled in a battle with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to prove that XRP is not an unregistered security. While the case is currently in the appeals phase in the Second Circuit, it could be dropped when SEC chair Gary Gensler steps down and Donald Trump assumes control of the White House in January.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Ripple&#8217;s RLUSD will become a steady alternative that is not prone to volatility like XRP.</p>
<p>Amid the absence of federal stablecoin regulations, operating under state-level regulation is the best approach for companies looking to offer stablecoins. Ripple can launch RLUSD either by obtaining a limited purpose trust charter like Paxos and Gemini or through the BitLicense, which allows crypto exchanges to facilitate trading and custody of crypto.</p>
<p>Ripple first announced its plans to launch RLUSD in April. In June, Ripple acquired Standard Custody &amp; Trust Company, a limited purpose trust company chartered by the NYDFS. Standard Custody, which already had a license by the NYDFS to offer crypto custodial services, will become the issuer of RLUSD once the NYDFS greenlights the stablecoin.</p>
<p>In August, Ripple <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-starts-testing-its-stablecoin-rlusd-on-xrp-ledger-and-ethereum/">started</a> beta testing RLUSD on the XRP Ledger and Ethereum mainnet. At the time, the company also announced plans to expand the stablecoin to other blockchains. In a statement, Ripple had stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There is a clear demand for stablecoins that deliver trust, stability, and utility. Once RLUSD is available, Ripple will use both RLUSD and XRP in its cross-border payments solution to serve its global customers and dramatically improve their experience.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In October, Ripple announced that it has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-partners-with-top-exchanges-to-launch-rlusd-stablecoin-globally/">partnered</a> with top exchanges to make RLUSD available to users. This includes Uphold, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitstamp/">Bitstamp</a>, Bitso, MoonPay, Independent Reserve, CoinMENA, and Bullish.</p>
<p>Ripple intends to conduct regular, third-party audits of the reserves backing RLUSD and publish monthly reports.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/">Ripple’s stablecoin RLUSD expected to launch on Dec. 4 with NYDFS approval</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ripples-stablecoin-rlusd-expected-to-launch-on-dec-4-with-nydfs-approval/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/xrp-ripple-coin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/xrp-ripple-coin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazil eyes prohibition on stablecoin withdrawals to self-custody wallets</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-eyes-prohibition-on-stablecoin-withdrawals-to-self-custody-wallets/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-eyes-prohibition-on-stablecoin-withdrawals-to-self-custody-wallets/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 17:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455329</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Central Bank of Brazil (BCB) has unveiled a regulatory proposal prohibiting centralized exchanges from allowing users to withdraw stablecoins to self-custodial wallets. According to the public consultation notice, the transfer of stablecoins — called &#8220;tokens denominated in foreign currencies&#8221; — between residents would be restricted in cases where Brazilian law already allows payments in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-eyes-prohibition-on-stablecoin-withdrawals-to-self-custody-wallets/">Brazil eyes prohibition on stablecoin withdrawals to self-custody wallets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Central Bank of Brazil (BCB) has unveiled a regulatory proposal prohibiting centralized exchanges from allowing users to withdraw stablecoins to self-custodial wallets.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the public consultation notice, the transfer of stablecoins — called &#8220;tokens denominated in foreign currencies&#8221; — between residents would be restricted in cases where Brazilian law already allows payments in foreign currencies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The BCB shared in a statement:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;The initiative reflects our commitment to adapting the financial system to the realities of digital assets while safeguarding the integrity of international capital flows.&#8221; </strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The move is part of the</span> <strong><a href="https://www.planalto.gov.br/ccivil_03/_ato2019-2022/2022/lei/l14478.htm">crypto regulation bill</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> approved in Brazil in December 2022, which determined that the BCB is responsible for creating the rules for the crypto industry in the country.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The public consultation will be open until Feb. 28, 2025, and market participants can share their opinions with the regulator. However, the BCB can override the inputs and do as described in the document.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Balancing regulations</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the Brazilian central bank, the proposed rules aim to enhance legal certainty for businesses and individuals while fostering competition and efficiency in the foreign exchange market.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The proposed regulation outlines three core activities for virtual asset services providers operating in the foreign exchange market: facilitating international payments and transfers via crypto, providing exchange or custody services for tokens denominated in Brazilian reais for non-residents, and managing transactions involving tokens pegged to foreign currencies.  </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition, crypto investments, whether inbound or outbound, would be subject to the same regulatory standards as traditional investments. External credit, direct foreign investment, and Brazilian capital abroad involving crypto would require compliance with existing international capital regulations.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Under the public consultation, centralized exchanges must also get a foreign exchange license to offer stablecoin-related services.</span></p>
<h2><strong>A significant market</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to data from Brazil&#8217;s Internal Revenue Service (RFB)</span> <strong><a href="https://www.gov.br/receitafederal/pt-br/assuntos/orientacao-tributaria/declaracoes-e-demonstrativos/criptoativos/arquivos/criptoativos_dados_abertos_20241113.pdf">published</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Nov. 13, nearly 4.4 million Brazilians transferred $4.2 billion in crypto in September.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stablecoins represented 71.4% of all the value transferred during the month, with roughly $3 billion transacted. Tether USD (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tether/">USDT</a>) dominated with $2.77 billion moved by Brazilian crypto investors.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-eyes-prohibition-on-stablecoin-withdrawals-to-self-custody-wallets/">Brazil eyes prohibition on stablecoin withdrawals to self-custody wallets</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-eyes-prohibition-on-stablecoin-withdrawals-to-self-custody-wallets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/brazil.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/brazil.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase to halt USDC earn program on MiCA compliant regions</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-to-halt-usdc-earn-program-on-mica-compliant-regions/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-to-halt-usdc-earn-program-on-mica-compliant-regions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 22:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase will halt rewards for USD Coin (USDC) holders located in the European Economic Area (EEA) on Dec. 1 due to the upcoming Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) regulation, according to an email sent to customers on Nov. 28. The exchange said the move is a result of the new requirements for e-money tokens, which is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-to-halt-usdc-earn-program-on-mica-compliant-regions/">Coinbase to halt USDC earn program on MiCA compliant regions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> will halt rewards for USD Coin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/usd-coin/">USDC</a>) holders located in the European Economic Area (EEA) on Dec. 1 due to the upcoming Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) regulation, according to an email sent to customers on Nov. 28.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The exchange said the move is a result of the new requirements for e-money tokens, which is how stablecoins are labeled under MiCA. Users will continue accruing yield with their USDC balances until Nov. 30, with the value paid within the first 10 business days of December.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Coinbase&#8217;s USDC rewards program is available in over 100 jurisdictions. It generates daily yields over users&#8217; USDC balances in the exchange, and the annual percentage yield (APY) varies depending on the user&#8217;s location.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Run for compliance</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The MiCA rules for stablecoins have prompted multiple crypto firms in the EEA to make moves to adapt to the evolving landscape. Coinbase revealed in early October that</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-mica-alignment-in-europe-to-delist-major-stablecoins-like-tethers-usdt/">it plans to remove</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> all non-compliant stablecoins from its platform in jurisdictions where MiCA is effective.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitstamp</span> <strong><a href="https://blog.bitstamp.net/post/bitstamp-confirms-changes-to-accord-with-mica-regulation/">delisted</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Tether&#8217;s euro-pegged stablecoin <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/tether/">Tether</a> EURt (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tether-eurt/">EURt</a>) for not meeting MiCA requirements, while Binance decided </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-to-limit-unregulated-stablecoins-in-eu-ahead-of-new-crypto-rules/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>limit services</strong></a> related to unregulated stablecoins in June</span>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Stablecoin issuer Tether has also made moves to ensure regulatory compliance. On Nov. 18, the crypto company</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-invests-in-dutch-firm-to-launch-mica-compliant-stablecoins/">invested in the Dutch fintech Quantoz</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> to boost the creation of MiCA-compliant stablecoins EURQ and USDQ.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, Tether</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-to-focus-on-hadron-as-it-exits-eurt-amid-regulatory-challenges-in-europe/">announced</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Nov. 27 that it would halt support of its euro-pegged stablecoin EURt. Holders can redeem the tokens until Nov. 27, 2025.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tether CEO Paolo Ardoino said the company will focus on other initiatives until a &#8220;more risk-averse regulatory framework&#8221; exists in Europe. He added that MiCA represents potential banking systemic risks.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-to-halt-usdc-earn-program-on-mica-compliant-regions/">Coinbase to halt USDC earn program on MiCA compliant regions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-to-halt-usdc-earn-program-on-mica-compliant-regions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/usdc-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/usdc-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Standard Chartered calls stablecoins crypto&#8217;s first &#8216;killer app&#8217;</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 12:39:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>According to a Standard Chartered report, stablecoins are shifting from initial use in crypto exchanges to broader applications in global finance. The study indicates that stablecoins are increasingly used for purposes akin to traditional finance, such as saving and transacting in U.S. dollars and facilitating cross-border payments. Standard Chartered comments on how stablecoins&#8217; dominant use [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/">Standard Chartered calls stablecoins crypto&#8217;s first &#8216;killer app&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to a Standard Chartered <a href="https://www.sc.com/en/corporate-investment-banking/stablecoins/">report</a>, stablecoins are shifting from initial use in crypto exchanges to broader applications in global finance.</p>
<p>The study indicates that stablecoins are increasingly used for purposes akin to traditional finance, such as saving and transacting in U.S. dollars and facilitating cross-border payments.</p>
<p>Standard Chartered comments on how stablecoins&#8217; dominant use case is evolving.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;There is growing evidence of increasing stablecoin use for a variety of purposes akin to those provided in traditional finance.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>According to the report, one significant factor driving this shift is the demand for faster and more accessible cross-border transactions. Traditional correspondent banking systems have limitations, especially in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/usdt-or-usdc-key-considerations-when-choosing-a-stablecoin/">emerging markets</a> with declining access. Stablecoins offer a solution by enabling the transfer of digital dollar assets at speeds comparable to email, bypassing the slow and sometimes unreliable traditional systems.</p>
<p>The report highlights that stablecoins are now being adopted for saving in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/circle-ceo-sees-stablecoins-as-linchpin-for-global-trade/">USD terms</a>, transacting in USD, and cross-border USD-to-USD transactions. A survey cited in the study found that in countries like Brazil, Turkey, Nigeria, India, and Indonesia, 69% of respondents use stablecoins for currency substitution, 39% for paying for goods and services, and another 39% for cross-border payments.</p>
<p>While U.S. dollar-pegged stablecoins dominate the market, accounting for 99.3% of the market capitalization, there&#8217;s a growing interest in non-USD stablecoins. The emergence of stablecoins linked to other national currencies, such as the Turkish lira, indicates a potential shift towards more diverse offerings in the stablecoin ecosystem.</p>
<p>The report also notes that the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/stablecoin-market-cap-hits-new-ath-after-more-than-2-years/">stablecoin</a> market cap is currently $163 billion, which is small compared to the overall financial markets but has significant room for growth. The potential for expansion is tied to regulatory developments. The report suggests,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We expect this use case to continue to grow, particularly if U.S. stablecoin regulation is passed, as now looks likely under a Trump administration.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Standard Chartered argues that the growing adoption of stablecoins for real-world applications highlights their role as a &#8220;first killer app&#8221; in digital assets. They provide an alternative for the unbanked and offer efficiencies in cross-border transactions that traditional systems have yet to match.</p>
<figure id="attachment_455103" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-455103" style="width: 1024px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-large wp-image-455103" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-28-at-12.50.36-1024x615.png" alt="Stablecoin usage (Source: Standard Chartered)" width="1024" height="615" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-28-at-12.50.36-1024x615.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-28-at-12.50.36-300x180.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-28-at-12.50.36-768x461.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-28-at-12.50.36-1536x923.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/Screenshot-2024-11-28-at-12.50.36.png 1548w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-455103" class="wp-caption-text">Stablecoin usage (Source: Standard Chartered)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Per the Standard Chartered report, the future of stablecoins appears <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/tether-invests-in-dutch-firm-to-launch-mica-compliant-stablecoins/">promising</a>, with opportunities for increased adoption in both developed and emerging markets. The combination of technological advancement and regulatory support may position stablecoins as a significant component of the global financial infrastructure.</p>
<p>Standard Chartered has been bullish on Bitcoin and the broader crypto market recently, recommending investors purchase Bitcoin below $60,000 regardless of this month&#8217;s election outcome. With Bitcoin rallying toward $100,000, investors who followed this advice have garnered considerable returns in a short period.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/">Standard Chartered calls stablecoins crypto&#8217;s first &#8216;killer app&#8217;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/standard-chartered-stablecoin.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/standard-chartered-stablecoin.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
