<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>BTC Halving News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/btc-halving/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/btc-halving/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 22:30:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>BTC Halving News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/btc-halving/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Post halving, Bitcoin miners are choosing between hodling BTC and upgrading to AI</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/post-halving-bitcoin-miners-are-choosing-between-hodling-btc-and-upgrading-to-ai/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/post-halving-bitcoin-miners-are-choosing-between-hodling-btc-and-upgrading-to-ai/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monika Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 22:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After the Bitcoin halving took place in April, major Bitcoin miners have increasingly started choosing one of two strategies — either hodl the BTC they mine or gear up with artificial intelligence (AI). The BTC halving slashes the earings of miners by half every four years — a deflationary mechanism that also helps maintain the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/post-halving-bitcoin-miners-are-choosing-between-hodling-btc-and-upgrading-to-ai/">Post halving, Bitcoin miners are choosing between hodling BTC and upgrading to AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-cuts-production-sinks-revenues-for-top-miners/">Bitcoin halving</a> took place in April, major Bitcoin miners have increasingly started choosing one of two strategies — either hodl the BTC they mine or gear up with artificial intelligence (AI). The BTC halving slashes the earings of miners by half every four years — a deflationary mechanism that also helps maintain the hard cap of 21 million Bitcoin.</p>
<p>Public miners like MARA Holdings, Riot Platforms, and CleanSpark are holding the BTC they mine in the hope that its value will increase over time.</p>
<p>Wolfie Zhao, an analyst at research firm TheMinerMag, <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-19/bitcoin-miners-pivoting-to-ai-outperform-hodlers-six-months-after-halving?srnd=phx-crypto">told</a> Bloomberg:</p>
<blockquote><p>“By avoiding the immediate sale of Bitcoin at a loss, they [miners] can keep potential losses unrealized and position themselves for gains if a bull market materializes.”</p></blockquote>
<p>However, the strategy that is popular with crypto mining stock traders is an investment in AI. For instance, the stock of Core Scientific nearly quadrupled since it announced the signing of multi-billion-dollar contracts with AI startup CoreWeave. Core Scientific emerged from bankruptcy with a <a href="https://www.reuters.com/legal/bitcoin-miner-core-scientific-gets-court-approval-restructuring-2024-01-16/">successful restructuring</a> earlier this year.</p>
<p>At the same time, stocks of MARA and Riot, who are betting on holding BTC, have dropped by 20% and 36%, respectively, this year. Similarly, shares of Iris Energy and Bit Digital, which have been investing in AI, have been faring better than those holding BTC.</p>
<p>The strategy of holding BTC seems feasible since miners like MARA and Clean Spark run profitable operations. Besides, in a market with rising Bitcoin prices, the strategy appears to be a good one.</p>
<p>In fact, with the market rising, Bitcoin miners have again started borrowing and issuing more shares. And those like MARA are using the funds to buy more crypto, following in the footsteps of MicroStrategy.</p>
<p>However, Ethan Vera, chief operating officer at Luxor Technology, a Bitcoin mining software and services firm, sounded a warning. He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>“In a rising Bitcoin price environment, it is going to be an extremely successful strategy, but it’ll be a disaster if Bitcoin prices plummet&#8230;You will continue to see negative profits and they are hiding how bad the industry is right now and how bad their operations are by diluting shareholders and buying newer machines.”</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/post-halving-bitcoin-miners-are-choosing-between-hodling-btc-and-upgrading-to-ai/">Post halving, Bitcoin miners are choosing between hodling BTC and upgrading to AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/post-halving-bitcoin-miners-are-choosing-between-hodling-btc-and-upgrading-to-ai/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/bitcoin-ai.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/bitcoin-ai.jpg" length="1100" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why is Bitcoin hash rate so important for its security?</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/why-is-hash-rate-so-important-for-the-security-of-bitcoin/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/why-is-hash-rate-so-important-for-the-security-of-bitcoin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 10:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=424627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s hash rate is a critical metric that measures the computational power used to mine and process transactions on the Bitcoin network. It is expressed in hashes per second (h/s), with standard denominations including kilohashes (kH/s), megahashes (MH/s), gigahashes (GH/s), terahashes (TH/s), petahashes (PH/s), and exahashes (EH/s). The hash rate indicates how many calculations or [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/why-is-hash-rate-so-important-for-the-security-of-bitcoin/">Why is Bitcoin hash rate so important for its security?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/glossary/hash-rate/">hash rate</a> is a critical metric that measures the computational power used to mine and process transactions on the <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> network. It is expressed in hashes per second (h/s), with standard denominations including kilohashes (kH/s), megahashes (MH/s), gigahashes (GH/s), terahashes (TH/s), petahashes (PH/s), and exahashes (EH/s). The hash rate indicates how many calculations or guesses are made per second by mining equipment to solve complex mathematical problems required to validate transactions and add new blocks to the blockchain.</p>
<p>The hash rate is essential for several reasons:</p>
<h2>Network Security:</h2>
<p>A <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/luxor-q1-report-predicts-recovery-in-bitcoin-hashprice-over-next-five-months/">higher hash rate</a> signifies a more secure network. It means more computational power is required to alter the blockchain, making it more resistant to attacks, such as the 51% attack, where a malicious actor would need to control the majority of the network&#8217;s hash rate to manipulate transactions.</p>
<p>A lower hash rate signifies less computational power dedicated to mining and processing transactions, which reduces the network&#8217;s overall security. This makes it more susceptible to attacks and decreases the trust and reliability of the decentralized system. Fewer miners are securing the network, making it easier for a malicious actor to gain control of more than 50% of the network&#8217;s computational power. This control would allow the attacker to manipulate transactions, double-spend coins, and potentially disrupt the network&#8217;s integrity.</p>
<h2>Mining Difficulty:</h2>
<p>The hash rate directly influences the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-sees-second-negative-adjustment-following-april-halving/">mining difficulty</a>, which measures how hard it is to find a new block. As more miners join the network and the hash rate increases, the difficulty adjusts to ensure that blocks are seen consistently, typically every 10 minutes for Bitcoin. This self-regulating mechanism helps maintain the network&#8217;s stability and predictability.</p>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s hash rate, a measure of the computational power used to mine and process transactions on the network, directly influences the mining difficulty. Mining difficulty indicates how challenging it is to solve the cryptographic problems required to mine a new block and receive a reward. This parameter adjusts based on the network&#8217;s hash rate to maintain a consistent block production time, typically every 10 minutes for Bitcoin.</p>
<p>When the hash rate increases, more computational resources are being used to mine blocks, leading to several critical effects:</p>
<p>As the hash rate rises, the network adjusts the mining difficulty upwards. This adjustment ensures that blocks are still mined at regular intervals despite the increased computational power. The difficulty parameter is recalculated approximately every 2,016 blocks (about every two weeks) to reflect the current hash rate. This adjustment mechanism ensures that regardless of the number of miners, the average block time remains close to 10 minutes, maintaining the stability of the Bitcoin network.</p>
<p>Conversely, fewer computational resources are available when the hash rate decreases, leading to the network lowering the mining difficulty to ensure that blocks can still be mined at the target rate. This adjustment makes it easier for the remaining miners to find new blocks and maintain the blockchain.</p>
<h2>Economic Viability for Miners:</h2>
<p>The hash rate helps miners estimate their potential <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/research-btc-price-surge-increases-miner-profitability-indicating-market-bottom/">profitability</a>. Higher hash rates generally mean more competition among miners, which can affect their rewards. Miners must consider the hash rate and electricity and hardware costs to determine if mining is economically viable.</p>
<p>A low hash rate often reflects reduced profitability for miners. Many miners may exit the network if mining becomes unprofitable, especially after events like Bitcoin halvings that reduce block rewards. This departure can further decrease the hash rate, creating a negative feedback loop that exacerbates the risks above until the subsequent difficulty adjustment.</p>
<p>The hash rate also correlates with energy consumption, as higher computational power requires more electricity, meaning Bitcoin directly relates to energy. Unlike traditional financial systems, which can create derivatives of financial instruments that far outweigh the natural resources they represent, Bitcoin has a direct, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/podcasts/climate-physicist-sees-bitcoin-as-a-tool-for-ecological-sustainability/">unbreakable connection to its resources</a>. Bitcoin&#8217;s hash rate, while often linked to environmental concerns, is in many ways the complete opposite. It is a protection against greed and overabundance, one that harnesses renewable, waste, and stranded energy and can be curtailed to help support the energy grid.</p>
<h2>Indicator of Network Health:</h2>
<p>The hash rate serves as an indicator of the overall health and robustness of the Bitcoin network. A rising hash rate suggests growing interest and investment in mining infrastructure. In contrast, a declining hash rate could signal potential issues, such as reduced miner participation or increased vulnerability to attacks.</p>
<p>A lower hash rate means fewer miners participating, and the time required to validate and add transactions to the blockchain can increase. This slowdown can impact the usability of Bitcoin, especially for transactions that require timely settlement. It can also lead to higher transaction fees as miners prioritize transactions with higher fees to maximize their reduced rewards, and users compete to have their transactions included in the next block.</p>
<p>A lower hash rate can also lead to centralization of mining power among fewer, more extensive mining operations. This centralization increases the risk of coordinated attacks or failures, undermining the decentralized nature of the Bitcoin network and posing additional security risks.</p>
<p>Additionally, the distribution of hash rates across different geographical locations and mining pools is crucial for preventing centralization and enhancing the security and robustness of the Bitcoin network.</p>
<hr />
<p>Ultimately, Bitcoin&#8217;s hash rate is a vital measure of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/babylon-secures-70-million-to-turn-bitcoin-into-pos-security-backbone/">network&#8217;s security</a>, mining difficulty, and economic viability for miners. It reflects the computational power dedicated to maintaining the blockchain and plays a crucial role in ensuring the integrity and stability of the Bitcoin network.</p>
<p>The system is self-regulating and designed to protect against bad actors attempting to take down the network. As the hash rate increases or decreases, so does the difficulty of ensuring balance and sustainability of the network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/why-is-hash-rate-so-important-for-the-security-of-bitcoin/">Why is Bitcoin hash rate so important for its security?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/why-is-hash-rate-so-important-for-the-security-of-bitcoin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/bitcoin-hashrate-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/bitcoin-hashrate-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin miner CleanSpark records highest single mining day in April in post-halving report</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-miner-cleanspark-records-highest-single-mining-day-in-april-in-post-halving-report/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-miner-cleanspark-records-highest-single-mining-day-in-april-in-post-halving-report/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=416692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>CleanSpark has released its first monthly unaudited Bitcoin mining and operations update since the halving. The company exceeded 17 EH/s in hashrate, mining an impressive 721 BTC with a record daily high of over 48 BTC. CEO Zach Bradford highlighted the company&#8217;s monthly gains in efficiency metrics as they deploy advanced S21 machines across their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-miner-cleanspark-records-highest-single-mining-day-in-april-in-post-halving-report/">Bitcoin miner CleanSpark records highest single mining day in April in post-halving report</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CleanSpark has released its first monthly unaudited <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> mining and operations update since the halving. The company exceeded 17 EH/s in hashrate, mining an impressive 721 BTC with a record daily high of over 48 BTC.</p>
<p>CEO Zach Bradford highlighted the company&#8217;s monthly gains in efficiency metrics as they deploy advanced S21 machines across their expanding facilities. These improvements have amplified mining output and optimized operational costs. He commented,</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="color: #2d2c2c;">&#8220;The remarkable increase in transaction fees immediately following the halving has significantly bolstered our bitcoin production this month, resulting in a robust increase to our bitcoin treasury.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Bradford emphasized CleanSpark&#8217;s industry-leading scale and low mining costs, positioning them to excel in the new post-halving environment. The company has already observed signs of less efficient miners ceasing operations, which is expected to contribute to a decline in the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-faces-potential-miner-capitulation-as-hash-rate-continues-to-drop/">global hash rate</a> and a temporary yet beneficial <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/short-term-bitcoin-holders-show-restraint-in-recent-price-drop/">correction</a> in Bitcoin&#8217;s spot price over the coming weeks.</p>
<p>In April 2024, CleanSpark mined 721 BTC, bringing their year-to-date total to 2,752 BTC. As of April 30, the company held 5,739 BTC in its treasury. CleanSpark sold 2.88 bitcoin in April at an average price of approximately $64,000 per Bitcoin. Their deployed fleet consisted of 136,496 miners with a month-end fleet efficiency of 24.22 J/TH and a current hashrate of 17.3 EH/s.</p>
<p>The company is making progress on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-announces-acquisition-of-four-bitcoin-mining-facilities/">expanding</a> its Dalton, GA, campus. Once complete, the expansion, referred to as Dalton 4, will run a fleet of S21s in a 15MW facility, adding approximately 0.8 EH/s. This will bring CleanSpark&#8217;s total hashrate at the Dalton campus, consisting of four independent data centers, to 2.4 EH/s.</p>
<p>CleanSpark&#8217;s strong performance in April demonstrates its ability to thrive in the competitive post-halving Bitcoin mining landscape. With its focus on efficiency, expanding operations, and strategic planning, the company believes it is well-positioned for continued success in the months and years ahead.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-miner-cleanspark-records-highest-single-mining-day-in-april-in-post-halving-report/">Bitcoin miner CleanSpark records highest single mining day in April in post-halving report</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-miner-cleanspark-records-highest-single-mining-day-in-april-in-post-halving-report/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/bitcoin-mining-cleanspark.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/bitcoin-mining-cleanspark.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin market poised for potential bull trend resumption amid ongoing redistribution phases</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-market-poised-for-potential-bull-trend-resumption-amid-ongoing-redistribution-phases/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-market-poised-for-potential-bull-trend-resumption-amid-ongoing-redistribution-phases/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 11:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=415435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Maksim Balashevich, CEO of crypto analytics firm Santiment, believes Bitcoin&#8217;s market conditions post-halving suggest a period of ongoing redistribution followed by a potential resumption of the bull trend. In a recent report, Balashevich and his team analyzed on-chain data to uncover nuanced behavioral patterns among market participants. &#8220;The present and the future,&#8221; Balashevich stated in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-market-poised-for-potential-bull-trend-resumption-amid-ongoing-redistribution-phases/">Bitcoin market poised for potential bull trend resumption amid ongoing redistribution phases</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Maksim Balashevich, CEO of crypto analytics firm Santiment, believes <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin&#8217;s</a> market conditions post-halving suggest a period of ongoing redistribution followed by a potential resumption of the bull trend. In a recent <a href="https://insights.santiment.net/read/btc-halved-these-on-chain-metrics-reveal-the-hidden-dynamic-behind-7758">report</a>, Balashevich and his team analyzed on-chain data to uncover nuanced behavioral patterns among market participants.</p>
<p>&#8220;The present and the future,&#8221; Balashevich stated in the report, is &#8220;a mix of news&#8221; for Bitcoin. He pointed to the Network Realized Profit/Loss (NRPL) metric, which &#8220;reveals patterns similar to those observed during the peak periods of 2013, 2017, and 2021.&#8221; Specifically, there appears to be a reluctance to realize profits, a trend evident in Santiment&#8217;s latest charts.</p>
<p>While some might view this as a sign of strong hands, Balashevich cautioned that &#8220;these &#8216;strong hands&#8217; could become shaky ones&#8221; and potentially &#8220;mark the bottom once panic sets in.&#8221; However, he also noted a more positive indicator in the Mean Dollar Invested Age (MDIA) metric, suggesting that the market has been undergoing active redistribution for about 4-5 months.</p>
<p>&#8220;This suggests that the market may be gearing up to resume the bull trend, potentially leading to further redistribution over the typical 12-month cycle observed in past years,&#8221; Balashevich explained. As for who has been buying lately, Santiment&#8217;s supply distribution data reveals that predominantly smaller holders have been accumulating while whales remain stable.</p>
<p>Mid-sized holders, often called &#8220;sharks,&#8221; are declining their BTC balances, &#8220;maybe in favour of memecoins,&#8221; Balashevich quipped. He described the current setup as &#8220;where one would be warned to be cautious at least.&#8221;</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the Santiment CEO emphasized that the future outlook for Bitcoin varies &#8220;widely depending on your overall investment strategy, portfolio size, and risk tolerance.&#8221; Rather than focusing solely on predictions, he encourages investors to &#8220;ask the right questions.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The data, combined with your observations and analysis, will guide you to the answers best suited to your situation,&#8221; Balashevich advised. By examining <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoins-recovery-on-track-with-previous-market-cycle-trends/">historical trends</a> and current metrics like NRPL, MDIA, and supply distribution, Santiment&#8217;s research aims to provide a comprehensive view of the complex market forces at play in Bitcoin&#8217;s post-halving environment.</p>
<p>While the future remains uncertain, Santiment&#8217;s analysis suggests that Bitcoin may be poised for further redistribution and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoins-surge-past-72k-leaves-99-percent-of-entities-in-profit/">potential bull market continuation</a>, provided market participants stay vigilant and adapt their strategies accordingly.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-market-poised-for-potential-bull-trend-resumption-amid-ongoing-redistribution-phases/">Bitcoin market poised for potential bull trend resumption amid ongoing redistribution phases</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-market-poised-for-potential-bull-trend-resumption-amid-ongoing-redistribution-phases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-5.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-5.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin halving interest higher than ever with under 12 hours left to go</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-interest-higher-than-ever-with-under-12-hours-left-to-go/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-interest-higher-than-ever-with-under-12-hours-left-to-go/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 14:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=413475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With less than 12 hours remaining until the next Bitcoin halving, online interest in the event has hit its highest rate, according to detailed tracking information provided by blockchain analytics platform Santiment. Santiment is tracking social volume and dominance around the event, with volume spiking to its second-highest level ever and dominance reaching a new [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-interest-higher-than-ever-with-under-12-hours-left-to-go/">Bitcoin halving interest higher than ever with under 12 hours left to go</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With less than 12 hours remaining until the next <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> halving, online interest in the event has hit its highest rate, according to detailed tracking information provided by blockchain analytics platform Santiment.</p>
<p>Santiment is tracking social volume and dominance around the event, with volume spiking to its second-highest level ever and dominance reaching a new all-time high at 3.87% of crypto social activity.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413548" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413548" style="width: 2056px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-413548 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04.png" alt="Bitcoin halving social interest (Santiment)" width="2056" height="904" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04.png 2056w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04-300x132.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04-1024x450.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04-768x338.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04-1536x675.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-14.35.04-2048x900.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2056px) 100vw, 2056px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413548" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin halving social interest (Santiment)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Throughout this year, interest in the <a href="/glossary/halving">halving</a> has seen peaks and troughs, with notable spikes in volume in February and March, followed by a gradual increase throughout April. However, its dominance in the broader crypto conversation was insignificant until the past week. Interest has doubled over the past seven days while Bitcoin price has tumbled from over $70,000 to as low as $59,000.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<figure id="attachment_413534" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413534" style="width: 2068px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413534 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25.png" alt="Bitcoin halving social interest 2024 (Santiment)" width="2068" height="892" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25.png 2068w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25-300x129.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25-1024x442.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25-768x331.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25-1536x663.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.24.25-2048x883.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2068px) 100vw, 2068px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413534" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin halving social interest 2024 (Santiment)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Intriguingly, interest in the event has differed across social platforms. Mentions on Telegram are down 90% from the last halving in 2020. Reddit, however, has seen a consistent surge in halving related conversations, breaking the 2020 peak several times throughout 2024. Still, Reddit mentions have also cooled off today and are around half the level seen the day before the halving in 2020.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413536" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413536" style="width: 2058px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413536 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52.png" alt="Bitcoin halving Reddit, Twitter interest (Santiment)" width="2058" height="1272" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52.png 2058w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52-300x185.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52-1024x633.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52-768x475.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52-1536x949.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.26.52-2048x1266.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2058px) 100vw, 2058px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413536" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin halving Reddit, Telegram interest (Santiment)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Twitter shows a unique pattern with spikes in activity in May 2022 and June 2023 before a recent surge in recent days. While Twitter mentions have not quite hit the levels seen in 2020, they are within 10%.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413537" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413537" style="width: 2064px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413537 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03.png" alt="Bitcoin halving Twitter interest (Santiment)" width="2064" height="660" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03.png 2064w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03-300x96.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03-1024x327.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03-768x246.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03-1536x491.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.03-2048x655.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2064px) 100vw, 2064px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413537" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin halving Twitter interest (Santiment)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Bitcointalk forums have seen sustained yet meager interest in the halving, with less than half the interest in 2020.</p>
<figure id="attachment_413538" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413538" style="width: 2054px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413538 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13.png" alt="Bitcoin halving Bitcointalk interest (Santiment)" width="2054" height="592" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13.png 2054w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13-300x86.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13-1024x295.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13-768x221.png 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13-1536x443.png 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-at-11.27.13-2048x590.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2054px) 100vw, 2054px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413538" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin halving Bitcointalk interest (Santiment)</figcaption></figure>
<figure id="attachment_413571" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-413571" style="width: 1123px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-413571 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-152050.png" alt="Bitcoin halving Google Trends interest (Santiment)" width="1123" height="363" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-152050.png 1123w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-152050-300x97.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-152050-1024x331.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-19-152050-768x248.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1123px) 100vw, 1123px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-413571" class="wp-caption-text">Bitcoin halving Google Trends interest (Santiment)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Thus, while the total number of conversations regarding the halving has not reached the past halving euphoria, it is a more significant part of the conversation than ever before. Further, in terms of the wider world, Google Trends has the Bitcoin halving on track to break all previous records by a large margin.</p>
<p>As of press time Bitcoin has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-soars-past-65000-as-israel-iran-sparring-looks-to-conclude/">risen</a> around 7% to trade around $64,000 as the halving nears.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-interest-higher-than-ever-with-under-12-hours-left-to-go/">Bitcoin halving interest higher than ever with under 12 hours left to go</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-halving-interest-higher-than-ever-with-under-12-hours-left-to-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-interest-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-interest-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mining through the Bitcoin halving: Survival strategies for 2024</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/mining-through-the-halving-survival-strategies-for-2024/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/mining-through-the-halving-survival-strategies-for-2024/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Shane Neagle]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 09:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=410041</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin’s 4th halving event is scheduled to occur on April 22nd, at event block height 840,000. As each block, containing executed transactions, is mined, it is stamped with a block height, noting how many blocks have been generated before the latest one.  This way, block heights create a chronologically ordered digital ledger, granting Bitcoin its [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/mining-through-the-halving-survival-strategies-for-2024/">Mining through the Bitcoin halving: Survival strategies for 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a>’s 4th halving event is scheduled to occur on April 22nd, at event block height 840,000. As each block, containing executed transactions, is mined, it is stamped with a block height, noting how many blocks have been generated before the latest one. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This way, block heights create a chronologically ordered digital ledger, granting Bitcoin its mantle of decentralized transparency and security against double-spending. This also makes it instrumental in imposing the embedded halving logic on the entire Bitcoin network, occurring every 210,000 blocks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/glossary/halving/">halving</a> is there as an algorithmic monetary policy. Unlike the arbitrary central banking, halving predictably controls the inflow (inflation) of new bitcoins by cutting in half the miner BTC rewards. The very first Genesis block in 2009 delivered 50 BTC to miners. After the fourth halving, miners will receive 3.125 BTC per block mined. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The stark difference in these rewards translates to Bitcoin’s inflation rate. From over 1,000% to present 1.7%, Bitcoin’s inflation rate will once again be cut in half. And as less BTC is available in the supply, each Bitcoin becomes more valuable.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_410042" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-410042" style="width: 965px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-410042 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.25.02 PM.png" alt="" width="965" height="546" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.25.02 PM.png 965w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.25.02 PM-300x170.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.25.02 PM-768x435.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 965px) 100vw, 965px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-410042" class="wp-caption-text">The inversely proportional relationship between BTC price and inflation rate. Image credit: woobull.com</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Yet, Bitcoin halvings are just one of many factors impacting BTC price. One of the most severe halving impacts revolves around Bitcoin mining profitability. If BTC rewards become so low, would this force BTC selloffs from struggling mining companies? And if that is the case, wouldn’t the selloff pressure suppress BTC price?</span></p>
<h2><strong>Understanding the Halving and Its Impact on Miners</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To understand the importance of something, it is best to imagine its absence. In the case of Bitcoin halving, its absence would mean that all 21 million BTC would have been immediately available upon the launch of the Bitcoin mainnet.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Conversely, that would greatly diminish BTC scarcity, especially given its initial unproven, novel proof of concept as a digital asset. After three halvings, Bitcoin scarcity has proven a successful foil against fiat currency debasement, as central banks tamper with their respective money supplies. In other words, halvings paced out the Bitcoin supply and demand dynamic, allowing for adoption to unfold.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And as Bitcoin adoption increased, the Bitcoin mining network became more secure. That’s because more Bitcoin miners elevate Bitcoin mining difficulty, which is auto-adjusted every two weeks. Following the reshuffling of the supply and demand dynamic, Bitcoin halvings typically result in multiple gains pre and post halvings.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_410043" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-410043" style="width: 935px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-410043" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.26.05 PM.png" alt="" width="935" height="534" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.26.05 PM.png 935w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.26.05 PM-300x171.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.26.05 PM-768x439.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 935px) 100vw, 935px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-410043" class="wp-caption-text">BTC price moves within 500 days of each halving. Image credit: Pantera Capital</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Likewise, the very purpose of Bitcoin mining difficulty is to regulate the rate at which new transaction blocks are added to the network (~10 min), after every 2016 blocks. Without this mechanism, Bitcoin mainnet would be less secure because miners could be disincentivized from participating.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">With the Bitcoin mining difficulty, their profitability is auto-corrected. If too many miners unplug, the difficulty lowers, making it more profitable to mine regardless of cut rewards. If more miners onboard the network, the difficulty elevates, making it less profitable to secure the network (its computing power expressed in </span><strong><a href="https://www.blockchain.com/explorer/charts/hash-rate">hash rate</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, this is offset with BTC price rising over time, owing to its supply scarcity. When BTC mining rewards are cut in half, miners suffer a profitability hit. If the mining difficulty is not lowered, they must increase their cost-efficiency by reinvesting in operations’ upgrades. Accordingly, these miner cycles are called periods of accumulation and capitulation.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_410045" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-410045" style="width: 1078px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-410045" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.27.02 PM.png" alt="" width="1078" height="597" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.27.02 PM.png 1078w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.27.02 PM-300x166.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.27.02 PM-1024x567.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.27.02 PM-768x425.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1078px) 100vw, 1078px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-410045" class="wp-caption-text">At peak BTC price highs, miners start selling to upgrade operations. Red spikes denote selling while green spikes denote BTC accumulation.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the end, Bitcoin miners must carefully think ahead. Without overextending themselves in the expansion/debt department, they rely on BTC price boost to carry them through the halvings.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Challenges for Bitcoin Miners Post-2024 Halving</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As of March 26th, the total hash rate of the Bitcoin network is 614.6 million TH/s, or 614.6 EH/s. Bitcoin miner revenue per TH/s is </span><strong><a href="https://www.theblock.co/data/on-chain-metrics/bitcoin/bitcoin-miner-revenue-per-th-s-7dma">$0.10</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. To put this into context, Bitmain’s latest mining rig, Antminer S21 priced around $4,500, yields a hash rate of 188 TH/s while consuming 3500 Watts worth of electricity.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some machines are even more powerful and expensive, such as the Antminer S21 Hyd 335T. Against the cost of these machines, miners must account for electricity costs, cooling, maintenance, debt interest payments and the cost of facilities themselves. Those companies unable to perform this balancing act will go bankrupt, as it happened to </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/core-scientific-wins-court-approval-to-enact-reorganization-plan-exit-bankruptcy/">Core Scientific</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in 2022. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For individuals using ordinary PCs and laptops, Bitcoin mining long ceased to be profitable. They would have to invest in specialized ASIC machines to go against the rising Bitcoin mining difficulty and subsequent increase in energy costs. The USG, reliant on central banking and currency debasement, is well aware of this fact.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of January, the Energy Information Administration (EIA) began to explore how to cripple miners&#8217; operations. By </span><strong><a href="https://www.eia.gov/pressroom/releases/press550.php">requesting mandatory survey data</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on their energy consumption, EIA would then relay findings to the Department of Energy (DoE) to enact restrictive policies. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Owing to the swift legal action of Texas Blockchain Council (TBC) and Riot, this action has been halted as of </span><strong><a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.txwd.1172776308/gov.uscourts.txwd.1172776308.24.0.pdf">March 2 filing</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Technological Advancements and Efficiency Improvements </strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin’s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/glossary/proof-of-work/">proof-of-work</a> is the critical component of BTC value. It makes it possible for a digital asset to be anchored into physical reality via energy consumption and hardware assets. Otherwise, a multitude of cryptocurrencies could be created at low-cost, introducing noise in their valuation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">But just as energy consumption is Bitcoin’s strength, it is also its weakness from a political standpoint. Case in point, Elon Musk revoked Bitcoin payment from Tesla in May 2021, triggering a major crash. Since those days, Bitcoin mining has gone green, having drawn </span><strong><a href="https://www.batcoinz.com/p/issue-003-one-red-three-green">54.5% of energy</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> from sustainable sources.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In addition to using regenerative hydropower, such as Norwegian Kryptovault, Bitcoin miners can put excess heat to good use. For instance, Kryptovault funnels this hot air to dry out chopped logs for the lumber industry. Many smaller mining operations took this approach to heat their homes.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">Heating an entire home with <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#bitcoin</a> mining <a href="https://t.co/470jJ7PSGW">pic.twitter.com/470jJ7PSGW</a></p>
<p>— Documenting ₿itcoin <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4c4.png" alt="📄" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@DocumentingBTC) <a href="https://twitter.com/DocumentingBTC/status/1607893417555640320?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 28, 2022</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Other miners, such as Crusoe Energy Systems, attached their operations to oil and natural drill wells, using the excess gas instead of setting it wastefully on fire. On a larger scale, Bitcoin miners even help to balance the electrical grid, as noted by now deceased ERCOT CEO Brad Jones.</span></p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-media-max-width="560">
<p dir="ltr" lang="en">The <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#bitcoin</a> energy debate is over.</p>
<p>Head of the Texas electrical grid, Brad Jones explains, &#8220;<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Bitcoin?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Bitcoin</a> mining is helping balance our grid and is driving more renewables into our system&#8221;<a href="https://t.co/kGYwAkOVv8">pic.twitter.com/kGYwAkOVv8</a></p>
<p>— Documenting ₿itcoin <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f4c4.png" alt="📄" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@DocumentingBTC) <a href="https://twitter.com/DocumentingBTC/status/1632412610917285894?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 5, 2023</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the high end, Bitcoin miners are turning to the densest and greenest form of energy &#8211; nuclear. TeraWulf began its construction of the </span><strong><a href="https://www.terawulf.com/nautilus-cryptomine/">Nautilus Cryptomine</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> facility as the first nuclear-power Bitcoin mining operation. At 2 cents per KW/h, TeraWulf is looking to become the most cost-effective miner in the world.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Within the next halving cycle, much is expected of </span><strong><a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2024/03/240325172414.htm">hydrogen</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> infrastructure as the next best solution to nuclear power. However, the most common path to cost-effectiveness remains the pooling of resources in </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vertical/mining-pool/">mining pools</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<h2><strong>What to Expect In the Post-Halving Landscape</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Serving as a currency debasement foil, Bitcoin provides an out for miners as well. They buy time with debt to upgrade, in the hopes of boosted BTC price repaying that debt down the line. The problem is, only the prepared miners, with the up-to-date rigs and favorable energy costs will survive. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After all, it is they who will keep the Bitcoin mining difficulty elevated. Those who can’t compete will leave the network, making the job easier for competitors as network difficulty is auto-adjusted. According to Luxor’s base case, in the scenario of BTC price remaining within the $66k &#8211; $66k range, 3% Bitcoin miners could leave the network.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_410046" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-410046" style="width: 1110px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-410046 size-full" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.30.28 PM.png" alt="" width="1110" height="589" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.30.28 PM.png 1110w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.30.28 PM-300x159.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.30.28 PM-1024x543.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.30.28 PM-768x408.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1110px) 100vw, 1110px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-410046" class="wp-caption-text">Image credit: Luxor Hashrate Index</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, </span><strong><a href="https://hashrateindex.com/blog/bitcoin-halving-2024/">Luxor projects</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Bitcoin difficulty to reach 725 EH/s by the end of the year. This would level the post-halving hashprice at $53/PH/day, aligning with the flat case hashprice projection.</span></p>
<figure id="attachment_410047" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-410047" style="width: 1109px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-410047" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.31.15 PM.png" alt="" width="1109" height="633" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.31.15 PM.png 1109w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.31.15 PM-300x171.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.31.15 PM-1024x584.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/Screenshot-2024-04-05-at-5.31.15 PM-768x438.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1109px) 100vw, 1109px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-410047" class="wp-caption-text">From bear case to super bull, this is the spectrum that will deliver either profits or bankruptcies for Bitcoin miners.</figcaption></figure>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Presently, the breakeven hashprice stands at $37.20/PH/day, without accounting for firmware upgrades. Other companies, like </span><strong><a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5de588aa3e9c044c1ad8cb59/t/658eefda7a041b7a901d527f/1703866333433/Blockware-2024-Forecast.pdf">Blockware Solutions</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, expect hashrate to reach ~670 EH/s by the end of the year, using the 2020 halving as benchmark when the hashrate increased by 30% by the end of the year.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Keeping this in mind, Bitcoin miners should plan for long-term scalability, such as TerraWulf’s investment in nuclear power. In the meantime, to hedge against uncertainty, miners could take advantage of </span><strong><a href="https://tokenist.com/investing/bitcoin-options/">Bitcoin derivatives products</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Case in point, several trading platforms currently exist which provide exchange traded futures as the mechanism to sell forward their mining productivity. Just as in traditional markets with commodities, miners could use this strategy to safeguard against BTC price fluctuations. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">And with recurrent revenue streams, the spike in operational costs could be lessened. Likewise, Bitcoin mining companies can diversify and offer cloud mining services with enhanced </span><strong><a href="https://cast.ai/cloud-security/">cloud security</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Conclusion</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Taking all of its elements into account, Bitcoin is a marvel of both software engineering and economic theory. It turns out, it is possible to enact monetary policy and incentives without resorting to direct centralized tampering. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitcoin miners play a key role in this digital enactment. Although they have to resort to the Darwinian play of the survival of the fittest, the unknowns are less prevalent. With three halvings behind, data for projections is there to take advantage of. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The only question remains, which Bitcoin miners aligned their financial modeling with the worst bear case?</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/mining-through-the-halving-survival-strategies-for-2024/">Mining through the Bitcoin halving: Survival strategies for 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/mining-through-the-halving-survival-strategies-for-2024/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CleanSpark to add 23EH/s new BTC miners amid potential hash rate drop post-halving</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-to-add-23eh-s-new-btc-miners-amid-potential-hash-rate-drop-post-halving/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-to-add-23eh-s-new-btc-miners-amid-potential-hash-rate-drop-post-halving/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 13:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=411908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Institutional Bitcoin data provider Block Scholes anticipates a novel impact from next week&#8217;s Bitcoin halving on the network&#8217;s performance. The company believes that it may lead to an immediate drop in the network&#8217;s hash rate by roughly 25% within the first two weeks. The firm predicts this event will have a unique effect on the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-to-add-23eh-s-new-btc-miners-amid-potential-hash-rate-drop-post-halving/">CleanSpark to add 23EH/s new BTC miners amid potential hash rate drop post-halving</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Institutional Bitcoin data provider Block Scholes anticipates a novel impact from next week&#8217;s Bitcoin halving on the network&#8217;s performance. The company believes that it may lead to an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/anticipated-post-halving-hash-rate-correction/">immediate drop</a> in the network&#8217;s hash rate by roughly 25% within the first two weeks. The firm predicts this event will have a unique effect on the network compared to previous years, particularly in how quickly the difficulty adjusts post-halving.</p>
<p>Eamonn Gashier, Founder and CEO of Block Scholes, highlighted that the total block reward, in terms of both <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> and USD, typically rebounds to pre-halving levels months after the event despite an immediate reduction in rewards. &#8220;There will be 672 blocks after the halving — block 840,000 — before difficulty is adjusted, marking the shortest wait time miners have faced post-halving for a difficulty adjustment,&#8221; said Gashier. He also noted that a more substantial drop in hash rate is anticipated shortly after the halving, potentially taking longer to recover due to the largest dollar-denominated impact on miner revenue ever seen, combined with the wait time for a significant <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-rises-4-before-halving-event/">difficulty adjustment</a>.</p>
<p>In the longer term, Block Scholes expects the hash rate to continue its exponential growth, albeit at a slower pace. This forecast is based on the high miner rewards and eventual adjustments in mining difficulty to compensate for the reduced block reward.</p>
<h2>CleanSpark commits to 100k more S21 Pro Miners.</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, CleanSpark Inc. has significantly advanced its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-announces-acquisition-of-four-bitcoin-mining-facilities/">mining capabilities</a>, achieving a new high of over 17 exahashes per second (EH/s) as its recently acquired data center in Dalton, GA, comes online. The company also exercised an option to upgrade and purchase 100,000 Bitmain S21 Pros, increasing its total purchased hash rate by 17% to 23.4 EH/s.</p>
<p>This strategic move by CleanSpark, as detailed by CEO Zach Bradford, is aimed at enhancing efficiency ahead of the halving. &#8220;Efficiency is the most important variable as we head into the halving,&#8221; said Bradford. The upgrade to the S21 Pro model, which operates at 15 joules per terahash, represents a 14% improvement in efficiency over the S21 model. The company stated that this increase in efficiency supports the broader Bitcoin network by potentially increasing the company&#8217;s market share post-halving while reducing overall network energy consumption.</p>
<p>With the halving days away, both CleanSpark and the broader Bitcoin mining industry may face significant shifts with unprecedented price discovery for this time in a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-hits-new-73-6k-all-time-high-as-etf-influx-surpasses-1-billion/">Bitcoin cycle</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-to-add-23eh-s-new-btc-miners-amid-potential-hash-rate-drop-post-halving/">CleanSpark to add 23EH/s new BTC miners amid potential hash rate drop post-halving</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/cleanspark-to-add-23eh-s-new-btc-miners-amid-potential-hash-rate-drop-post-halving/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-hashrate.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-hashrate.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin mining difficulty rises 4% just days before halving event</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-rises-4-before-halving-event/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-rises-4-before-halving-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BTC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=411539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin mining difficulty increased by 4% during the past day, reaching a high of 86.39 trillion hashes on April 10. This uptick is consistent with the ongoing trend witnessed since the beginning of the year, highlighting the mounting computational challenges miners face on the leading digital asset network. The increasing difficulty has occurred amid BTC&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-rises-4-before-halving-event/">Bitcoin mining difficulty rises 4% just days before halving event</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> mining difficulty increased by 4% during the past day, reaching a high of 86.39 trillion hashes on April 10.</p>
<p>This uptick is consistent with the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-hits-new-ath-after-record-7-3-spike/">ongoing trend</a> witnessed since the beginning of the year, highlighting the mounting computational challenges miners face on the leading digital asset network.</p>
<p>The increasing difficulty has occurred amid BTC&#8217;s rapid rise to more than $70,000 thanks to the bullish momentum fueled by spot exchange-traded funds and the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/less-than-10000-blocks-to-the-next-bitcoin-halving-why-grayscale-says-this-ones-different/">impending halving event</a>.</p>
<h2>Mining difficulty</h2>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s mining difficulty adjusts approximately every two weeks after completing 2,016 blocks. This critical process evaluates whether miners&#8217; activities have resulted in shorter or longer block discovery times.</p>
<p>When mining difficulty increases, miners must allocate more computational power to mine a block. This surge indicates a rise in miners joining the network, intensifying the computational workload. Also, heightened difficulty contributes to a more robust blockchain, amplifying the energy needed to mount a network attack.</p>
<p>Simultaneously, the Bitcoin network&#8217;s collective <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/anticipated-post-halving-hash-rate-correction/">hash rate is steadily rising</a>, averaging 639 exahash per second (EH/s) over a seven-day simple moving average, according to hashrate index <a href="https://data.hashrateindex.com/network-data/btc">data</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth noting that despite the ongoing hash rate uptrend, Bitcoin&#8217;s hash price, the compensation miners receive per hash for their computational efforts, experienced a significant surge in the first quarter. This surge can be attributed to Bitcoin&#8217;s price skyrocketing by 67.0% during the quarter, far surpassing the growth in hash rate.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Halving event</span></p>
<p>Bitcoin&#8217;s upcoming halving, slated for around April 20, will slash BTC&#8217;s block reward by 50% to 3.125 BTC.</p>
<p><a href="https://nydig.com/research/1q24-review-and-look-ahead">According</a> to analysts at NYDIG, the event is more <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hut8-mining-ceo-says-bitcoins-coming-halving-will-be-on-a-different-scale/">significant for mine</a>rs than for the price of the flagship digital asset. They argue that the reduction in supply is relatively small compared to the asset&#8217;s trading volumes and the demands from the spot ETFs.</p>
<p>However, historical data indicates that while the halving may not trigger an immediate price surge, it plays a crucial role in shaping Bitcoin&#8217;s price cycles. So, with the current <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-opens-week-soaring-past-70000-igniting-115-million-in-market-liquidations/">positive price performance</a> before the halving, investors have grounds for optimism regarding Bitcoin&#8217;s future potential.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-rises-4-before-halving-event/">Bitcoin mining difficulty rises 4% just days before halving event</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-mining-difficulty-rises-4-before-halving-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-halving-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Runes Liquid Fund launches with $3 million investment as halving nears</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/runes-liquid-fund-launches-with-3-million-investment-as-halving-nears/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/runes-liquid-fund-launches-with-3-million-investment-as-halving-nears/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 14:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ordinals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=410554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sora Ventures, a venture capital firm focused on the Bitcoin ecosystem, has announced the successful raise of $3 million to launch a Runes Liquid Fund, a new investment vehicle dedicated to investing in liquid assets on the Runes Protocol. Investors include Bankless Ventures, SpaceshipDAO, entities from BTC Inc. Bitcoin Magazine, and Serafund. Runes refers to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/runes-liquid-fund-launches-with-3-million-investment-as-halving-nears/">Runes Liquid Fund launches with $3 million investment as halving nears</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sora Ventures, a venture capital firm focused on the <a href="/coins/bitcoin">Bitcoin</a> ecosystem, has announced the successful raise of $3 million to launch a Runes Liquid Fund, a new investment vehicle dedicated to investing in liquid assets on the Runes Protocol. Investors include Bankless Ventures, SpaceshipDAO, entities from BTC Inc. Bitcoin Magazine, and Serafund.</p>
<p>Runes refers to a new fungible token protocol introduced to the Bitcoin blockchain. This protocol is designed to facilitate the creation, issuance, and transfer of Bitcoin-native digital commodities, potentially transforming how digital assets are managed and exchanged on the network.</p>
<p>The Runes protocol is built upon an indexer-based model that extends the social consensus mechanisms first popularized by the Ordinals initiative. It utilizes a <a href="/glossary/utxo">UTXO</a> (Unspent Transaction Output)-based system, where tokens, known as Runes, are directly issued into a UTXO during the transaction that sets their initial supply, ticker symbol, and decimal precision. This approach is closely aligned with Bitcoin&#8217;s native design principles and aims to provide a more efficient and flexible management of token balances and transfers.</p>
<p>One of the key features of the Runes protocol is the introduction of Runestones, which are akin to &#8220;precompiles&#8221; for Runes. These instructions are stored within the OP_RETURN of a transaction and are responsible for facilitating the movement of Runes from inputs to outputs. They also ensure future compatibility through an even-odd tagging system.</p>
<p>The Runes protocol is expected to support a wide range of applications and interactions, from intricate inscriptions that could influence the abilities of digital collectibles to facilitating off-chain liquidity pools for Rune trading. This opens up new possibilities for DeFi on the Bitcoin network, which has generated excitement within the community.</p>
<p>The launch of Runes is strategically timed to coincide with the Bitcoin halving around April 20, and the Runes protocol is set to launch at this time. Runes were created by developer Casey Rodarmor, who is also known for creating the <a href="/cryptos/brc20">Ordinals</a> protocol. The introduction of Runes is seen as a significant evolution in the Bitcoin protocol&#8217;s capabilities for handling digital assets directly on its blockchain.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Liquid Fund supports Ordinals ecosystem</h2>
<p>According to Jason Fang, Managing Partner at Sora Ventures, the Runes Liquid Fund will serve as a bridge to bring top Ethereum investors into the Bitcoin ecosystem as the firm continues its efforts to support the growth of the Ordinals ecosystem. The fund will invest in various assets, including memes, NFTs on the Runes Protocol, and fungible tokens built around the Runes narrative.</p>
<p>Fang emphasized the importance of educating investors by demonstrating actual alpha from their investments, stating, &#8220;There is no better way to educate investors than to show them actual alpha from our investment.&#8221;</p>
<p>As the Ordinals ecosystem continues to gain traction, Sora Ventures aims to expand its business beyond the initial fund to provide more investors outside of Bitcoin with exposure to this growing sector. The firm&#8217;s venture arm, Sora Ventures Fund 2, recently announced plans to convert 70% of its $50 million assets under management towards the Ordinals ecosystem. Fang confirmed that more than 50% of the fund has already been verbally committed, and the firm is actively seeking to onboard more institutions interested in gaining exposure to the rising Bitcoin Ordinals scene.</p>
<p>In addition to its investment activities, Sora Ventures has invested in over 30 companies in the Bitcoin Layer 1 space, taking a unique approach that has established the firm as a Bitcoin L1-heavy fund. The firm has not invested in any <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/press-releases/bitcoin-layer-2-conference-2024-unveils-first-look-at-all-star-speakers/">Bitcoin Layer 2</a> projects to date.</p>
<p>To further support the Ordinals ecosystem, Sora Ventures is hosting one of the largest Ordinals <a href="https://sora.vc/">conferences</a> in Taipei, Taiwan. The event, to be held in the City of Taipei on December 13-14, is expected to attract more than 150 speakers worldwide to discuss the latest developments and opportunities in the Ordinals space.</p>
<p>As the Bitcoin Ordinals ecosystem continues to evolve and grow, Sora Ventures is positioning itself as a key player in driving innovation and investment in this emerging sector. With its focus on liquid assets, venture investments, and educational initiatives, the firm aims to play a significant role in shaping the future of the Ordinals ecosystem.</p>
<p><em>Disclaimer: Sora Ventures is an investor in CryptoSlate.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/runes-liquid-fund-launches-with-3-million-investment-as-halving-nears/">Runes Liquid Fund launches with $3 million investment as halving nears</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/runes-liquid-fund-launches-with-3-million-investment-as-halving-nears/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/sora-ventures.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/sora-ventures.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitcoin Cash successfully completes halving, price leaps to its highest since 2021</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-cash-successfully-completes-halving-price-leaps-to-its-highest-since-2021/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-cash-successfully-completes-halving-price-leaps-to-its-highest-since-2021/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 10:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BTC Halving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin Cash]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=409652</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitcoin Cash experienced a notable surge, soaring over 10% following the completion of the blockchain&#8217;s network halving. The digital asset, which has been on a consistent upward trajectory since the year began, has witnessed a remarkable 23% surge over the past week and an impressive 43% upswing in the last 30 days, according to data [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-cash-successfully-completes-halving-price-leaps-to-its-highest-since-2021/">Bitcoin Cash successfully completes halving, price leaps to its highest since 2021</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin-cash/">Bitcoin Cash</a> experienced a notable surge, soaring over 10% following the completion of the blockchain&#8217;s network halving.</p>
<p>The digital asset, which has been on a consistent upward trajectory since the year began, has witnessed a remarkable 23% surge over the past week and an impressive 43% upswing in the last 30 days, according to data from <em>CryptoSlate</em>.</p>
<p>As of press time, BCH was trading at $673, its highest level since May 2021.</p>
<p>Market analysts have attributed this price spike in BCH to several factors, including its recent halving event and the current <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-embraces-bitcoin-lightning-network-to-speed-up-transactions/">bullish sentiments</a> surrounding the market.</p>
<h2>Bitcoin Cash halving</h2>
<p>Bitcoin Cash is a proof-of-work blockchain network that forked out of Bitcoin in 2017. The network was designed to facilitate faster and cheaper transactions. However, it has seen limited adoption from the crypto community.</p>
<p>In April 2020, BCH had its inaugural halving event, reducing miner rewards from 12.5 BCH to 6.25 BCH. This recent halving occurred at block height 840,000, further slashing miner rewards to 3.125 coins per block.</p>
<p>Ludovic Lars, a Bitcoin Cash enthusiast, <a href="https://x.com/lugaxker/status/1775799435227763197?s=20">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<span class="css-1qaijid r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">The halving of </span><span class="r-18u37iz">Bitcoincash</span><span class="css-1qaijid r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0 r-poiln3"> finally took place last night at 10:45 p.m. UTC (12:45 a.m. CEST). The block subsidy increased from 6.25 to 3.125 BCH. The network, however, experienced a big slowdown: blocks 839,990 and 839,991 were mined almost 4 hours apart.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Post-halving, Bitcoin Unlimited <a href="https://explorer.bitcoinunlimited.info/" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">data</a> reveals that the network has confirmed 840,017 blocks, meaning around 17 blocks have been validated since the event.</p>
<p>Additionally, OKLink <a href="https://www.oklink.com/chainhub/bch/network-stats?tabs=dashboard">data</a> shows that BCH&#8217;s network mining difficulty has spiked to its highest level since 2019 at 761,589.2. Simultaneously, miner&#8217;s rewards have dipped from an average of 0.0003 recorded at the beginning of this year to 0.00017 as of press time.</p>
<h2 class="s3">A precursor to Bitcoin&#8217;s halving?</h2>
<p>Market experts have noted that BCH&#8217;s halving might serve as a precursor for the approaching <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/less-than-10000-blocks-to-the-next-bitcoin-halving-why-grayscale-says-this-ones-different/">Bitcoin halving.</a></p>
<p>BTC is set to undergo its fourth halving on April 20, where miner block rewards will be cut in half from 6.25 BTC to 3.125 BTC.</p>
<p>Notably, key players, such as asset management firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/grayscale-investments/">Grayscale</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/hut-8/">Hut 8</a> Mining CEO Asher Genoot, have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hut8-mining-ceo-says-bitcoins-coming-halving-will-be-on-a-different-scale/">emphasized</a> that this upcoming event will substantially influence the broader crypto landscape.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-cash-successfully-completes-halving-price-leaps-to-its-highest-since-2021/">Bitcoin Cash successfully completes halving, price leaps to its highest since 2021</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-cash-successfully-completes-halving-price-leaps-to-its-highest-since-2021/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-cash-halving.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/bitcoin-cash-halving.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
