<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>DAO/Blockchain Governance News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/governance/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/governance/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:29:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>DAO/Blockchain Governance News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/governance/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Wintermute secures approval to overhaul Ethena’s revenue sharing model</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/wintermute-secures-approval-to-overhaul-ethenas-revenue-sharing-model/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/wintermute-secures-approval-to-overhaul-ethenas-revenue-sharing-model/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Ethena Foundation announced on Nov. 15 that the risk committee approved Wintermute&#8217;s proposal to overhaul revenue sharing for the Ethena protocol. The changes, aimed at benefiting staked ENA (sENA) holders, are expected to take effect by the end of November, pending the finalization of implementation details. Wintermute, a prominent market maker and Ethena backer, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wintermute-secures-approval-to-overhaul-ethenas-revenue-sharing-model/">Wintermute secures approval to overhaul Ethena’s revenue sharing model</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Ethena Foundation announced on Nov. 15 that the risk committee approved <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/wintermute/">Wintermute&#8217;s</a> proposal to overhaul revenue sharing for the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethena/">Ethena</a> protocol.</p>
<p>The changes, aimed at benefiting staked ENA (sENA) holders, are expected to take effect by the end of November, pending the finalization of implementation details.</p>
<p>Wintermute, a prominent market maker and Ethena backer, suggested the changes to address what it described as a misalignment between sENA holders and the protocol&#8217;s revenue-generating success.</p>
<p>The Ethena protocol, which supports the U.S. dollar-pegged stablecoin <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethena-usde/">USDe</a>, has seen substantial revenue growth, but that success has not directly translated into benefits for sENA stakeholders.</p>
<h2>Aiming for alignment</h2>
<p>In its proposal, Wintermute emphasized the need for better alignment between sENA holders and the protocol&#8217;s financial outcomes.</p>
<p>According to the firm:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The Ethena protocol has achieved significant market traction, yet sENA holders lack a direct connection to this revenue growth”</p></blockquote>
<p>The proposed changes include introducing a mechanism to allocate a portion of Ethena&#8217;s revenue to programs that enhance the utility and value of staked governance tokens. The foundation echoed Wintermute&#8217;s concerns and committed to ensuring that future revenues exclusively benefit the protocol.</p>
<p>In a recent update, it clarified that no portion of Ethena&#8217;s earnings would flow to external entities or affiliated development groups, such as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ethena-labs/">Ethena Labs</a>. Governance processes will determine any uses of funds beyond operational reserves and rewards for sUSDe holders.</p>
<h2>Governance and broader impact</h2>
<p>Wintermute&#8217;s proposal also called for increased transparency regarding past revenue allocations. The foundation has pledged to adhere to this principle moving forward, ensuring that all earnings remain under community governance through ENA and sENA voting structures.</p>
<p>The Ethena Foundation is collaborating with the risk committee to finalize the mechanics of the new revenue-sharing model. The activation parameters are expected to be in place by Nov. 30.</p>
<p>Ethena&#8217;s ecosystem has drawn support from major industry players, including Binance Labs, Fidelity Investments, and Dragonfly, alongside Wintermute. With this latest development, Ethena aims to strengthen the relationship between its governance token holders and its broader protocol performance.</p>
<p>The approval marks a step toward realigning incentives across the Ethena ecosystem, potentially setting a precedent for how governance protocols address stakeholder alignment and revenue transparency.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wintermute-secures-approval-to-overhaul-ethenas-revenue-sharing-model/">Wintermute secures approval to overhaul Ethena’s revenue sharing model</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/wintermute-secures-approval-to-overhaul-ethenas-revenue-sharing-model/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ethena-usde.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ethena-usde.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MakerDAO founder proposes strict deflationary tokenomics amid rebranding process</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-founder-proposes-strict-deflationary-tokenomics-amid-rebranding-process/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-founder-proposes-strict-deflationary-tokenomics-amid-rebranding-process/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 01:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451022</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Rune Christensen, founder of Sky (formerly MakerDAO), has proposed a strictly deflationary approach to the protocol&#8217;s governance token as the community prepares to vote on whether to revert its brand or not on Nov. 11. Christensen explained that the proposed changes would affect the governance token supply, whether it continues as SKY or pivots back [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-founder-proposes-strict-deflationary-tokenomics-amid-rebranding-process/">MakerDAO founder proposes strict deflationary tokenomics amid rebranding process</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/rune-christensen/">Rune Christensen</a>, founder of Sky (formerly <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/makerdao/">MakerDAO</a>), has </span><strong><a href="https://x.com/RuneKek/status/1851751635153764394">proposed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a strictly deflationary approach to the protocol&#8217;s governance token as the community prepares to vote on whether to revert its brand or not on Nov. 11.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Christensen explained that the proposed changes would affect the governance token supply, whether it continues as SKY or pivots back to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/maker/">MKR</a>.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Deflationary tokenomics</strong></h2>
<p>If approved, the proposed tokenomics would eliminate token emissions under regular conditions, transforming the token structure to be strictly deflationary.</p>
<p>The burning mechanism, integral to Maker&#8217;s tokenomics, would permanently reduce the total token supply over time. An exception to this rule would exist only in cases of significant financial shortfall, potentially jeopardizing Maker&#8217;s stablecoins — <span style="font-weight: 400;">Sky Dollar (USDS) </span>and <span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/multi-collateral-dai/">DAI</a></span>.</p>
<p>Under the proposal, the ecosystem would introduce “Star Token Rewards,” including Spark (SPK), which token holders could earn through governance participation and activation of Maker’s Seal Engine, adding new incentives for engagement while adhering to the deflationary model.</p>
<h2><strong>Distinct scenarios ahead</strong></h2>
<p>The community vote will also decide whether to retain the established Maker brand or fully adopt the Sky identity. If the Sky brand wins, MakerDAO plans to migrate the entire MKR ecosystem into SKY, rebranding MKR tokens as Wrapped 24k Sky Tokens (SKY24K).</p>
<p>This transition aims to prevent confusion about legacy MKR tokens and avoid requiring holders to make any changes to their existing positions. The switch would simplify integration, enabling MKR holders to access Seal Engine features and governance without complications.</p>
<p>In the event that the Maker brand prevails, Sky would shift into an auxiliary role as a “Star,” promoting adoption in a way complementary to Spark, which primarily drives collateral and borrowing activity. Under this structure, Sky&#8217;s token would be renamed OLD_SKY, convertible back to MKR at a fixed rate of 1:24000, or, for a limited time, exchanged 1:1 for tokens governing the Sky Star.</p>
<h2>Dual-Star system</h2>
<p>Christensen&#8217;s proposal envisions Spark and Sky as complementary &#8220;Stars&#8221; within Maker&#8217;s ecosystem, targeting both the supply and demand sides.</p>
<p>While Spark would focus on collateral allocation and borrowing incentives, Sky would concentrate on building adoption through USDS utilization. Sky would also control the Sky.money platform and operate with an Accessibility Reward system, providing incentives for projects that increase USDS adoption.</p>
<p>In its initial phases, Sky will have exclusive access to the Accessibility Reward system, while Spark will hold exclusive rights to Maker&#8217;s Allocation System. This temporary distinction aims to streamline each Star&#8217;s focus as the ecosystem grows.</p>
<p>The final vote on this proposal will take place from Nov. 11 to Nov. 14, with additional details to be released in the coming days. MakerDAO is positioned to strengthen its foundational structures, either with a renewed Maker brand or a streamlined Sky transition, fostering sustainable growth through expanded USDS and a more engaged, incentivized community.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-founder-proposes-strict-deflationary-tokenomics-amid-rebranding-process/">MakerDAO founder proposes strict deflationary tokenomics amid rebranding process</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-founder-proposes-strict-deflationary-tokenomics-amid-rebranding-process/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/makerdao-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/makerdao-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>MakerDAO unveils revamped stablecoin and governance tokens</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-unveils-revamped-stablecoin-and-governance-tokens/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-unveils-revamped-stablecoin-and-governance-tokens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 20:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=440043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>MakerDAO introduced new upgraded versions of its DAI stablecoin and the MKR governance token, called NewStable (NST) and NewGovToken (NGT), respectively. According to the Aug. 22 announcement, upgrading to the new tokens is optional, and they will not make DAI and MKR obsolete — both will continue to be available as before unless the protocol&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-unveils-revamped-stablecoin-and-governance-tokens/">MakerDAO unveils revamped stablecoin and governance tokens</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MakerDAO </span><strong><a href="https://x.com/MakerDAO/status/1826614481494962325">introduced</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> new upgraded versions of its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/multi-collateral-dai/">DAI</a> stablecoin and the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/maker/">MKR</a> governance token, called NewStable (NST) and NewGovToken (NGT), respectively. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the Aug. 22 <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/x/">announcement</a>, upgrading to the new tokens is optional, and they will not make DAI and MKR obsolete — both will continue to be available as before unless the protocol&#8217;s governance decides otherwise.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Users will be able to swap DAI for the new NST token 1:1 and will maintain the ability to revert their holdings to DAI anytime. Additionally, Maker explained that DAI will focus on crypto-native use cases, while NST is targeted at mass adoption.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, the swap between MKR and NGT will happen at a ratio of 1:24,000, which means that one MKR token will be equivalent to 24,000 NGT. The weight disparity is intended to promote broader engagement in governance. The announcement added:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“It allows more users to hold a significant number of NewGovToken and actively influence the future of the ecosystem.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The announcement did not disclose dates for the upgrade.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Push for mass adoption</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">MakerDAO co-founder <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/rune-christensen/">Rune Christensen</a></strong> first proposed the concept of a new version of the DAI stablecoin on May 15. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a </span><a href="https://forum.makerdao.com/t/reconciling-the-two-opposing-paths-for-decentralized-stablecoins/24280"><span style="font-weight: 400;">blog post</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Christensen explained that DAI is &#8220;straddling two worlds&#8221;— one marked by the culture of pure decentralization and the other aimed at fulfilling its original purpose, which is delivering utility and value to real people at scale.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He added that the two worlds are incompatible with each other. According to Christensen:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“Unfortunately these two worlds are fundamentally in friction with each other, as noted by the Stablecoin Trilemma, which states that achieving a dollar peg, maintaining pure decentralization, and scaling to large sizes simultaneously is not feasible.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To overcome this issue, NewStable intends to focus on mass market adoption and on regulatorily-compliant Real-World Asset (RWA) backing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To fulfill its purpose of regulatory compliance, NewStable will have an upgrade mechanism to introduce a freeze function, which will follow the rules of law in jurisdictions where Maker needs a high level of regulatory certainty.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, the implementation of this function will be decided by the project&#8217;s governance and won&#8217;t be available at NST&#8217;s launch.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Despite remaining active after NST&#8217;s implementation, DAI will start losing its yield offering, as NewStable will be the only stablecoin in MakerDAO&#8217;s ecosystem with value-accruing capabilities.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Endgame</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The NST and NGT tokens are part of MakerDAO&#8217;s &#8220;Endgame,&#8221; and these labels will be replaced as soon as the protocol executes its rebranding.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Maker&#8217;s </span><strong><a href="https://endgame.makerdao.com/endgame/overview">documentation</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the Endgame plan is a comprehensive proposal aimed at enhancing the governance and tokenomics of the MakerDAO ecosystem, leading it to a stable and resilient state where the ecosystem is self-sustainable, with minimal changes to its core components.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Along with the tokenomics changes, the plan’s core components also include the introduction of sub-decentralized autonomous organizations to handle specific matters, broad focus areas, and groups of aligned voters focused on high-level governance decisions.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-unveils-revamped-stablecoin-and-governance-tokens/">MakerDAO unveils revamped stablecoin and governance tokens</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/makerdao-unveils-revamped-stablecoin-and-governance-tokens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/maker-dai.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/maker-dai.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vitalik Buterin urges pluralistic approach to governance, moving past cypherpunk origins</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/buterin-urges-pluralistic-approach-to-governance-moving-past-cypherpunk-origins/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/buterin-urges-pluralistic-approach-to-governance-moving-past-cypherpunk-origins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 17:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=439804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin called for a fundamental shift in how the crypto community approaches governance. In an Aug. 21 blog post, Buterin advocated for a &#8220;plurality philosophy&#8221; that he believes is essential for managing the evolving landscape of blockchains, cryptocurrencies, and decentralized autonomous organizations (DAOs). He further urged the crypto space to move beyond [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/buterin-urges-pluralistic-approach-to-governance-moving-past-cypherpunk-origins/">Vitalik Buterin urges pluralistic approach to governance, moving past cypherpunk origins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> co-founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/vitalik-buterin/">Vitalik Buterin</a> called for a fundamental shift in how the crypto community approaches governance.</p>
<p>In an Aug. 21 blog <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/08/21/plurality.html">post</a>, Buterin advocated for a &#8220;plurality philosophy&#8221; that he believes is essential for managing the evolving landscape of blockchains, cryptocurrencies, and decentralized autonomous organizations (DAOs).</p>
<p>He further urged the crypto space to move beyond its cypherpunk origins, which emphasize independence from traditional governance, and embrace a more integrated approach that prioritizes collaboration and public goods.</p>
<h2>Rethinking governance</h2>
<p>In his blog, Buterin highlighted the need for robust internal governance within blockchain and DAO ecosystems to ensure their long-term sustainability. He argued that the community must shift from simply avoiding external control to actively creating governance structures that support the ongoing evolution of these technologies.</p>
<p>Buterin used recent examples, such as Florida Governor Ron DeSantis&#8217;s ban on synthetic meat and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/google/">Google&#8217;s</a> real-time scam detection feature in Android, to illustrate the broader societal challenges of balancing autonomy with collective governance.</p>
<p>Buterin criticized DeSantis&#8217;s decision to ban synthetic meat, framing it as an example of a tension between freedom and governance. DeSantis justified the ban by claiming it was necessary to protect local farmers from global elites who, he argued, are pushing synthetic meat as part of a broader agenda.</p>
<p>However, Buterin sees this move as an infringement on individual freedom, particularly the freedom to choose what to consume. He views the ban as an authoritarian measure that goes against the principles of freedom by limiting access to a potentially more ethical and sustainable food option.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he said that Google&#8217;s scam detection is an example of the complex trade-offs between protecting users and preserving individual freedoms. The system operates entirely on the user&#8217;s device, ensuring that no personal data is sent to external servers, which aligns with privacy-centric values.</p>
<p>However, Buterin noted that despite these privacy safeguards, the feature has drawn criticism from some freedom-minded individuals, including Meredith Whittaker, the president of the Signal Foundation.</p>
<p>Whittaker and others are concerned that even well-intentioned technologies like this could set a precedent for more invasive surveillance measures in the future, potentially leading to greater control over individuals and infringing on personal freedoms.</p>
<h2>Impact of Plurality Philosophy</h2>
<p>Buterin draws heavily from the ideas in &#8220;Plurality: The Future of Collaborative Technology and Democracy,&#8221; a book by Glen Weyl and Audrey Tang.</p>
<p>The book advocates for a social philosophy that promotes cooperation among diverse groups and offers a model for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vitalik-buterin-sees-crypto-utility-growing-in-developing-world-wary-of-cbdcs-exchanges/">digital democracy</a> that avoids the extremes of authoritarianism and libertarianism.</p>
<p>Buterin argued that a pluralistic approach, which values social connections as much as individual autonomy, is better suited to managing the complexities of the modern digital world.</p>
<p>He suggested that plurality-inspired technologies could address key governance challenges in the crypto space, such as scalable voting systems and digital identity management. By adopting these approaches, the community can build more resilient and adaptable governance structures.</p>
<p>Buterin acknowledges that while plurality may seem unconventional in a world dominated by task-oriented and leader-centric movements, it offers a robust framework for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/buterin-argues-for-blockchain-as-defense-against-efficiency-of-authoritarian-regimes/">tackling the long-term challenges</a> of governance in an interconnected digital age.</p>
<p>He called on the crypto community to rethink its approach to governance, emphasizing the need for a model that embraces diversity, fosters collaboration, and adapts to the rapidly changing technological landscape.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/buterin-urges-pluralistic-approach-to-governance-moving-past-cypherpunk-origins/">Vitalik Buterin urges pluralistic approach to governance, moving past cypherpunk origins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/buterin-urges-pluralistic-approach-to-governance-moving-past-cypherpunk-origins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/vitalik-buterin-plurality-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/vitalik-buterin-plurality-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Curve founder’s $6.3 million funding request under fire for lacking clarity</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/curve-founders-6-3-million-funding-request-under-fire-for-lacking-clarity/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/curve-founders-6-3-million-funding-request-under-fire-for-lacking-clarity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 19:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DAOs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=439551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Curve DAO members have raised concerns over a recent proposal by Curve Finance founder Michael Egorov, who has requested 21 million CRV tokens, valued at approximately $6.3 million, to support ongoing development efforts. The proposal has sparked debate within the community, with many calling for greater transparency and detailed information on how the funds will [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/curve-founders-6-3-million-funding-request-under-fire-for-lacking-clarity/">Curve founder’s $6.3 million funding request under fire for lacking clarity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/curve-dao-token/">Curve DAO</a> members have raised concerns over a recent proposal by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/curve-dao-token/">Curve Finance</a> founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/michael-egorov/">Michael Egorov</a>, who has requested <a href="https://gov.curve.fi/t/funding-proposal-for-swiss-stake-ag-the-company-building-curve/10204/22">21 million CRV tokens</a>, valued at approximately $6.3 million, to support ongoing development efforts.</p>
<p>The proposal has sparked debate within the community, with many calling for greater transparency and detailed information on how the funds will be utilized.</p>
<p>Egorov submitted the proposal on Aug. 19, seeking a substantial portion of the DAO&#8217;s Community Fund to support the continued research and development of Curve&#8217;s key components. Swiss Stake, a key contributor to the DeFi protocol, has been instrumental in developing the platform&#8217;s stable swap mechanism and governance system.</p>
<p>The proposed funds would be used to maintain the company&#8217;s 25-person team and to continue research and development efforts. However, the request represents a marked shift from the DAO&#8217;s usual practices, which have traditionally been <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/binance-labs-invests-5m-in-curve-dao-token-following-60m-july-hack/">more conservative</a> in deploying community resources.</p>
<h2>Lack of clarity</h2>
<p>The proposal has drawn criticism from community members who argue that it lacks essential details, including a clear roadmap, specific milestones, and a detailed breakdown of how the funds will be spent. This lack of clarity has fueled skepticism about the necessity and timing of the request.</p>
<p>Many members have already made clear that they do not intend to support the proposal in its current form. One influential member, who holds a substantial amount of CRV tokens, voiced opposition by stating:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Without a clear plan and detailed expenditure, I cannot support this proposal. I intend to vote against it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The proposed allocation, nearly half of the Community Fund&#8217;s current holdings of 47.5 million CRV, has raised additional questions about the long-term sustainability of such funding practices. Critics worry that approving this request could set a precedent that may strain the DAO&#8217;s financial resources in the future.</p>
<h2>Legal concerns</h2>
<p>In response to these concerns, Egorov acknowledged that the proposal represents a significant &#8220;cultural shift&#8221; for the DAO, noting that it diverges from the Community Fund&#8217;s traditional, more conservative use.</p>
<p>He explained that legal advice had influenced the level of detail he could provide in the proposal and emphasized that while the proposal might seem less transparent due to these constraints, he intended to mitigate any concerns by committing to regular bi-annual reports that would detail how the funds were being used.</p>
<p>He also assured the community that any unused portions of the allocated funds would be rolled over to the following year, ensuring that the funds would be managed responsibly and with continued oversight.</p>
<p>Additionally, Egorov proposed that any future funding requests would include more detailed documentation, aligning with the community&#8217;s expectations for transparency and accountability.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/curve-founders-6-3-million-funding-request-under-fire-for-lacking-clarity/">Curve founder’s $6.3 million funding request under fire for lacking clarity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/curve-founders-6-3-million-funding-request-under-fire-for-lacking-clarity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/curve-finance-funding.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/curve-finance-funding.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Polygon unveils 1 billion POL token program to boost developer engagement</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/polygon-unveils-1-billion-pol-token-program-to-boost-developer-engagement/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/polygon-unveils-1-billion-pol-token-program-to-boost-developer-engagement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 16:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[POL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Polygon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=425365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Polygon, the Ethereum layer-2 blockchain, has unveiled a Community Treasury initiative funded with 1 billion POL tokens, which will be distributed over the next decade to drive developer engagement on the network. According to the June 11 press release, the tokens will be sourced from 1% of the network&#8217;s annual token emissions, as detailed in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/polygon-unveils-1-billion-pol-token-program-to-boost-developer-engagement/">Polygon unveils 1 billion POL token program to boost developer engagement</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/polygon/">Polygon</a>, the Ethereum <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/layer-2/">layer-2</a> blockchain, has unveiled a Community Treasury initiative funded with 1 billion POL tokens, which will be distributed over the next decade to drive developer engagement on the network.</p>
<p>According to the June 11 press release, the tokens will be sourced from 1% of the network&#8217;s annual token emissions, as detailed in the POL whitepaper.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Polygon grant</span></p>
<p>Polygon has launched the first season of its Community Grant Program (CGP), offering developers an initial 35 million MATIC valued at around $22 million. Future seasons will provide up to 100 million POL tokens as the network <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/matic-falls-5-as-polygon-labs-activates-next-gen-pol-token-on-ethereum-mainnet/">transitions from MATIC to POL</a>.</p>
<p>Polygon&#8217;s CGP aims to support early-stage builders with essential funding. Polygon stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Building is hard. The goal of CGP is to support developers while they build. Waiting until a project has finished building and produces results misses a key piece of true innovation: the opportunity to take chances.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Developers can apply for grants from June 11 to Aug. 31. The grants range from 5,000 MATIC to over 50,000 MATIC. The Community Treasury Board will oversee the selection process.</p>
<p>Applications are open for the General Grants Track and the Consumer Crypto Track. The General Grants Track includes all projects building on the Polygon protocol, such as protocol infrastructure and developer tooling libraries.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the Consumer Crypto Track targets projects focused on driving consumer adoption, including gaming, decentralized social platforms, content creation, and NFT innovations.</p>
<p class="s3">Crypto community members have welcomed the initiative, pointing out that it would motivate builders to develop innovative projects.</p>
<p class="s3">Game developer Chris Heatherly <a href="https://x.com/chrisheatherly/status/1800538718912282789">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Watch as Polygon goes from &#8216;dead&#8217; to the hottest chain going because they now have rewards.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/polygon-unveils-1-billion-pol-token-program-to-boost-developer-engagement/">Polygon unveils 1 billion POL token program to boost developer engagement</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/polygon-unveils-1-billion-pol-token-program-to-boost-developer-engagement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/polygon-pol.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/polygon-pol.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dora Factory airdrops tokens to over 1 million Cosmos stakers</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/dora-factory-airdrops-tokens-to-over-1-million-cosmos-stakers/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/dora-factory-airdrops-tokens-to-over-1-million-cosmos-stakers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ATOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cosmos Hub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dora]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=424562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Dora Factory, a leading blockchain infrastructure provider, airdropped its native DORA token to over 1 million Cosmos Hub stakers on June 5 to boost participation in the ecosystem&#8217;s governance and decentralized funding activities. Dora Factory focuses on decentralized governance and public goods funding tools. The company has developed technologies like Dora Vota and Public Good [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dora-factory-airdrops-tokens-to-over-1-million-cosmos-stakers/">Dora Factory airdrops tokens to over 1 million Cosmos stakers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dora Factory, a leading blockchain infrastructure provider, airdropped its native DORA token to over 1 million Cosmos Hub stakers on June 5 to boost participation in the ecosystem&#8217;s governance and decentralized funding activities.</p>
<p>Dora Factory focuses on decentralized governance and public goods funding tools. The company has developed technologies like Dora Vota and Public Good Staking to enhance decentralized governance.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Funding public goods</span></p>
<p>Following the airdrop, the project stated that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/cosmos-ecosystem/">Cosmos</a> communities could participate in the ATOM Economic Zone (AEZ) quadratic funding program — an initiative it is spearheading with DoraHacks and Atom Accelerator DAO. This campaign aims to mobilize decentralized communities to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/first-decentralized-web3-funding-parachain-polimec-goes-live-on-polkadot/">support public goods projects through fundraising</a>.</p>
<p>Cosmos users can participate using their <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/cosmos/">ATOM</a> tokens to vote and donate to public goods teams they want to support. This initiative aims to aid early-stage developers and decide the allocation of an 80,000 ATOM and $200,000 USDC matching pool over ten rounds of AEZ Quadratic Funding and MACI voting. The smart contracts for this voting round are on the Dora Vota network, allowing the community to use the airdropped DORA tokens as gas fees.</p>
<p>The team emphasized that the campaign was more than just distributing the reward pool to early-stage projects and vital public goods in AEZ. They stated it was also a democratic governance experiment designed to harness community power to support public goods and promising developers.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Privacy voting</span></p>
<p>Also, Dora Factory launched an innovative on-chain voting system with enhanced privacy features known as Minimal Anti-Collusion Infrastructure (MACI). This system allows community members to vote and review projects anonymously while protecting their addresses.</p>
<p>The team said it whitelisted a record 1 million addresses to participate in testing MACI privacy voting and would distribute $20,000 USDC stablecoin to the selected teams. Dora Factory will cover all voting fees for this round through Dora Vota&#8217;s native Gas Station feature.</p>
<p>MACI voting could revolutionize on-chain governance for the Cosmos community and other blockchains, making decentralized governance more efficient and cost-effective.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dora-factory-airdrops-tokens-to-over-1-million-cosmos-stakers/">Dora Factory airdrops tokens to over 1 million Cosmos stakers</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/dora-factory-airdrops-tokens-to-over-1-million-cosmos-stakers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/dora-cosmos-airdrop-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/dora-cosmos-airdrop-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana validators approve 100% allocation of priority fees, ending 50/50 burn split</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/solana-validators-approve-100-allocation-of-priority-fees-ending-50-50-burn-split/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/solana-validators-approve-100-allocation-of-priority-fees-ending-50-50-burn-split/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=421700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Solana validators voted to allocate 100% of priority fees to themselves on May 27, ending the previous 50/50 split between burning fees and rewarding validators. The proposal, known as SIMD-0096, passed with 77% approval. It aims to address perceived flaws in the current system and align incentives for network security and efficiency. The change in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/solana-validators-approve-100-allocation-of-priority-fees-ending-50-50-burn-split/">Solana validators approve 100% allocation of priority fees, ending 50/50 burn split</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a> validators voted to allocate 100% of priority fees to themselves on May 27, ending the previous 50/50 split between burning fees and rewarding validators.</p>
<p>The proposal, known as <a href="https://forum.solana.com/t/proposal-for-enabling-the-reward-full-priority-fee-to-validator-on-solana-mainnet-beta/1456/10">SIMD-0096</a>, passed with 77% approval. It aims to address perceived flaws in the current system and align incentives for network security and efficiency.</p>
<p>The change in priority fee allocation seeks to reduce the potential for side deals between transaction submitters and block producers, which proponents argue could undermine network security.</p>
<p>Validators such as Everstake, Jito, Helius, Stakehaus, Leapfrog, Bonk, Solend, and Pico.sol supported the change.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, validators, including Step Finance, Triton, GREED, Solana Compass, Shinobu, Orangefin, AG, Pumpkin Pull, and Edgevana, opposed the proposal.</p>
<h2>Bug in the system</h2>
<p>Critics, like Hanko Baggins from Bandito Stake, raised concerns about removing the burn mechanism, which helps manage Solana&#8217;s annual inflation rate.</p>
<p>Baggins suggested that while increased fees might benefit validators in the short term, the removal of the burn could impact the network&#8217;s long-term health and suppress SOL&#8217;s price.</p>
<p>Solana co-founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/anatoly-yakovenko/">Anatoly Yakovenko</a> addressed these concerns, stating that the current system requires users to pay double the priority fee to outbid tips, which go entirely to validators and are not burned. He described the priority fee burn as a bug in the system.</p>
<p>Laine from Stakewiz estimated that the change could lead to a 4.6% increase in Solana&#8217;s issuance, aligning it with levels from a year ago. He emphasized that SIMD-0096 is part of a broader plan to improve block reward distribution, with other proposals like SIMD-0123 also in development.</p>
<h2>Delayed implementation</h2>
<p>Although the vote has concluded, the activation of SIMD-0096 may take several months, as the current Solana Mainnet or upcoming upgrade does not support it.</p>
<p>The delay allows for further discussion and development of additional proposals, such as SIMD-0123, which aims to streamline block reward distribution, and SIMD-0109, which proposes a native tipping mechanism.</p>
<p>The decision to allocate 100% of the priority fees to validators highlights the varied perspectives within the Solana ecosystem and sets the stage for ongoing discussions about the network&#8217;s future.</p>
<p>The move comes amid <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-etf-approval-will-set-stage-for-solana-etf-commodity-classification/">growing interest</a> in Solana, following its meteoric climb to a local high of $210 earlier in March. The network has also recorded the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/defi-landscape-shifts-as-solana-dethrones-ethereum-in-trading-volume/">highest trading volume</a> in recent weeks.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/solana-validators-approve-100-allocation-of-priority-fees-ending-50-50-burn-split/">Solana validators approve 100% allocation of priority fees, ending 50/50 burn split</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/solana-validators-approve-100-allocation-of-priority-fees-ending-50-50-burn-split/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/solana-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/solana-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum Foundation considering formal conflict of interest policy after community backlash</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-foundation-considers-formal-conflict-of-interest-policy-after-community-backlash/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-foundation-considers-formal-conflict-of-interest-policy-after-community-backlash/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 20:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=421391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum Foundation (EF) is considering implementing a formal conflict of interest policy following backlash over two prominent developers joining EigenLayer as advisors. Executive director Aya Miyaguchi addressed the issue in a social media post, emphasizing the importance of maintaining credible neutrality within the organization. She said the foundation shares the community&#8217;s concerns and is committed [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-foundation-considers-formal-conflict-of-interest-policy-after-community-backlash/">Ethereum Foundation considering formal conflict of interest policy after community backlash</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ethereum-foundation/">Ethereum Foundation</a> (EF) is considering implementing a formal conflict of interest policy following backlash over two prominent developers joining <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-edges-near-4000-as-eigenlayer-becomes-second-largest-defi-protocol/">EigenLayer</a> as advisors.</p>
<p>Executive director <a href="https://x.com/AyaMiyagotchi/status/1793965259524653058">Aya Miyaguchi</a> addressed the issue in a social media post, emphasizing the importance of maintaining credible neutrality within the organization. She said the foundation shares the community&#8217;s concerns and is committed to maintaining trust.</p>
<p>Miyaguchi said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;It is clear that relying on culture and individual judgment has not been sufficient, and we have been working on a formal policy to address this problem for a while now. We will be accelerating this work and will share an update soon.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Controversy</h2>
<p>The controversy began on May 18 when prominent crypto trader Jordan Fish, known as Cobie, publicly questioned <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/?s=Ethereum">Ethereum</a> co-founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/vitalik-buterin/">Vitalik Buterin</a> about the ethics of EF developers receiving significant financial incentives from projects built on the network.</p>
<p>Cobie&#8217;s tweet specifically used EigenLayer as an example and sparked widespread discussion on social media about potential conflicts of interest. He wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;How do you feel about Ethereum Foundation core developers or researchers taking life-changing packages from projects built on Ethereum to become ‘advisors,&#8217; when those projects may have conflicted incentives with Ethereum, either now or in the future? For example — purely theoretically, of course — let&#8217;s say, EigenLayer.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Following Cobie&#8217;s tweet, Ethereum Foundation researcher Justin Drake disclosed his advisory role at EigenLayer on May 19. Drake revealed that he received a substantial incentive in Eigen tokens, estimated to be worth millions of dollars over a three-year vesting period.</p>
<p>The disclosure heightened concerns about transparency and potential conflicts of interest between EigenLayer and the Ethereum Foundation. Drake also stated that the information had been public since May 3, and the timing of the disclosure with Cobie&#8217;s tweet was a coincidence.</p>
<p>On May 21, another Ethereum Foundation researcher, Dankrad Feist, also disclosed his advisory role at EigenLayer. Feist, known for his work on &#8220;danksharding,&#8221; confirmed he had also received a significant allocation of EIGEN tokens and assured the community that his advisory role would not influence his positions on the development of EigenLayer.</p>
<h2>Conflict of interest concerns</h2>
<p>The disclosures have raised questions about potential conflicts of interest, especially given the systemic risks EigenLayer might pose to Ethereum. EigenLayer is a platform that allows users to deposit and &#8220;re-stake&#8221; Ether from various liquid staking tokens to secure third-party networks or validated services.</p>
<p>Many blockchain experts have expressed concerns about the potential centralization and additional load imposed on stakers by running restaking services.</p>
<p>Drake assured the community that he would reinvest or donate all proceeds to worthy projects within the Ethereum ecosystem and pledged to end the advisorship if EigenLayer&#8217;s direction conflicted with Ethereum&#8217;s interests.</p>
<p>Feist, in his disclosure, emphasized that he would take contrarian views on EigenLayer to focus on risks and decentralization. He wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I am taking this position personally, not representing the Ethereum Foundation, and with a focus on risks and decentralization. I do receive a significant amount of tokens from this position. I do not believe that they will change or influence my positions on how the core protocol should be developed, but I believe that the community should know about this so that they can keep me accountable.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The Ethereum Foundation&#8217;s move to formalize a conflict of interest policy marks a significant step in addressing the community&#8217;s concerns and maintaining trust within the ecosystem. The foundation is expected to provide further updates on the policy soon.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-foundation-considers-formal-conflict-of-interest-policy-after-community-backlash/">Ethereum Foundation considering formal conflict of interest policy after community backlash</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-foundation-considers-formal-conflict-of-interest-policy-after-community-backlash/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/ethereum-staking-2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/ethereum-staking-2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aave proposes upgrade to v4 in strategic 2030 roadmap</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/aave-proposes-upgrade-to-v4-in-strategic-2030-roadmap/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/aave-proposes-upgrade-to-v4-in-strategic-2030-roadmap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 22:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Governance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=416295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Aave Labs has released its strategic roadmap for 2030 that introduces several key initiatives, including the launch of Aave V4, a new visual identity, and expanded DeFi functionalities. The &#8220;Temp Check&#8221; proposal aims to gather the Aave community&#8217;s feedback on the proposed enhancements to advance the Aave protocol. Aave V4 At the heart of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/aave-proposes-upgrade-to-v4-in-strategic-2030-roadmap/">Aave proposes upgrade to v4 in strategic 2030 roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Aave Labs has released its strategic roadmap for 2030 that introduces several key initiatives, including the launch of Aave V4, a new visual identity, and expanded DeFi functionalities.</p>
<p>The &#8220;<a href="https://governance.aave.com/t/temp-check-aave-2030/17539">Temp Check</a>&#8221; proposal aims to gather the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/aave/">Aave</a> community&#8217;s feedback on the proposed enhancements to advance the Aave protocol.</p>
<h2>Aave V4</h2>
<p>At the heart of the proposal is the introduction of Aave V4, which will significantly improve the protocol&#8217;s user interface and extend its functionalities across diverse blockchain networks.</p>
<p>The new version includes a Cross-Chain Liquidity Layer (CCLL) that facilitates seamless asset transfers across supported chains, enhancing Aave&#8217;s operational fluidity.</p>
<p>Furthermore, Aave proposed plans to integrate Real World Assets (RWAs) with its native stablecoin, GHO, in collaboration with Chainlink. The integration aims to diversify the protocol&#8217;s asset base and stabilize the utility of GHO for daily transactions.</p>
<p>The proposal sets forth a three-year development timeline. Aave Labs plans to engage with the community regularly through feedback sessions and annual reviews to align the project&#8217;s development with the community&#8217;s expectations and the dynamic market conditions.</p>
<p>Aave Labs has also proposed a transition from a retroactive to a proactive funding model via a transparent budgeting approach involving community approval before project commencement. The proposed budget includes 15 million GHO and 25,000 stkAAVE, allocated to cover research, development, and security audits for the initial year.</p>
<h2>Updated Identity</h2>
<p>Aave has also proposed to update its visual identity to reflect its strategic future goals and enhance its brand recognition within the DeFi space. The new design aims to project a modern, distinctive image that aligns with Aave&#8217;s innovative outlook.</p>
<p>Aave Labs encouraged broad participation from developers and community members in realizing its goals, emphasizing that the protocol&#8217;s governance remains decentralized. Contributors are invited to engage actively in discussions and development processes, helping shape the protocol&#8217;s future.</p>
<p>Following community feedback, Aave Labs plans to refine and incorporate the input into the official Aave Governance Framework for final approval. The documentation related to this proposal is available under the CC0 license, facilitating open collaboration and widespread contribution.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/aave-proposes-upgrade-to-v4-in-strategic-2030-roadmap/">Aave proposes upgrade to v4 in strategic 2030 roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/aave-proposes-upgrade-to-v4-in-strategic-2030-roadmap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/aave-ethpow.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/aave-ethpow.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
