<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Layer2 News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/layer2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/layer2/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 23:40:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Layer2 News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/layer2/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Cardano&#8217;s Hydra shatters 1 million TPS during virtual Doom tournament</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-hydra-shatters-1-million-tps-during-virtual-doom-tournament/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-hydra-shatters-1-million-tps-during-virtual-doom-tournament/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 02:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cardano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hydra]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Cardano&#8217;s Layer-2 protocol Hydra reached a significant milestone of surpassing 1 million transactions per second (TPS) during its Doom gaming tournament. On Dec. 4, Charles Hoskinson, the founder of Cardano, shared screenshots confirming that the network had crossed the 1 million TPS mark globally. This achievement is part of the ongoing tournament to test Hydra&#8217;s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-hydra-shatters-1-million-tps-during-virtual-doom-tournament/">Cardano&#8217;s Hydra shatters 1 million TPS during virtual Doom tournament</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/cardano/">Cardano&#8217;s</a> Layer-2 protocol Hydra reached a significant milestone of surpassing 1 million transactions per second (TPS) during its Doom gaming tournament.</p>
<p>On Dec. 4, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/charles-hoskinson/">Charles Hoskinson</a>, the founder of Cardano, <a href="https://x.com/IOHK_Charles/status/1864125365997686941?t=TgKiUhw95MNyWnZw2pqOlQ&amp;s=19">shared</a> screenshots confirming that the network had crossed the 1 million TPS mark globally. This achievement is part of the ongoing tournament to test Hydra&#8217;s scalability.</p>
<p>Hoskinson <a href="https://x.com/IOHK_Charles/status/1863873849214882170?t=1vZqCTx33mu8fn-8XhV4OQ&amp;s=19">explained</a> that the high TPS is driven by each game frame being processed as a transaction. This demonstrates Hydra&#8217;s ability to handle substantial transaction volumes.</p>
<p>While the official <a href="https://hydra-twitter-visualizer.vercel.app/">data</a> shows a current TPS of 507 and a peak of over 807,000, these numbers are still far ahead of competing blockchain networks like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a>. For context, Hydra&#8217;s test outperformed Solana&#8217;s theoretical maximum TPS of 65,000 by over 100x, according to <a href="https://chainspect.app/dashboard">Chainspect</a>.</p>
<h2>Hydra&#8217;s potential</h2>
<p>Advocates like Josh Marchand, a software engineer at Sundaeswap (a decentralized exchange on Cardano), emphasized that Hydra&#8217;s value lies in its limitless scalability potential. He <a href="https://x.com/JSHyCS/status/1864347183689961557">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;1m is just an arbitrary number. The truly exciting part of Hydra is the limitlessness. The beauty of Hydra is that you could horizontally scale your system until you run out of silicon (or AWS vCPU units, in our case).&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>However, critics like crypto analyst Goku <a href="https://x.com/0xgoku_/status/1864329638916345885">pointed out</a> that the transactions processed during the Doom tournament were not settled on Cardano&#8217;s mainnet but were part of a testnet simulation.</p>
<p>Hydra, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-hydra-scaling-solution-goes-live-on-mainnet-as-ethereum-gas-fees-surge/">launched last year</a>, is a Layer-2 scaling solution designed to enhance Cardano&#8217;s scalability by increasing transaction speeds and throughputs while reducing latency and costs.</p>
<p>Despite facing some criticism, Hoskinson has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/charles-hoskinson-defends-hydra-as-cardano-defi-thrives/">defended</a> Hydra&#8217;s progress. The Doom tournament, however, has proven to be an effective showcase, drawing players worldwide to experience Hydra&#8217;s capabilities.</p>
<h2>Bullish Cardano ecosystem</h2>
<p>The development coincides with a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardano-and-xrp-outperform-bitcoin-by-over-200-as-developers-hard-work-pays-off/">strong market trend for Cardano</a>, which has climbed significantly over the last few weeks.</p>
<p>Based on <em>CryptoSlate</em> data, ADA is up more than 250% over the past 30 days, reaching a two-year high of over $1.29 before a retracement kicked in. The token was trading at $1.18 as of press time.</p>
<p>The Cardano network is also seeing an uptick in DeFi activity, with the total value locked on the platform nearing a record $700 million. These advancements come as the platform continues to advance its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-age-of-voltaire-nears-with-major-blockchain-upgrade/">decentralized governance efforts.</a></p>
<p>Cardano Foundation <a href="https://x.com/Cardano_CF/status/1864352884894081035">stated</a> that ongoing discussions at the Constitutional Convention emphasize the importance of community-driven decisions and reflect their efforts to build a more robust and resilient ecosystem.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-hydra-shatters-1-million-tps-during-virtual-doom-tournament/">Cardano&#8217;s Hydra shatters 1 million TPS during virtual Doom tournament</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/cardanos-hydra-shatters-1-million-tps-during-virtual-doom-tournament/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cardano-tps.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/cardano-tps.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celo&#8217;s token drops as Coinbase skips Layer-2 migration support</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 15:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Celo, a prominent Layer-1 blockchain, has seen its native token dump 5% after its upcoming transition to an Ethereum Layer-2 network within Optimism&#8217;s Superchain ecosystem turned &#8220;contentious.&#8221; On Nov. 27, Coinbase, the largest US-based crypto exchange, announced that it would not support Celo&#8217;s migration into a Layer 2 network. In contrast, Tether&#8217;s CEO Paolo Ardoino [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/">Celo&#8217;s token drops as Coinbase skips Layer-2 migration support</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/celo/">Celo</a>, a prominent Layer-1 blockchain, has seen its native token dump 5% after its upcoming transition to an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> Layer-2 network within <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/optimism/">Optimism&#8217;s</a> Superchain ecosystem turned &#8220;contentious.&#8221;</p>
<p>On Nov. 27, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>, the largest US-based crypto exchange, announced that it would not support Celo&#8217;s migration into a Layer 2 network. In contrast, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/tether/">Tether&#8217;s</a> CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paolo-ardoino/">Paolo Ardoino</a> confirmed the stablecoin issuer&#8217;s continued support for the network post-transition into the Ethereum ecosystem.</p>
<p>Data from <em>CryptoSlate</em> showed that this uncertainty negatively impacted the network&#8217;s CELO token, which fell 5% to $<span class="holepunch holepunch-coin_price_usd">0.81039 at press time.</span></p>
<h2>Community reaction</h2>
<p>These diverging views sparked mixed reactions within the community, with many criticizing Coinbase&#8217;s decision.</p>
<p>Marek Olszewski, CEO of Celo&#8217;s developer cLabs, <a href="https://x.com/marek_/status/1861900233460080650">expressed</a> disappointment with Coinbase&#8217;s stance. He <a href="https://x.com/marek_/status/1861900233460080650">questioned</a> whether this decision might deter other Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM)-compatible Layer-1 chains from embracing Ethereum&#8217;s Layer-2 scaling solutions.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the founder of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken&#8217;s</a> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/">Inkchain</a>, Andrew Koller, assured that his exchange would support the migration into an L2. He <a href="https://x.com/ak47ink/status/1861959538137854144">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;<span class="css-1jxf684 r-bcqeeo r-1ttztb7 r-qvutc0 r-poiln3">Kraken and Ink [loves]</span><span class="css-1jxf684 r-bcqeeo r-1ttztb7 r-qvutc0 r-poiln3"> the superchain and are fully committed to Ethereum scaling and making Kraken work for Celo users. we&#8217;ve asked the relevant teams to explore this to see if we can hit everything in time for Jan. 16th.&#8221;</span></p></blockquote>
<p>Despite the setback, Olszewski <a href="https://x.com/marek_/status/1861842855599522064">suggested</a> the Celo community could consider renaming its existing Layer-1 chain to &#8220;Celo Gold (CGLD)&#8221; to accommodate Coinbase&#8217;s current support framework. He hinted that this might simplify future adoption if Coinbase supports the Layer-2 upgrade.</p>
<h2>Community urges Coinbase to rethink</h2>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/eigenlayer/">EigenLayer</a> founder Sreeram Kannan <a href="https://x.com/sreeramkannan/status/1861911269818974482">speculated</a> that Coinbase&#8217;s decision could stem from &#8220;an oversight&#8221; rather than outright opposition. He encouraged the exchange to revisit its stance, emphasizing the potential benefits of supporting Celo&#8217;s integration into the OP Stack.</p>
<p>Kannan stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I think this is likely an oversight internally in Coinbase. There is no chance the company building the leading Ethereum L2 in users and a core contributor to OP public goods will choose to discontinue supporting Celo after it becomes an OP stack based L2.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>On the other hand, Nass Eddequiouaq, the CEO of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/a16z/">a16z</a>-funded crypto startup Bastion, highlighted the operational and regulatory complexities exchanges face when adding support for new chains, particularly in the US. He <a href="https://x.com/nassyweazy/status/1861989220031627584">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Exchanges and custodian have usually been waiting to see which branch of the fork picks up the activity before adding support for it and deprecating the other one.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/">Celo&#8217;s token drops as Coinbase skips Layer-2 migration support</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/celos-token-drops-as-coinbase-skips-layer-2-migration-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celo-ethereum-layer2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/celo-ethereum-layer2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starknet debuts Ethereum layer-2 staking with Bitwise as early validator</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-debuts-ethereum-layer-2-staking-with-bitwise-as-early-validator/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-debuts-ethereum-layer-2-staking-with-bitwise-as-early-validator/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 17:42:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Staking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitwise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[StarkNet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454748</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Starknet has launched its staking program for STRK tokens, becoming the first Ethereum layer-2 network to enable staking, according to a Nov. 26 statement shared with CryptoSlate. The program aims to empower token holders to participate in securing the network while earning rewards. In this initial phase, token holders with at least 20,000 STRK can [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-debuts-ethereum-layer-2-staking-with-bitwise-as-early-validator/">Starknet debuts Ethereum layer-2 staking with Bitwise as early validator</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Starknet has launched its staking program for STRK tokens, becoming the first Ethereum layer-2 network to enable staking, according to a Nov. 26 statement shared with <em>CryptoSlate</em>.</p>
<p>The program aims to empower token holders to participate in securing the network while earning rewards.</p>
<p>In this initial phase, token holders with at least 20,000 STRK can stake directly on the network. Those with fewer tokens can delegate their holdings to validators. Both groups will face a mandatory 21-day lockup period for unstaking, with rewards distributed proportionally based on the amount staked.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Starknet also encourages participants to use staking-enabled wallets, paving the way for broader institutional and retail adoption.</p>
<p>StarkWare CEO Eli Ben-Sasson said the launch of staking is a significant moment for the network. He emphasized that the staking initiative showcases blockchains&#8217; potential to handle increasing demand through rollups.</p>
<p>This milestone follows Starknet&#8217;s recent achievement of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-overtakes-coinbase-backed-base-with-stress-test-propelling-857-tps-milestone/">processing 857 transactions per second</a>, setting a benchmark for other Ethereum layer-2 solutions.</p>
<h2><strong>Bitwise joins an early validator</strong></h2>
<p>According to a Nov. 26 <a href="https://x.com/BitwiseInvest/status/1861424594034491793">announcement</a>, crypto investment firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitwise/">Bitwise</a> has become one of the first validators for Starknet&#8217;s staking program.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> ETF issuer stated that its Bitwise Onchain Solutions, known for its extensive Ethereum staking experience, will support STRK staking. The company has offered a public validator address that enables STRK holders to delegate their tokens easily to the platform.</p>
<p>The company explained that it views Starknet as a fitting choice to expand its staking products into layer-2 networks, citing the network&#8217;s role in advancing blockchain technology through innovations like ZK-STARKs and its Cairo programming language.</p>
<p>Bitwise CTO Hong Kim <a href="https://bitwiseinvestments.com/newsroom/bitwise-onchain-solutions-to-offer-non-custodial-staking-for-starknet">said</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;For years, Starknet has been pushing the frontiers of scaling and security with ZK-STARKs and its native smart-contract language, Cairo. This network has given back a great deal to the Ethereum community while staying committed to its vision of building a more accessible, transparent, and sovereign internet, the ‘Integrity Web.’&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-debuts-ethereum-layer-2-staking-with-bitwise-as-early-validator/">Starknet debuts Ethereum layer-2 staking with Bitwise as early validator</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/starknet-debuts-ethereum-layer-2-staking-with-bitwise-as-early-validator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/starkware-staking-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/starkware-staking-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitfinity bridges Bitcoin and Ethereum with new Layer-2 mainnet, raises $12 million</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bitfinity-bridges-bitcoin-and-ethereum-with-new-layer-2-mainnet-raises-12-million/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bitfinity-bridges-bitcoin-and-ethereum-with-new-layer-2-mainnet-raises-12-million/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 22:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[layer2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bitfinity Network, a Bitcoin Layer-2 solution compatible with the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM), has officially launched its mainnet after raising nearly $12 million, according to a Nov. 19 statement shared with CryptoSlate. The Layer-2 network aims to bridge the gap between Bitcoin and DeFi, offering enhanced interoperability and abstraction. Its goal is to bring Bitcoin-native [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitfinity-bridges-bitcoin-and-ethereum-with-new-layer-2-mainnet-raises-12-million/">Bitfinity bridges Bitcoin and Ethereum with new Layer-2 mainnet, raises $12 million</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bitfinity Network, a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> Layer-2 solution compatible with the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> Virtual Machine (EVM), has officially launched its mainnet after raising nearly $12 million, according to a Nov. 19 statement shared with <em>CryptoSlate</em>.</p>
<p>The Layer-2 network aims to bridge the gap between Bitcoin and DeFi, offering enhanced interoperability and abstraction. Its goal is to bring Bitcoin-native DeFi to a broader audience, making it easier for users to interact with Bitcoin-based decentralized applications (dApps).</p>
<p>The mainnet launch comes on the heels of significant institutional backing and a successful token sale. Bitfinity&#8217;s token is now listed on major exchanges like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kucoin/">KuCoin</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/huobi-korea/">Huobi</a>, and Gate.io, generating $5 million in over-the-counter (OTC) sales, primarily driven by community participation.</p>
<p>Bitfinity also secured $7 million earlier this year in a funding round backed by top investors, including Polychain&#8217;s Beacon Fund, ParaFi, Draft Ventures, Warburg Series, and 9 Yards Capital.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bitfinity said it is introducing Bitgems, a new feature that rewards users for social interactions. Participants can mine digital gems through a Token Generation Event (TGE) program, further engaging the community and expanding the ecosystem.</p>
<h2>Leveraging ICP technology</h2>
<p>Bitfinity integrates <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/internet-computer/">Internet Computer Protocol&#8217;s (ICP)</a> Chain Fusion Technology to support Bitcoin-native assets within an EVM-compatible environment. This integration aims to enable the secure development of Bitcoin smart contracts, offering a more decentralized and user-controlled ecosystem.</p>
<p>The network&#8217;s use of a threshold signature scheme creates a decentralized bridge to Ethereum, eliminating the need for centralized intermediaries and enhancing users&#8217; security and control.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bitfinity&#8217;s mainnet launch coincides with a surge in Bitcoin&#8217;s price and a resurgence of interest in its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trons-defi-ecosystem-set-for-a-boost-with-chainlink-collaboration/">DeFi ecosystem.</a> This increased activity has drawn more institutional attention, fueling excitement around Bitfinity&#8217;s potential to unlock new opportunities within the Bitcoin space.</p>
<p>Lomesh Dutta, the VP of Growth at Dfinity, emphasized that Bitfinity&#8217;s EVM compatibility could redefine Bitcoin&#8217;s DeFi landscape.</p>
<p>He stated:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The incredible community and investor support we’ve seen speaks to the impact of a platform designed to bring scalability, interoperability, and secure DeFi solutions to Bitcoin users.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitfinity-bridges-bitcoin-and-ethereum-with-new-layer-2-mainnet-raises-12-million/">Bitfinity bridges Bitcoin and Ethereum with new Layer-2 mainnet, raises $12 million</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bitfinity-bridges-bitcoin-and-ethereum-with-new-layer-2-mainnet-raises-12-million/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-evm.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitcoin-evm.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Optimism Foundation offered 25M OP tokens to attract Kraken’s L2 to the Superchain</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-foundation-offered-25m-op-tokens-to-attract-krakens-l2-to-the-superchain/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-foundation-offered-25m-op-tokens-to-attract-krakens-l2-to-the-superchain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=450641</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Optimism Foundation and Kraken closed a 25 million OP deal to bring the exchange&#8217;s new layer-2 (L2) blockchain, Ink, to the Superchain ecosystem. According to CryptoSlate data, the deal is worth $43 million at OP&#8217;s current price of $1.72. Grant Optimism Foundation&#8217;s chief growth officer, Ryan Wyatt, explained that the grant is structured to fund Kraken’s protocol engineering [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-foundation-offered-25m-op-tokens-to-attract-krakens-l2-to-the-superchain/">Optimism Foundation offered 25M OP tokens to attract Kraken’s L2 to the Superchain</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Optimism Foundation and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken</a> closed a 25 million <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/optimism/">OP</a> deal to bring the exchange&#8217;s new layer-2 (L2) blockchain, Ink, to the Superchain ecosystem. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="color: #333333;">According to CryptoSlate data, the deal is worth $43 million at OP&#8217;s current </span><em style="color: #333333;">price of </em><span style="color: #333333;">$1.72</span>.</span></p>
<h2>Grant</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Optimism Foundation&#8217;s chief growth officer, Ryan Wyatt, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><a href="https://x.com/Fwiz/status/1851280684473897466" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>explained</strong></a> that the grant is structured to fund Kraken’s protocol engineering and </span>incentivize major transaction milestones. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The 25 million tokens are split into two segments: five million $OP tokens will support engineering efforts specific to the OP Stack, while the remaining 20 million are earmarked for achieving transaction benchmarks that would generate substantial fees for the OP Collective.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Wyatt, the remaining 20 million tokens will be paid out as &#8220;massive transaction milestones&#8221; are met. The aim is to drive fees to the Optimism Collective, giving the deal a positive return on investment.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wyatt also highlighted that this deal was also offered to other crypto firms that deployed blockchains using Optimism&#8217;s infrastructure, such as <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase&#8217;s</a> L2 blockchain Base.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Tokens paid as grants</strong></h2>
<p>The foundation has emphasized that the grant represents more than simple deployment costs, typically estimated at under $3,000 per month.</p>
<p>According to Wyatt:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;They [Kraken] will contribute to protocol engineering and development of the OP Stack, committing to interoperability, Superchain ERC-20 standards, and broader ecosystem goals.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>He clarified that Kraken&#8217;s work would include deep integration efforts to strengthen the OP Stack&#8217;s potential across the DeFi sector.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wyatt also </span><strong><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1qVMhLmmch3s6XSbiBe8hgD4ntMkPIOhc1WrhsYsQc7M/edit?gid=470961921#gid=470961921">shared</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a public document detailing OP token allocations, which shows nearly 480 million OP tokens committed to &#8220;Partner fund + seed fund + Unallocated.&#8221; He further </span><strong><a href="https://x.com/Fwiz/status/1851296259539419200">vowed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that &#8220;transparency will continue to increase.&#8221;</span></p>
<h2><strong>Another CEX-backed L2</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Kraken </span><strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/">announced</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> its Ethereum L2 on Oct. 24 and said the network will be a general-use network like Base. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to the announcement, the Superchain was chosen to satisfy Ink&#8217;s ambition to be an interoperable blockchain while maintaining Ethereum&#8217;s (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">ETH</a>) underlying security as a layer-1 blockchain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Base, the only layer-2 blockchain deployed on Superchain by a centralized exchange until now, has been very successful. It crossed $2 billion in total value locked (TVL) in late September and sits at $2.7 billion as of Oct. 29, becoming the largest Ethereum L2 by TVL, per DefiLlama </span><a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Base"><span style="font-weight: 400;">data</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">. </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-foundation-offered-25m-op-tokens-to-attract-krakens-l2-to-the-superchain/">Optimism Foundation offered 25M OP tokens to attract Kraken’s L2 to the Superchain</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-foundation-offered-25m-op-tokens-to-attract-krakens-l2-to-the-superchain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/kraken-ethereum.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/kraken-ethereum.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kraken eyes DeFi expansion with launch of Ink, its new Ethereum layer-2 network</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 15:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Exchanges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kraken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[optimism]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449907</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crypto exchange Kraken announced the upcoming launch of Ink, an Ethereum layer-2 network based on the Optimism Superchain, in an Oct. 24 statement. Ink aims to empower users to trade, borrow, and lend tokens without the need for intermediaries, marking a significant shift from Kraken&#8217;s current centralized exchange model. Ink founder Andrew Koller said: &#8220;Ink [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/">Kraken eyes DeFi expansion with launch of Ink, its new Ethereum layer-2 network</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Crypto exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/kraken/">Kraken</a> announced the upcoming launch of Ink, an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> layer-2 network based on the Optimism Superchain, in an Oct. 24 statement.</p>
<p>Ink aims to empower users to trade, borrow, and lend tokens without the need for intermediaries, marking a significant shift from Kraken&#8217;s current centralized exchange model.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.kraken.com/news/announcing-ink">Ink</a> founder Andrew Koller said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Ink will work closely with developers and the community to create a compelling ecosystem for all. We’re excited to accelerate the move onchain with an interoperable L2 that will make it even more seamless for crypto users to access DeFi. Ink the future.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The network plans to launch its testnet for developers later this year, with a full rollout for retail and institutional users anticipated in the first quarter of 2025.</p>
<h2>Why Optimism Superchain?</h2>
<p>Kraken stated that its choice of the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-invites-layer-3-networks-to-join-its-superchain-promising-advanced-features/">Optimism Superchain</a> would allow it to benefit from Ethereum&#8217;s robust security. This would also position Ink as part of the Superchain — a unified network of blockchains that shares security, governance, and values designed to enhance Ethereum scalability.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the exchange decision aligns with the growing trend among major crypto firms, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/uniswap/">Uniswap</a>, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/worldcoin-rebrands-as-world-targets-1-billion-users-with-new-blockchain-and-biometric-tech/">World</a>, which <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/worldcoin-unveils-world-chain-a-layer-2-network-built-for-humans/">leverage this technology</a> for their layer-2 networks.</p>
<p>Optimism Unlimited Chief Growth Officer Ryan Wyatt <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241024404091/en/Introducing-Ink-The-Layer-2-Opening-Exciting-DeFi-Opportunities-to-Everyone">commented</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Optimism&#8217;s technology powers the Superchain, and nearly 50% of all Ethereum L2 transactions. As part of this Superchain ecosystem, Ink will contribute to Optimism governance and drive revenue back to the Optimism Collective as we work together to scale Ethereum.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Despite this significant adoption of Optimism technology, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbitrum/">Arbitrum</a> remains the dominant layer-2 network, according to DeFillama data.</p>
<h2>Kraken&#8217;s expanding product portfolio</h2>
<p>The launch of Ink complements Kraken&#8217;s expanding range of products aimed at solidifying its industry position.</p>
<p>This month, the exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-launches-kbtc-as-competition-heats-up-in-wrapped-bitcoin-market/">introduced kBTC</a>, a new wrapped <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> product designed to enhance the top crypto availability in DeFi activities. The firm stated that each kBTC is securely backed 1:1 by an equivalent amount of Bitcoin held in its custody.</p>
<p>Further, Kraken also announced the integration of  <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/eigenlayer/">EigenLayer</a> to allow its users to restake their ETH directly from its platform.</p>
<p>In addition, Kraken has launched a derivatives trading platform in Bermuda following the acquisition of a Class F Digital Business License from the Bermuda Monetary Authority (BMA).</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/">Kraken eyes DeFi expansion with launch of Ink, its new Ethereum layer-2 network</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/kraken-eyes-defi-expansion-with-launch-of-ink-its-new-ethereum-layer-2-network/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kraken-ink.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/kraken-ink.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uniswap introduces Unichain, sparking a 12% surge in UNI token</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/uniswap-introduces-unichain-sparking-a-12-surge-in-uni-token/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/uniswap-introduces-unichain-sparking-a-12-surge-in-uni-token/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 15:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UNI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unichain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uniswap]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=447573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Decentralized exchange Uniswap&#8216;s UNI token surged following the announcement of Unichain, the platform&#8217;s Ethereum layer-2 network. Data from CryptoSlate shows that UNI rose over 12%, reaching $8.07—the highest it&#8217;s been in three months. This rise made UNI the top-performing digital asset in the market, which otherwise saw major tokens like Bitcoin lose about 2% of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/uniswap-introduces-unichain-sparking-a-12-surge-in-uni-token/">Uniswap introduces Unichain, sparking a 12% surge in UNI token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Decentralized exchange <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/uniswap/">Uniswap</a>&#8216;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/uniswap/">UNI</a> token surged following the announcement of Unichain, the platform&#8217;s <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> layer-2 network.</p>
<p>Data from CryptoSlate shows that UNI rose over 12%, reaching $8.07—the highest it&#8217;s been in three months. This rise made UNI the top-performing digital asset in the market, which otherwise saw major tokens like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> lose about 2% of their value.</p>
<p>As the governance token of Uniswap, a leading decentralized exchange with over $2.4 trillion in trading volume, UNI is ranked among the top 25 digital assets by market capitalization.</p>
<p><span style="color: #333333; font-size: 22px; font-weight: bold;">Unichain</span></p>
<p>On Oct. 10, Uniswap Labs unveiled <a href="https://blog.uniswap.org/introducing-unichain">Unichain</a> as a key solution in advancing Ethereum&#8217;s scaling roadmap.</p>
<p>Designed with DeFi users and protocols in mind, Unichain is built on the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/optimism-invites-layer-3-networks-to-join-its-superchain-promising-advanced-features/">Optimism Superchain</a>, an Ethereum layer-2 (L2) network utilizing Optimistic rollups.</p>
<p>Unichain promises one-second block times, delivering near-instant transaction speeds. This enhancement improves user experience, boosts market efficiency, and reduces losses from miner extractable value (MEV).</p>
<p>Furthermore, Unichain offers around a 95% reduction in transaction costs compared to Ethereum&#8217;s layer-1, with the potential for even lower fees in the future.</p>
<p>Unichain also plans to introduce a decentralized validation network, allowing nodes to verify blocks. This feature will add extra security and reduce the likelihood of conflicting or invalid blocks.</p>
<p>Unichain will support seamless multi-chain swaps, ensuring fast and secure cross-chain transactions. As part of the Optimism Superchain, it offers native interoperability while adhering to standards like ERC-7683 to make cross-chain swaps smoother.</p>
<p>Unichain will be MIT-licensed to encourage widespread adoption of the technology. The network&#8217;s testnet is now live, with a mainnet launch expected soon.</p>
<h2>Why L2s are importance</h2>
<p>In the past year, the crypto industry has seen an influx of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/cryptos/layer-2/">layer-2 solutions</a>, with market experts arguing that this has caused network fragmentation.</p>
<p>However, Uniswap Labs&#8217; CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/hayden-adams/">Hayden Adams</a> explained the importance of multiple L2 chains for scaling Ethereum, pointing out that the &#8220;internet of value can&#8217;t operate on a single chain.&#8221;</p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/haydenzadams/status/1844363698485198899">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The internet of value can&#8217;t run on a single chain. Ethereum&#8217;s rollup-centric roadmap aims to scale by having many L2 chains that seamlessly interface with each other. We are excited by this vision, and aim to accelerate it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/uniswap-introduces-unichain-sparking-a-12-surge-in-uni-token/">Uniswap introduces Unichain, sparking a 12% surge in UNI token</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/uniswap-introduces-unichain-sparking-a-12-surge-in-uni-token/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/unichain-uniswap.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/unichain-uniswap.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Ethereum’s next step is zero-knowledge</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/why-ethereums-next-step-is-zero-knowledge/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/why-ethereums-next-step-is-zero-knowledge/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Viglione]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=445728</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The following is a guest post by Rob Viglione, CEO of Horizen Labs. In the past year, there have been some major milestones along the Ethereum roadmap that have leveled up the network. EIP-4844 (aka Dencun) introduced blobs and proto-danksharding, making data storage an order of magnitude cheaper for Layer 2s and resulting in far [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/why-ethereums-next-step-is-zero-knowledge/">Why Ethereum’s next step is zero-knowledge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>The following is a guest post by <span data-sheets-root="1">Rob Viglione</span>, <span data-sheets-root="1">CEO of Horizen Labs.</span></em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the past year, there have been some major milestones along the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> roadmap that have leveled up the network. EIP-4844 (aka Dencun) introduced blobs and proto-danksharding, making data storage an order of magnitude cheaper for Layer 2s and resulting in far lower transaction fees. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, Layer 2s (mostly of the optimistic variety) have become more integrated and widely used in applications, making it possible to transact for less than a penny, and improving on Ethereum’s fundamental infrastructure. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, as anyone who has paid attention to gas fees will know, there is still too much congestion on Ethereum, and as the real-world usage of blockchains grows, more and more dApps will be competing for block space and computation. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It doesn’t take an engineer or cryptographer to know that this is unsustainable. We’ve seen what happens when Ethereum gets too congested. In some particularly high-surge moments, users have paid more than 2 ETH just to complete a transaction, and some of those transactions still failed as users scrambled to have them prioritized. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In a perfect world, we would move as much of that computation offchain, and still be able to post a succinct, verifiable proof that ensures the data is correct and in the right place. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Zero-knowledge proofs make this possible, but it’s still challenging for blockchains to verify transactions with so many potential possibilities in the EVM, and it can quickly become expensive to go this route. Zk-rollups have to pay for specialized hardware that creates a ZK proof via a prover, and then that typically needs to be converted into a proof type that Ethereum can understand. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In short, optimistic rollups are relatively easy and affordable to verify, while zk-rollups are challenging and expensive. For small and even medium-sized businesses that want to do some of their business onchain and keep it confidential, zk-rollups are the way to go, but proof verification can be a prohibitive expense. </span></p>
<h2><b>Rollup ecosystems have their own interests</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Up to this point, the branded L2s haven’t been interested in a modular proof verification solution like zkVerify — which can reduce verification costs by 90% or more. They could adopt it down the road, but it isn’t their focus at the moment. Generally, the big L2 ecosystems believe in verifying all of these ZK proofs on the same chain and amortizing these costs across users. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, we did find an opportunity with rollup-as-a-service (RaaS) providers, because they believe in a modular approach to blockchains and tend to service small and medium-sized projects who can’t afford to pay those verification costs. For them, the idea of sending proofs to a standalone chain and then sending the proof verification back to Ethereum makes a lot of sense. Just like with modular data availability, we are now seeing RaaS providers adopt modular proof verification with open arms. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The big L2s have two main arguments against this approach: first, they believe it lessens the L2’s security to move proof verification to a different layer. In actuality, some of these L2s already verify their proofs offchain. They just don’t publicize that. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Their other argument is that they would prefer to aggregate proofs, by grouping a large batch of proofs together and essentially creating a “proof of proofs.” By doing that, the big L2s are able to spread the cost over a much larger number of transactions. However, they don’t seem so concerned that with this approach, it might take a few hours to aggregate hundreds of proofs, at a potentially higher cost. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Aggregation makes sense for a lot of use cases, but not necessarily for an application where you want to do something quickly and have it verified in the same amount of time. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At the end of the day, you still have to trust the L2 that you’re on.</span></p>
<h2><b>In some ways, the EVM is stuck in 2017</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As our team kept digging into the ZK space and Ethereum’s relationship with it, we discovered that Ethereum actually does have some compatibility with zero-knowledge elliptic curves using a precompile, which essentially makes it more efficient to handle the computation involved in verifying a proof. But the network currently only supports three mathematical operations on a single curve. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What does this mean for users? Since some zk-SNARKs cannot be verified, it requires the proofs to be wrapped in a more friendly form (using the bn128 proof), which results in less efficiency, more room for error, and potentially higher costs. Ideally, developers should be able to choose the zk-SNARK that best fits their application, and not being able to do so means they have to compromise on quality. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Technically, it’s possible for Ethereum to adopt more advanced precompiles over time, but it can take years for them to be implemented. The last precompile was implemented in 2017, and there have been none since. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Why is that? A lack of demand? Is it actually not feasible to implement these on Ethereum? And even if the community is able to do so, would it still be inefficient to compute with these new precompiles on the EVM?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">It’s not clear. But what is clear is that the EVM needs to be overhauled, and having ZK proofs verified onchain is still too costly for the average use case. After hardware, it’s the biggest expense when using a zk-rollup.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">At Horizen Labs, we’re tackling this in two ways: by offering modular proof verification in the form of zkVerify, and building a fully EVM-compatible chain with support for the latest zero-knowledge precompiles. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, Horizen 2.0 is built on Substrate, which allows for forkless upgrades that are automatically applied right after a community vote. No work has to be done on the node side, and no hard fork is required. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Some teams will prefer staying within a dedicated ecosystem like Horizen 2.0, with its own tight-knit community and network effects. Others will choose to go the RaaS route to build their own custom rollup, and they’ll be able to enjoy the cost savings of offchain proof verification there as well.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are multiple ways to evolve the EVM with ZK, but we believe it needs to happen before the next wave of adoption. </span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/why-ethereums-next-step-is-zero-knowledge/">Why Ethereum’s next step is zero-knowledge</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/why-ethereums-next-step-is-zero-knowledge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/ethereum-zk.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/ethereum-zk.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum&#8217;s Buterin vows to support only highly decentralized Layer-2 projects</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereums-buterin-vows-to-support-only-highly-decentralized-layer-2-projects/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereums-buterin-vows-to-support-only-highly-decentralized-layer-2-projects/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 12:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[layer2]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=443385</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin announced a change in how he will discuss Layer 2 (L2) projects starting next year. In a Sept. 12 X post, Buterin said he would only publicly recognize L2s that have reached Stage 1 or higher in their decentralization efforts regardless of his investment. He stated: &#8220;I take this seriously. Starting [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereums-buterin-vows-to-support-only-highly-decentralized-layer-2-projects/">Ethereum&#8217;s Buterin vows to support only highly decentralized Layer-2 projects</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> co-founder <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/vitalik-buterin/">Vitalik Buterin</a> announced a change in how he will discuss Layer 2 (L2) projects starting next year.</p>
<p>In a Sept. 12 X post, Buterin said he would only publicly recognize L2s that have reached Stage 1 or higher in their decentralization efforts regardless of his investment.</p>
<p>He <a href="https://x.com/VitalikButerin/status/1834061075970683367">stated</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I take this seriously. Starting next year, I plan to only publicly mention (in blogs, talks, etc) L2s that are stage 1+, with &#8216;maybe a short grace period&#8217; for new genuinely interesting projects. It doesn&#8217;t matter if I invested, or if you&#8217;re my friend; stage 1 or bust.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p data-v-f87c67ca="">Buterin outlined the criteria for Stage 1+ rollups. According to him, a network would require 75% consensus from the council to override the proof system, with at least 26% of council members being independent of the rollup.</p>
<p data-v-f87c67ca="">Buterin noted that his requests were reasonable and necessary for the security of the networks. He said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p data-v-f87c67ca="">&#8220;Stage 1 (75% threshold on council to override the proof system, 26%+ of council must be outside the rollup team) is a very reasonable moderate milestone. The multisigs I&#8217;m in have not had a single liveness failure in years, let alone 26%.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>
<p data-v-f87c67ca="">The Ethereum co-founder concluded that the &#8220;era of rollups being glorified multisigs is coming to an end. The era of cryptographic trust is upon us.&#8221;</p>
<h2>Layer-2 networks criticism</h2>
<p data-v-f87c67ca="">Buterin&#8217;s current position comes as Ethereum layer-2 networks have recently been criticized for their centralized structures.</p>
<p data-v-f87c67ca=""><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Last month, Cyber Capital&#8217;s Justin Bons raised concerns, <a href="https://x.com/Justin_Bons/status/1829908379524882828" target="_blank" rel="noopener">arguing</a> that these networks pose risks due to their centralization, potentially allowing them to steal users&#8217; funds.</span></p>
<p>However, Buterin countered that highly decentralized L2 solutions cannot take users&#8217; funds without reaching a strong consensus.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, these debates occur as Ethereum&#8217;s Layer 2 networks, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbitrum/">Arbitrum</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/optimism/">Optimism</a>, Base, and zkSync, have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/base-sees-explosive-growth-with-1-3-bn-bridged-and-6-m-users/">surged in growth</a>. Already, Over 80% of Ethereum&#8217;s transactions now occur on L2 solutions, and there are growing indications that their developments will only further accelerate due to their high level of adoption.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereums-buterin-vows-to-support-only-highly-decentralized-layer-2-projects/">Ethereum&#8217;s Buterin vows to support only highly decentralized Layer-2 projects</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereums-buterin-vows-to-support-only-highly-decentralized-layer-2-projects/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/vitalik-buterin-layer2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/vitalik-buterin-layer2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase&#8217;s Base network surpasses 1 million daily active addresses, outpaces competitors</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-base-network-surpasses-1-million-daily-active-addresses-outpaces-competitors/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-base-network-surpasses-1-million-daily-active-addresses-outpaces-competitors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 10:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Layer2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arbitrum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BASE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coinbase]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=440536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase&#8217;s layer-2 network Base has recently achieved a key milestone, hitting over 1 million daily active addresses. According to data from blockchain analytics platform GrowThePie, the Ethereum layer-2 network surpassed the 1 million mark for the first time on Aug. 24 when its active addresses reached 1.05 million. Blockchain analytics platform Token Terminal corroborated this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-base-network-surpasses-1-million-daily-active-addresses-outpaces-competitors/">Coinbase&#8217;s Base network surpasses 1 million daily active addresses, outpaces competitors</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase&#8217;s</a> layer-2 network Base has recently achieved a key milestone, hitting over 1 million daily active addresses.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://x.com/growthepie_eth/status/1828040728070520848">data</a> from blockchain analytics platform GrowThePie, the Ethereum layer-2 network surpassed the 1 million mark for the first time on Aug. 24 when its active addresses reached 1.05 million.</p>
<figure id="attachment_440566" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-440566" style="width: 892px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="wp-image-440566" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6A34XWYAA4tin.png" alt="Coinbase Base" width="892" height="431" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6A34XWYAA4tin.png 393w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6A34XWYAA4tin-300x145.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 892px) 100vw, 892px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-440566" class="wp-caption-text">Coinbase Base Daily Active Addresses (Source: GrowThePie)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Blockchain analytics platform Token Terminal corroborated this and compared Base&#8217;s growth to other layer-2 networks, concluding that Coinbase&#8217;s solution has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/base-sees-explosive-growth-with-1-3-bn-bridged-and-6-m-users/">outperformed its competitors</a>.</p>
<figure id="attachment_440567" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-440567" style="width: 900px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-440567" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6JUFBWQAAGFNZ.jpeg" alt="Base Vs Other Layer-2 networks" width="900" height="429" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6JUFBWQAAGFNZ.jpeg 900w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6JUFBWQAAGFNZ-300x143.jpeg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV6JUFBWQAAGFNZ-768x366.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-440567" class="wp-caption-text">Base Vs. Other Layer-2 Networks (Source: Token Terminal)</figcaption></figure>
<h2>Record-high transactions</h2>
<p>Unsurprisingly, this milestone has translated into a record-high number of transactions on the network.</p>
<p>GrowThePie&#8217;s data shows that Base processed more than 4 million transactions during the last 24 hours, while <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/arbitrum/">Arbitrum</a>—the largest Ethereum layer-2 network by total value locked—facilitated only 1.97 million transactions in the same period.</p>
<figure id="attachment_440569" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-440569" style="width: 1360px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-440569" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-27-105631.png" alt="Ethereum Layer-2 Networks Transaction Volume " width="1360" height="636" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-27-105631.png 1360w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-27-105631-300x140.png 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-27-105631-1024x479.png 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/Screenshot-2024-08-27-105631-768x359.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1360px) 100vw, 1360px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-440569" class="wp-caption-text">Ethereum Layer-2 Networks Transaction Volume (Source: GrowThePie)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Further, the decentralized exchange&#8217;s total trading activity across Base has soared recently. Per DeFillama&#8217;s <a href="https://defillama.com/dexs/chains">data</a>, the network now accounts for around 10% of the sector&#8217;s volume, behind <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/">Binance</a> Smart Chain (BSC) but ahead of major layer-1 blockchain networks like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/avalanche/">Avalanche</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/tron/">Tron</a>.</p>
<p>Notably, Token Terminal stated that the Base network accounts for 84% of the daily active addresses on Uniswap, the largest decentralized exchange in the industry.</p>
<figure id="attachment_440570" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-440570" style="width: 2560px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><img decoding="async" class="size-full wp-image-440570" src="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-scaled.jpg" alt="Uniswap active addresses" width="2560" height="1464" srcset="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-300x172.jpg 300w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-1024x585.jpg 1024w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-768x439.jpg 768w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-1536x878.jpg 1536w, https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/GV8U8SuWQAAFjj9-2048x1171.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /><figcaption id="caption-attachment-440570" class="wp-caption-text">Daily Active Addresses on Uniswap by Chains (Source: Token Terminal)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Market analysts highlighted the significance of these numbers, noting the strong adoption of Base despite its lack of a native token, unlike other layer-2 networks. Instead, Base has been able to attract <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/base-network-tvl-exceeds-3-billion-with-daily-users-surpassing-5-million/">increasing users</a> to its platform via its seamless interoperability features and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chainlink-tools-now-power-millions-of-transactions-on-base-network/">introduction of several innovations.</a></p>
<p>This has propelled it to become the second-largest Ethereum layer-2 network within a year of its launch. L2Beats <a href="https://l2beat.com/scaling/summary">data</a> shows that its market share stands at around 17%, with the total value of assets locked on it at $6.3 billion.</p>
<h2>Basenames launch</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, these important milestones coincide with the network&#8217;s recent launch of Basenames.</p>
<p>On Aug. 21, Base introduced Basenames, allowing users to purchase a name linked to their Base wallet addresses. This service, built on the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/ethereum-name-service/">Ethereum Name Service</a> platform, aims to enhance communication between users on Base.</p>
<p>By Aug. 26, Base&#8217;s lead developer Jesse Pollak announced that Basenames had attracted 200,000 users in its first week. Pollak also <a href="https://x.com/jessepollak/status/1828127709228306531?t=aKg-Nlnkbd9if4aENpuYZA&amp;s=19">revealed</a> that the network is exploring using multi-address domains with Basenames, allowing users to link multiple addresses to a single name.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-base-network-surpasses-1-million-daily-active-addresses-outpaces-competitors/">Coinbase&#8217;s Base network surpasses 1 million daily active addresses, outpaces competitors</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbases-base-network-surpasses-1-million-daily-active-addresses-outpaces-competitors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/base-coinbase.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/base-coinbase.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
