<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Crypto Regulation News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/regulation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/regulation/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 18:52:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Crypto Regulation News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/regulation/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Crypto industry frustrated over possibility of SEC commissioner Caroline Crenshaw’s renomination</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-industry-frustrated-over-possibility-of-sec-commissioner-caroline-crenshaws-renomination/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-industry-frustrated-over-possibility-of-sec-commissioner-caroline-crenshaws-renomination/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monika Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 18:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>On Dec 11, the U.S. Senate Banking Committee will decide whether to renominate Caroline Crenshaw, a Democrat Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) commissioner. Crenshaw has always been a staunch critic of cryptocurrencies and the crypto community is not happy with the prospect of her re-election. Crenshaw is &#8216;anti-crypto,&#8217; says Coinbase COO Crenshaw, who was sworn [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-industry-frustrated-over-possibility-of-sec-commissioner-caroline-crenshaws-renomination/">Crypto industry frustrated over possibility of SEC commissioner Caroline Crenshaw’s renomination</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Dec 11, the U.S. Senate Banking Committee will decide whether to renominate Caroline Crenshaw, a Democrat Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) commissioner. Crenshaw has always been a staunch critic of cryptocurrencies and the crypto community is not happy with the prospect of her re-election.</p>
<h2>Crenshaw is &#8216;anti-crypto,&#8217; says Coinbase COO</h2>
<p>Crenshaw, who was sworn into her role in August 2020, was one of two SEC commissioners who opposed the approval of spot Bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) in January. In her letter dissenting from the SEC&#8217;s decision, which Crenshaw called &#8220;unsound and ahistorical,&#8221; she wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I fear that today we are setting ourselves up for tomorrow’s failure, and it will be the investors that we have a duty to protect who will ultimately pay the price.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>SEC commissioner, Jaime Lizárraga, the only other SEC commissioner who voted against Bitcoin ETFs, did not add his name to her letter.</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/james-seyffart/">James Seyffart</a>, a Bloomberg ETF analyst, Crenshaw was even &#8220;<a href="https://x.com/JSeyff/status/1865147022812049635">more vehemently anti-crypto</a>&#8221; than SEC chair <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gary-gensler/">Gary Gensler</a>, who has been called &#8220;<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-chair-gary-genslers-behavior-cannot-be-chalked-off-as-good-faith-mistakes-says-tyler-winklevoss/">evil</a>&#8221; himself. In fact, she served as more than &#8220;just an ally to Gensler,&#8221; Seyffart wrote in an X <a href="https://x.com/JSeyff/status/1865147022812049635">post</a> earlier this week.</p>
<p>In a Dec. 7 X <a title="null" href="https://x.com/emiliemc/status/1865191039495024804" target="null" rel="null noopener" data-ct-non-breakable="null">post</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> president and COO Emilie Choi wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Caroline Crenshaw is anti-crypto. She even embarrassingly opposed Bitcoin ETFs. The SEC has to change.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Given Crenshaw&#8217;s widely-known opinions against crypto, the community is frustrated with the upcoming vote on Wednesday. Alexander Grieve, vice president of government affairs at crypto investment firm Paradigm, called it &#8220;one last &#8220;gift&#8221; for crypto&#8221; that Democrat Senate Banking Chair Sherrod Brown is &#8220;trying to ram through&#8221; before he gives up his chair.</p>
<p>If the Senate vote passes, Crenshaw will hold on to her position in the SEC till 2029. However, if she&#8217;s not confirmed by the Senate, president-elect <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a> will be free to nominate someone as replacement.</p>
<p>Austin Campbell, CEO of digital payments firm WSPN, wrote in an X <a href="https://x.com/CampbellJAustin/status/1865446006625648707">post</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I will remind all Democrats that Caroline Crenshaw voted that the SEC should disobey a Federal judge, break the law, and instead reject BTC ETFs after being ordered to approve them by a court.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Trump&#8217;s SEC chair pick has received the crypto community&#8217;s approval</h2>
<p>Earlier this week, Trump <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trump-confirms-nomination-of-paul-atkins-as-the-new-sec-chair/">appointed</a> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paul-atkins/">Paul Atkins</a>, a former SEC commissioner known for being pro-crypto, to be the next SEC chief. The crypto industry welcomed the news with open arms.</p>
<p>Atkins, who served as a Republican SEC commissioner from 2002 to 2008, is expected to take a much more lenient approach to regulating crypto than Gensler. Atkins is known for his advocacy of free-market principles and investor protection and his focus on clarifying complex financial markets.</p>
<p>Atkins&#8217; nomination. is &#8220;sorely needed and cannot come a day too soon,&#8221; Coinbase chief legal officer Paul Grewal said in an X post.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-industry-frustrated-over-possibility-of-sec-commissioner-caroline-crenshaws-renomination/">Crypto industry frustrated over possibility of SEC commissioner Caroline Crenshaw’s renomination</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/crypto-industry-frustrated-over-possibility-of-sec-commissioner-caroline-crenshaws-renomination/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sec-crypto.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/sec-crypto.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FSOC warns stablecoins pose stability risks, calls for legislative action to enhance oversight</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/fsoc-warns-stablecoins-pose-stability-risks-calls-for-legislative-action-to-enhance-oversight/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/fsoc-warns-stablecoins-pose-stability-risks-calls-for-legislative-action-to-enhance-oversight/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TradFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456412</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) raised concerns that stablecoins pose a mounting risk to financial stability due to inadequate oversight and significant market concentration, according to its 2024 annual report. The report called for urgent legislative action to create a comprehensive federal framework for stablecoin issuers to mitigate risks tied to their rapid growth [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fsoc-warns-stablecoins-pose-stability-risks-calls-for-legislative-action-to-enhance-oversight/">FSOC warns stablecoins pose stability risks, calls for legislative action to enhance oversight</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Financial Stability Oversight Council (FSOC) raised concerns that stablecoins pose a mounting risk to financial stability due to inadequate oversight and significant market concentration, according to its 2024 <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/261/FSOC2024AnnualReport.pdf">annual report</a>.</p>
<p>The report called for urgent legislative action to create a comprehensive federal framework for stablecoin issuers to mitigate risks tied to their <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/">rapid growth</a> and limited transparency.</p>
<p>It also called for stricter oversight of the wider crypto market amid growing integration with the traditional financial system and sustained institutional adoption.</p>
<h2>Recommendations for stablecoins</h2>
<p>The FSOC emphasized that stablecoins, often marketed as reliable digital alternatives to traditional currencies, are acutely vulnerable to runs without stringent risk management standards.</p>
<p>It also argued that the opacity surrounding issuers&#8217; reserves and operational practices further undermines market discipline and increases the potential for fraud. The report noted that one issuer accounts for approximately <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/stablecoin-market-hits-2-year-high-of-183b-amid-trump-victory-fueled-optimism/">70% of the market</a>, amplifying the risk of systemic disruptions should the entity fail. However, it did not explicitly name the entity.</p>
<p>The council urged Congress to establish a comprehensive federal prudential framework for stablecoin issuers. Recommended measures include requiring robust reserve management, setting minimum capital and liquidity standards, and implementing regular reporting obligations.</p>
<p>The report stressed that such a framework would address risks related to payment system disruptions and enhance investor and consumer protections. FSOC members also highlighted stablecoins&#8217; growing integration with traditional financial systems as a key concern.</p>
<p>The report warned that without appropriate risk management standards, any instability in the stablecoin market could cascade into broader financial markets. In the absence of legislative action, the council advised federal agencies to explore alternative regulatory measures under existing authorities.</p>
<h2>Integration with TradFi</h2>
<p>The FSOC also detailed the expanding footprint of crypto-assets in traditional markets and warned that the sector&#8217;s rising integration with traditional finance also required increased oversight.</p>
<p>While the total global market value of crypto-assets remains modest compared to traditional financial markets at just under $2 trillion, recent regulatory approvals of spot exchange-traded products (ETPs) have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bloomberg-analyst-says-altcoin-etfs-will-ignite-a-wild-crypto-market-in-2025/">heightened investor accessibility</a>. The market value of spot crypto-asset ETPs surged to nearly $80 billion in 2024 following the SEC&#8217;s approval of several listings earlier this year.</p>
<p>Despite their growth, the FSOC emphasized that the crypto-asset ecosystem remains a high-risk sector. The report identified significant gaps in regulatory oversight of the crypto spot market, citing a lack of explicit federal rulemaking authority to address fraud, market manipulation, and other risks.</p>
<p>To counter these challenges, the FSOC recommended granting federal financial regulators explicit powers to oversee crypto markets that fall outside securities regulation.</p>
<p>While acknowledging the transformative potential of digital assets, the FSOC emphasized the need for a balanced regulatory approach that supports innovation while safeguarding financial markets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fsoc-warns-stablecoins-pose-stability-risks-calls-for-legislative-action-to-enhance-oversight/">FSOC warns stablecoins pose stability risks, calls for legislative action to enhance oversight</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/fsoc-warns-stablecoins-pose-stability-risks-calls-for-legislative-action-to-enhance-oversight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/stablecoins.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/stablecoins.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEC rejecting Solana ETFs is Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;parting gift&#8217; to crypto industry – Bloomberg analyst</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 22:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) will reportedly reject two spot Solana (SOL) exchange-traded funds (ETF) applications, according to Bloomberg ETF senior analyst Eric Balchunas. Balchunas said the rejections were Chair Gary Gensler&#8217;s &#8220;parting gift&#8221; to the crypto industry. Fox News reported Eleanor Terrett revealed sources at two Solana ETF issuers told her the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/">SEC rejecting Solana ETFs is Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;parting gift&#8217; to crypto industry – Bloomberg analyst</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) will reportedly reject two spot Solana (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">SOL</a>) exchange-traded funds (ETF) applications, according to Bloomberg ETF senior analyst <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/eric-balchunas/">Eric Balchunas</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Balchunas said the rejections were Chair <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gary-gensler/">Gary Gensler&#8217;s</a> &#8220;parting gift&#8221; to the crypto industry.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fox News reported Eleanor Terrett revealed sources at two Solana ETF issuers told her the SEC will not approve any new crypto-related ETF under Gensler. He is slated to</span><strong> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-chair-gary-gensler-to-step-down-on-jan-20/">step down</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Jan. 20, 2025.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Balchunas</span> <strong><a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1865061168630374620">expects</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the issuers to file for the Solana ETFs again once <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paul-atkins/">Paul Atkins</a> begins his term as SEC chair. President-elect <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a> confirmed Atkins for the role</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trump-confirms-nomination-of-paul-atkins-as-the-new-sec-chair/">on Nov. 27</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In response to the news, former <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vaneck/">VanEck</a> digital asset strategy director <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gabor-guracs/">Gabor Gurbacs</a></span> commented<span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Gensler “<a href="https://x.com/gaborgurbacs/status/1865061656629281110">will take a hike soon,</a>” and Balchunas</span> <strong><a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1865070360703496638">replied</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;This was his parting gift I guess.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, Balchunas&#8217; fellow Bloomberg ETF analyst <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/james-seyffart/">James Seyffart</a> argued that Gensler had no choice on the Solana ETF matter, as it would be &#8220;disingenuous&#8221; to allow SOL-related exchange-traded products while the regulator claims the crypto is a security in multiple lawsuits.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, the new SEC administration will be responsible for sorting out the crypto lawsuits where SOL is considered a security. Until then, Seyffart sees applications as &#8220;dead in the water&#8221; until the watchdog decides on a new course of action. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This pushes back the Solana ETF approval timeline, which Seyffart initially projected to conclude in August 2025. Nevertheless, he added that this was the earliest of the deadlines, and he expected it would be pushed back.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Two gifts</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seyffart also highlighted that the SEC&#8217;s recent brief on the Binance case is the real parting gift, which he argued was an unnecessary move for the regulator.</span></p>
<p><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Ripple&#8217;s chief legal officer, Stuart Alderoty, recently <a href="https://x.com/s_alderoty/status/1864730425274569019" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>shared</strong></a><strong> </strong>that the regulator filed an 81-page document urging the court not to dismiss the Binance lawsuit that accuses the exchange of offering 11 tokens as investment contracts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Alderoty:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;Instead of standing down and pausing crypto litigation with new leadership just weeks away, Gensler&#8217;s SEC filed an 81-page brief in the Binance case yesterday, recycling the same failed arguments — including the absurd (and unsupported) claim that crypto has no inherent value.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/">SEC rejecting Solana ETFs is Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;parting gift&#8217; to crypto industry – Bloomberg analyst</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/gary-gensler-crypto-regulation.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/gary-gensler-crypto-regulation.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Australia intensifies crypto ATM oversight to curb money laundering risks</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto ATMs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Transaction Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC) has intensified efforts to enforce Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing (AML/CTF) regulations among crypto ATM providers. On Dec. 6, the watchdog said that crypto ATMs are increasingly used for money laundering and other illicit activities. Despite the country having around 400 registered crypto exchanges, only a small portion [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/">Australia intensifies crypto ATM oversight to curb money laundering risks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Australian Transaction Reports and Analysis Centre (AUSTRAC) has intensified efforts to enforce Anti-Money Laundering and Counter-Terrorist Financing (AML/CTF) regulations among crypto ATM providers.</p>
<p>On Dec. 6, the watchdog said that crypto ATMs are increasingly used for money laundering and other illicit activities. Despite the country having around 400 registered crypto exchanges, only a small portion operate crypto ATMs. This gap leaves a significant share of Australia&#8217;s 1,200 crypto ATMs potentially non-compliant.</p>
<p>AUSTRAC CEO Brendan Thomas highlighted the risks posed by crypto ATMs, emphasizing their appeal to criminals due to their accessibility and capability for near-instant, irreversible transactions.</p>
<p>He stated:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;We’re seeing too many Australians falling victim to scams carried out through cryptocurrency, and we’ve heard of some victims losing their life savings, which is just heart breaking. As the use of cryptocurrency increases, so too will criminal exploitation, which is why this taskforce will work to eliminate non-compliant high risk operations.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>AUSTRAC has launched a task force to ensure compliance among digital currency exchanges (DCEs) operating <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/california-to-limit-bitcoin-atm-transactions-to-1000-per-day-to-combat-fraud/">crypto ATMs</a> in order to tackle this issue. The initiative focuses on enforcing minimum compliance standards and implementing stronger safeguards to detect and prevent fraud and scams.</p>
<p>Crypto ATM operators in Australia are required to adhere to strict AML/CTF obligations. These include registering with AUSTRAC, conducting Know Your Customer (KYC) checks, monitoring transactions, and reporting cash transactions exceeding AUD 10,000 (approximately USD 6,430). Non-compliance risks significant financial penalties and swift action from the regulator.</p>
<p>Thomas warned:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Cryptocurrency ATM providers need to ensure they are complying with their money laundering obligations and are reducing the risks of crime. If they’re ignoring those obligations they risk being subject to significant financial penalties and AUSTRAC won’t hesitate in taking action.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The move aligns with a broader global trend of increased scrutiny <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">of crypto ATMs. German authorities recently <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/germany-seizes-28-million-in-raid-on-unlicensed-crypto-atms/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">seized 13 crypto ATMs</a> and €50,000 in cash due to non-compliant operations</span>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/">Australia intensifies crypto ATM oversight to curb money laundering risks</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/australia-intensifies-crypto-atm-oversight-to-curb-money-laundering-risks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/australia-crypto-atm.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/australia-crypto-atm.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coinbase exec publishes FDIC letters urging banks to halt or avoid crypto services</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-executive-publishes-fdic-letters-urging-banks-to-halt-or-avoid-crypto-services/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-executive-publishes-fdic-letters-urging-banks-to-halt-or-avoid-crypto-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Coinbase chief legal officer Paul Grewal has disclosed letters from the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to banks throughout 2022, urging them to halt or avoid crypto-related activities. The letters, which date back to March 11, 2022, have been dubbed &#8220;pause letters&#8221; due to their repeated recommendations to suspend or refrain from engaging in crypto [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-executive-publishes-fdic-letters-urging-banks-to-halt-or-avoid-crypto-services/">Coinbase exec publishes FDIC letters urging banks to halt or avoid crypto services</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinbase/">Coinbase</a> chief legal officer <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paul-grewal/">Paul Grewal</a> has disclosed letters from the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to banks throughout 2022, urging them to halt or avoid crypto-related activities.</span></p>
<p>The letters, which date back to March 11, 2022, have been dubbed &#8220;pause letters&#8221; due to their repeated recommendations to suspend or refrain from engaging in crypto services.</p>
<h2>FDIC concerns</h2>
<p>The FDIC letters cited various concerns, including the agency&#8217;s lack of clarity on regulatory requirements for crypto-related activities. One excerpt noted:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;At this time, the FDIC has not yet determined what, if any, regulatory fillings will be necessary for a bank to engage in this type of activity.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Many sections of the documents were heavily redacted, potentially to protect the proprietary nature of the services or products discussed. The FDIC also emphasized the need for additional information about the banks&#8217; crypto offerings to ensure they would operate &#8220;in a safe and sound manner.&#8221;</p>
<p>The letters further scrutinized the legal analysis conducted by banks regarding the permissibility of such activities under Part 362 of the FDIC Rules and Regulations, which governs insured state banks. This suggests that some state-chartered banks explored offering crypto-related services in 2022.</p>
<h2><strong>Operation Chokepoint 2.0</strong></h2>
<p>The release of these documents stems from Coinbase&#8217;s Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) request <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-files-foia-requests-targeting-fdic-over-crypto-banking-restrictions/">filed on Oct. 18</a>, which sought clarity on an alleged 15% deposit cap imposed on crypto-friendly banks.</p>
<p>Grewal argued that the letters provide evidence of &#8220;Operation Chokepoint 2.0,&#8221; a purported effort by the Biden administration to stifle the crypto industry. He emphasized that the claims were not a conspiracy theory and criticized the FDIC for withholding significant information through redactions and releasing only a fraction of the relevant documents.</p>
<p>He called for the incoming US administration to reverse what he described as &#8220;politically motivated regulatory decisions.&#8221;</p>
<p>According to Grewal:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;The incoming administration has the opportunity to reverse so many poor crypto policy decisions, chief among them politically motivated regulatory decisions like Operation Chokepoint 2.0.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, others in the industry also criticized the letters and raised further concerns about the involvement of the Federal Reserve, which is copied on many of the letters sent to banks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/caitlin-long/">Caitlin Long</a>, CEO and founder of Custodia Bank, said the Fed&#8217;s mention in the letters is evidence that the</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> pause letters were coordinated decisions. She also characterized the so-called pause letters as indefinite directives meant to discourage lawful crypto activities.</span></p>
<p>She said:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;These weren&#8217;t &#8216;pause letters&#8217; bc the pause was indefinite. These were really &#8216;cease &amp; desist&#8217; letters cloaked in legalese&#8230;designed to crush law-abiding #crypto.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The pause letters, spanning nearly two years and nine months, suggest a coordinated effort among regulators to limit banks&#8217; participation in cryptocurrency-related activities. Critics argue that such measures undermine the industry&#8217;s ability to innovate and expand within the US financial system.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-executive-publishes-fdic-letters-urging-banks-to-halt-or-avoid-crypto-services/">Coinbase exec publishes FDIC letters urging banks to halt or avoid crypto services</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-executive-publishes-fdic-letters-urging-banks-to-halt-or-avoid-crypto-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-operation-chokepoint.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/coinbase-operation-chokepoint.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pump Fun updates terms to block UK users days after FCA warning</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/pump-fun-updates-terms-to-block-uk-users-days-after-fca-warning/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/pump-fun-updates-terms-to-block-uk-users-days-after-fca-warning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 17:59:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456380</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pump.Fun has restricted access to users in the UK days after receiving a regulatory warning from the country&#8217;s financial watchdog. The decision comes after a Dec. 3 warning from the UK&#8217;s Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), which flagged the Solana-based memecoin launchpad for potentially offering financial products without authorization. In compliance with UK regulations, Pump.Fun updated [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/pump-fun-updates-terms-to-block-uk-users-days-after-fca-warning/">Pump Fun updates terms to block UK users days after FCA warning</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/pump-fun/">Pump.Fun</a> has restricted access to users in the UK days after receiving a <a href="https://www.fca.org.uk/news/warnings/pumpfun">regulatory warning</a> from the country&#8217;s financial watchdog.</p>
<p>The decision comes after a Dec. 3 warning from the UK&#8217;s Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), which flagged the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a>-based memecoin launchpad for potentially offering financial products without authorization.</p>
<p>In compliance with UK regulations, Pump.Fun updated its terms of service on Dec. 6 to exclude British users. Visitors from the region are now met with a notification explaining the change.</p>
<p>The FCA, the nation&#8217;s primary financial watchdog, requires all crypto firms to register before offering services to UK residents. Since the rules were introduced in 2020, only 47 out of 347 applicants have successfully obtained FCA approval, reflecting the regulator&#8217;s stringent standards.</p>
<p>By restricting access for UK users, Pump.Fun joins a growing list of crypto platforms adjusting operations to navigate regulatory challenges. However, critics argue that such actions are often reactive and do little to address underlying issues of transparency and governance.</p>
<h2>Controversy</h2>
<p>Pump.Fun, which facilitates rapid token issuance for meme-inspired cryptocurrencies, has faced <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/how-traders-make-over-60k-per-week-rugging-98-of-memecoins-on-pumpfun/">escalating scrutiny</a> in recent months. The platform, which processes 62% of decentralized exchange transactions on the Solana blockchain, gained popularity for its ability to simplify token creation.</p>
<p>However, the same ease of use has attracted allegations of misuse. The controversy intensified earlier this year when Pump.Fun introduced live-streaming capabilities, a feature aimed at enhancing community engagement and offering new tools for developers.</p>
<p>While initially well-received, the feature was soon mired in allegations of abuse, including scams and unregulated promotions conducted during streams. Critics accused the platform of failing to enforce adequate safeguards, leading to community backlash and demands for stricter oversight.</p>
<p>In response, Pump.Fun <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/solana-memecoins-turn-to-nsfw-content-as-pump-fun-livestreams-resemble-adult-webcam-site/">disabled live streaming</a>, but the damage to its reputation lingered. Regulators, already wary of the platform&#8217;s rapid growth, appeared to take notice of its perceived lack of controls.</p>
<p>Pump.Fun&#8217;s role in the memecoin boom has made it a target of both acclaim and controversy. The platform has fueled the creation of thousands of tokens, many of which have seen fleeting success.</p>
<p>Despite its success, Pump.Fun has faced persistent challenges in balancing growth with compliance. Observers note that platforms like Pump.Fun exemplifies the tension between decentralized innovation and regulatory enforcement, a dynamic that continues to shape the future of the crypto industry.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/pump-fun-updates-terms-to-block-uk-users-days-after-fca-warning/">Pump Fun updates terms to block UK users days after FCA warning</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/pump-fun-updates-terms-to-block-uk-users-days-after-fca-warning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pumpfun-uk.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/pumpfun-uk.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong races ahead with new stablecoin regulatory framework</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 15:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stablecoins]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456302</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has moved closer to formalizing its stablecoin regulations by publishing a bill in its gazette on Dec. 6 that establishes a clear framework for issuers and marketers. Stablecoins have become useful tools for cross-border transactions, with Standard Chartered recently calling them the crypto industry&#8217;s &#8220;killer app.&#8221; Under the new bill, stablecoin issuers and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/">Hong Kong races ahead with new stablecoin regulatory framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong has moved closer to formalizing its stablecoin regulations by publishing a bill in its <a href="https://www.info.gov.hk/gia/general/202412/06/P2024120500406.htm">gazette</a> on Dec. 6 that establishes a clear framework for issuers and marketers.</p>
<p>Stablecoins have become useful tools for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/standard-chartered-calls-stablecoins-cryptos-first-killer-app/">cross-border</a> transactions, with Standard Chartered recently calling them the crypto industry&#8217;s &#8220;killer app.&#8221;</p>
<p>Under the new <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-eyes-stablecoin-licensing-regime-to-bolster-crypto-stability/">bill</a>, stablecoin issuers and marketers must secure licenses from the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA). This requirement extends to stablecoins pegged to the Hong Kong dollar. Issuers must keep reserve assets in local banks, although the HKMA may occasionally allow foreign custody arrangements.</p>
<p>The legislation outlines strict compliance measures, including a minimum paid-up capital of HK$25 million (more than $3 million). Issuers must also demonstrate strong financial health, liquidity, and risk management capabilities. Activities like misrepresentation to promote stablecoins are prohibited to ensure consumer protection and market integrity.</p>
<p>Additionally, the HKMA will gain enhanced powers to oversee, investigate, and enforce compliance under this framework.</p>
<p>The initiative reflects Hong Kong&#8217;s commitment to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-adds-bybit-to-its-list-of-suspicious-crypto-exchanges/">addressing financial risks</a> while fostering innovation. Officials have emphasized that the framework aligns with international standards and embodies a principle of applying consistent regulation to similar activities and risks.</p>
<p>Christopher Hui, Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury, pointed out that the proposal aligns with the &#8220;same activity, same risks, same regulation&#8221; principle. This ensures the framework meets global standards and reinforces Hong Kong&#8217;s position as a leading financial hub.</p>
<p>Eddie Yue, Chief Executive of the HKMA, highlighted that the bill incorporates feedback from industry consultations and aims to foster sustainable growth within the stablecoin ecosystem.</p>
<p>The bill is set for a first reading in the Legislative Council on Dec. 18. If passed, Hong Kong will join early movers like the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/european-stablecoin-market-declines-under-newly-imposed-mica-rules/">European Union</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dmm-crypto-explores-stablecoin-launch-under-japans-regulations/">Japan</a> in regulating stablecoins while outpacing other jurisdictions like the US, which has yet to implement similar frameworks.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/">Hong Kong races ahead with new stablecoin regulatory framework</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-races-ahead-with-new-stablecoin-regulation-framework/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/hongkong-1.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/hongkong-1.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Long term Bitcoin HODLers in Czech Republic to pay zero capital gains tax from January</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/long-term-bitcoin-hodlers-in-czech-republic-to-pay-zero-capital-gains-tax-from-january/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/long-term-bitcoin-hodlers-in-czech-republic-to-pay-zero-capital-gains-tax-from-january/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 14:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Taxes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456315</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic approved an amendment granting exemptions for income from cryptoasset transfers. The move, passed on Dec. 6 and set to take effect on Jan. 1, 2025, introduces conditions under which individuals may exclude such income from personal taxation, echoing some established rules applied to securities. Under the new framework, individuals can claim an [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/long-term-bitcoin-hodlers-in-czech-republic-to-pay-zero-capital-gains-tax-from-january/">Long term Bitcoin HODLers in Czech Republic to pay zero capital gains tax from January</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Czech Republic <a href="https://x.com/BTCPrague/status/1865010348476059740">approved</a> an amendment granting exemptions for income from cryptoasset transfers. The move, passed on Dec. 6 and set to take effect on Jan. 1, 2025, introduces conditions under which individuals may exclude such income from personal taxation, echoing some established rules applied to securities.</p>
<p>Under the <a href="https://danovky.cz/en/news/detail/1540">new framework</a>, individuals can claim an exemption if the total gross annual income from these transactions does not exceed CZK 100,000 and, separately, if digital assets are held for more than three years before the sale.</p>
<p>As Czech consulting firm BDO <a href="https://www.bdo.cz/en-gb/insights/tax/proposal-to-exempt-income-of-natural-persons-from-the-transfer-of-crypto-assets-for-consideration?t">explained</a>, the legislation parallels exemptions granted to securities transfers, although the threshold for the time test involves a CZK 40 million aggregate limit that also applies to gains from securities and business shares. The measure excludes electronic cash tokens and requires that digital assets are not part of business assets for at least three years after ceasing self-employment.</p>
<p>This initiative appears to align with broader efforts at clarifying digital asset taxation. Implementation would follow ongoing digitalization measures and possible EU-level regulations, and per <a href="https://kpmg.com/us/en/taxnewsflash/news/2024/10/tnf-czech-republic-proposed-exemption-from-individual-income-tax-for-income-from-transfer-of-cryptoassets.html?t">KPMG</a>, the proposal relies on principles already familiar from securities exemptions. The absence of transitional provisions means digital assets acquired before 2025 may also qualify if sold under these conditions in subsequent tax years, but this raises questions of interpretation.</p>
<p>Without a dedicated definition of digital assets in the Income Tax Act, the scope of the exemption could extend across multiple types of crypto holdings. Interpretive uncertainties remain, as the amendment does not specify how to confirm the length of ownership, and it lacks an explanatory memorandum to clarify legislative intent or address technical ambiguities.</p>
<p>Recent market conditions provide context for shifting regulatory stances. In November, after the U.S. election, Bitcoin reached record highs approaching $100,000, reflecting heightened activity and market interest. Although the amendment focuses on the Czech Republic&#8217;s domestic tax environment, it emerges as one among various regulatory adjustments in response to evolving digital asset markets. Some observers note this approach may encourage long-term holding strategies.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/press-releases/legendary-investor-michael-saylor-to-speak-at-europes-largest-bitcoin-conference-btc-prague/">BTC Prague</a> reported, the vote in favor of the exemption framework was <a href="https://x.com/BTCPrague/status/1865010348476059740">unanimous</a>, potentially signaling domestic consensus on encouraging compliant crypto engagement through predictable rules.</p>
<p>The Czech authorities have not indicated any immediate guidance or clarifications on the new rules, leaving practitioners and taxpayers to rely on general principles. The forthcoming effective date could prompt advisors, exchanges, and individual holders to review record-keeping practices, ensuring alignment with a three-year holding criterion and aggregate transaction limits.</p>
<p>Although the legislation&#8217;s concise wording may invite future interpretative challenges, the core exemption provisions are now established.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/long-term-bitcoin-hodlers-in-czech-republic-to-pay-zero-capital-gains-tax-from-january/">Long term Bitcoin HODLers in Czech Republic to pay zero capital gains tax from January</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/long-term-bitcoin-hodlers-in-czech-republic-to-pay-zero-capital-gains-tax-from-january/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bitcoin-czech.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bitcoin-czech.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean watchdog squashes rumors of corporate crypto roadmap</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-watchdog-squashes-rumors-of-corporate-crypto-roadmap/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-watchdog-squashes-rumors-of-corporate-crypto-roadmap/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>South Korea&#8217;s Financial Services Commission (FSC) denied reports claiming the government has finalized a roadmap for issuing real-name crypto accounts to corporations, including public institutions and nonprofit organizations, according to a Dec. 4 press release. Local media outlets, including Hankyung, reported earlier in the day that the FSC planned to release a roadmap by the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-watchdog-squashes-rumors-of-corporate-crypto-roadmap/">South Korean watchdog squashes rumors of corporate crypto roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>South Korea&#8217;s Financial Services Commission (FSC) denied reports claiming the government has finalized a roadmap for issuing real-name crypto accounts to corporations, including public institutions and nonprofit organizations, according to a Dec. 4 <a href="https://www.fsc.go.kr/no010102/83516">press release</a>.</p>
<p>Local media outlets, including Hankyung, reported earlier in the day that the FSC planned to release a roadmap by the end of December, outlining a phased approach to corporate crypto account issuance.</p>
<p>The reports suggested that nonprofit organizations, such as universities and local governments, would be prioritized in the first phase, with broader inclusion of businesses and financial institutions being considered in later stages. The articles also attributed the prioritization of nonprofits to the need for crypto accounts to facilitate liquidity rather than investment purposes.</p>
<p>In an official statement, the FSC clarified that no decisions have been made regarding the issuance of real-name crypto accounts for corporations. The regulator emphasized that the issue remains under review and is being discussed through the Virtual Asset Committee, which engages stakeholders, including government agencies, private sector experts, and financial institutions.</p>
<p>The FSC said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The roadmap for corporate virtual asset accounts is still undergoing additional discussions, and no concrete regulatory measures have been finalized. We urge caution in interpreting speculative reports.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>South Korea has been <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-politicians-agree-to-implement-2-year-moratorium-on-crypto-taxation/">cautious in its approach</a> to crypto regulation, often balancing innovation with concerns over speculative trading and potential misuse. While individuals can access crypto trading platforms under strict identification protocols, corporate access remains restricted amid ongoing deliberations on security and compliance issues.</p>
<p>Industry experts say a formal policy allowing corporate crypto accounts could be a significant step for South Korea&#8217;s digital asset ecosystem. However, given the global scrutiny of crypto regulations and the risks associated with fraud and money laundering, regulators are likely to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korea-to-regulate-cross-border-crypto-trades-by-2025/">proceed cautiously</a>.</p>
<p>The FSC has called for accurate reporting on developments to prevent misinformation as it continues to evaluate comprehensive policies for the crypto sector.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-watchdog-squashes-rumors-of-corporate-crypto-roadmap/">South Korean watchdog squashes rumors of corporate crypto roadmap</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/south-korean-watchdog-squashes-rumors-of-corporate-crypto-roadmap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea-2.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/south-korea-2.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Circle balances compliance in Canada with operational efficiency through staff layoffs</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Circle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDC]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Circle has become the first stablecoin issuer to meet Canada&#8217;s new listing requirements for its USD Coin (USDC), marking a significant milestone amid ongoing reports of layoffs within the company. In a Dec. 4 post on X, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire announced that USDC is the first of the top dollar-backed stablecoins to comply with [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/">Circle balances compliance in Canada with operational efficiency through staff layoffs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/circle/">Circle</a> has become the first stablecoin issuer to meet Canada&#8217;s new listing requirements for its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/usd-coin/">USD Coin (USDC)</a>, marking a significant milestone amid ongoing reports of layoffs within the company.</p>
<p>In a Dec. 4 <a href="https://x.com/jerallaire/status/1864391925312139351">post</a> on X, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire announced that USDC is the first of the top dollar-backed stablecoins to comply with Canada&#8217;s updated regulations for digital assets.</p>
<p>The rules, set by the Ontario Securities Commission (OSC) and the Canadian Securities Administrators (CSA), cover Value-Referenced Crypto Assets (VRCA).</p>
<p>The compliance means USDC will remain available on registered crypto exchanges and trading platforms in Canada. These platforms must meet the new VRCA standards by Dec. 31, and non-compliant stablecoins will be delisted.</p>
<p>Several notable crypto firms, including <span style="color: #333333;"><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/gemini-to-exit-canadian-market-by-end-of-2024-amid-regulatory-shifts/">Gemini</a>, </span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/binance/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Binance</a>,<span style="color: #333333;"> and </span><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/paxos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Paxos</a>, have <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/paxos-becomes-latest-crypto-company-to-end-services-in-canada/">exited the Canadian market</a> in the past year, citing regulatory challenges. These departures followed the Canadian government&#8217;s introduction of stricter rules for the crypto industry.</p>
<p>However, Circle&#8217;s Head of Global Policy, Dante Disparte, highlighted that USDC&#8217;s continued presence in Canada demonstrates the company&#8217;s commitment to global regulatory standards.</p>
<p>He emphasized that Canada&#8217;s forward-thinking approach to regulation enhances the integrity of digital asset markets while supporting USDC&#8217;s use within the country&#8217;s growing ecosystem.</p>
<h2>Workforce reduction</h2>
<p>At the same time, Circle&#8217;s regulatory success coincides with reports of a 6% workforce reduction within the company, Bloomberg <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-05/usdc-stablecoin-issuer-circle-makes-layoffs-seeks-ai-led-boost?embedded-checkout=true">reported</a>.</p>
<p>A Circle spokesperson reportedly clarified that the layoffs were part of routine operational reviews to optimize investments and manage expenses. The spokesperson added that the firm continues to invest in critical teams and infrastructure while slightly scaling back on certain roles in other areas.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the company remains focused on expanding its geographic footprint, particularly in areas like Artificial Intelligence.</p>
<p>These moves coincide with USDC&#8217;s continued dominance as the second-largest stablecoin in the crypto market. According to <em>CryptoSlate&#8217;s</em> data, the digital asset controls 20% of the market with its $40 billion supply.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/">Circle balances compliance in Canada with operational efficiency through staff layoffs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/circle-balances-compliance-in-canada-with-operational-efficiency-through-strategic-layoffs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/circle-canada.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/circle-canada.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
