<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>ETF News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/etf/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/etf/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 21:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ETF News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/etf/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>SEC rejecting Solana ETFs is Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;parting gift&#8217; to crypto industry – Bloomberg analyst</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 22:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=456401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) will reportedly reject two spot Solana (SOL) exchange-traded funds (ETF) applications, according to Bloomberg ETF senior analyst Eric Balchunas. Balchunas said the rejections were Chair Gary Gensler&#8217;s &#8220;parting gift&#8221; to the crypto industry. Fox News reported Eleanor Terrett revealed sources at two Solana ETF issuers told her the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/">SEC rejecting Solana ETFs is Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;parting gift&#8217; to crypto industry – Bloomberg analyst</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) will reportedly reject two spot Solana (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">SOL</a>) exchange-traded funds (ETF) applications, according to Bloomberg ETF senior analyst <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/eric-balchunas/">Eric Balchunas</a>.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Balchunas said the rejections were Chair <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gary-gensler/">Gary Gensler&#8217;s</a> &#8220;parting gift&#8221; to the crypto industry.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Fox News reported Eleanor Terrett revealed sources at two Solana ETF issuers told her the SEC will not approve any new crypto-related ETF under Gensler. He is slated to</span><strong> <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-chair-gary-gensler-to-step-down-on-jan-20/">step down</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on Jan. 20, 2025.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Balchunas</span> <strong><a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1865061168630374620">expects</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the issuers to file for the Solana ETFs again once <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/paul-atkins/">Paul Atkins</a> begins his term as SEC chair. President-elect <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a> confirmed Atkins for the role</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/trump-confirms-nomination-of-paul-atkins-as-the-new-sec-chair/">on Nov. 27</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In response to the news, former <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vaneck/">VanEck</a> digital asset strategy director <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/gabor-guracs/">Gabor Gurbacs</a></span> commented<span style="font-weight: 400;"> that Gensler “<a href="https://x.com/gaborgurbacs/status/1865061656629281110">will take a hike soon,</a>” and Balchunas</span> <strong><a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1865070360703496638">replied</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;This was his parting gift I guess.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, Balchunas&#8217; fellow Bloomberg ETF analyst <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/james-seyffart/">James Seyffart</a> argued that Gensler had no choice on the Solana ETF matter, as it would be &#8220;disingenuous&#8221; to allow SOL-related exchange-traded products while the regulator claims the crypto is a security in multiple lawsuits.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As a result, the new SEC administration will be responsible for sorting out the crypto lawsuits where SOL is considered a security. Until then, Seyffart sees applications as &#8220;dead in the water&#8221; until the watchdog decides on a new course of action. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This pushes back the Solana ETF approval timeline, which Seyffart initially projected to conclude in August 2025. Nevertheless, he added that this was the earliest of the deadlines, and he expected it would be pushed back.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Two gifts</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seyffart also highlighted that the SEC&#8217;s recent brief on the Binance case is the real parting gift, which he argued was an unnecessary move for the regulator.</span></p>
<p><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Ripple&#8217;s chief legal officer, Stuart Alderoty, recently <a href="https://x.com/s_alderoty/status/1864730425274569019" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>shared</strong></a><strong> </strong>that the regulator filed an 81-page document urging the court not to dismiss the Binance lawsuit that accuses the exchange of offering 11 tokens as investment contracts.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to Alderoty:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;Instead of standing down and pausing crypto litigation with new leadership just weeks away, Gensler&#8217;s SEC filed an 81-page brief in the Binance case yesterday, recycling the same failed arguments — including the absurd (and unsupported) claim that crypto has no inherent value.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/">SEC rejecting Solana ETFs is Gensler&#8217;s &#8216;parting gift&#8217; to crypto industry – Bloomberg analyst</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/sec-rejecting-solana-etfs-is-genslers-parting-gift-to-crypto-industry-bloomberg-analyst/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/gary-gensler-crypto-regulation.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/gary-gensler-crypto-regulation.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grayscale files application to convert Solana trust into spot ETF</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-files-application-to-convert-solana-trust-into-spot-etf/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-files-application-to-convert-solana-trust-into-spot-etf/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 23:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Grayscale Investments has taken another step to expand its footprint in the digital asset market, filing with the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to convert its Grayscale Solana Trust into a spot exchange-traded fund (ETF). If approved, the ETF would trade under the ticker symbol GSOL on the New York Stock Exchange, offering investors [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-files-application-to-convert-solana-trust-into-spot-etf/">Grayscale files application to convert Solana trust into spot ETF</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Grayscale Investments has taken another step to expand its footprint in the digital asset market, filing with the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to convert its Grayscale Solana Trust into a spot exchange-traded fund (ETF).</p>
<p>If approved, the ETF would trade under the ticker symbol GSOL on the New York Stock Exchange, offering investors direct exposure to Solana (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">SOL</a>), one of the fastest-growing blockchain platforms in the crypto ecosystem.</p>
<p>The filing, submitted as a 19b-4 request, marks Grayscale&#8217;s continued push to transform its existing crypto trusts into fully regulated ETFs. The firm has already achieved this for its flagship Bitcoin and Ether investment products, which now trade as spot ETFs following SEC approval earlier this year.</p>
<p>According to the filing, the Grayscale Solana Trust is currently the world&#8217;s largest Solana-focused investment fund, managing approximately $134.2 million in assets as of the filing date.</p>
<p>The news caused SOL to surge almost 7% to $238 before a minor retrace to $234 as of press time.</p>
<h2>Heightened competition</h2>
<p>Grayscale’s move comes amid <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/canary-capital-joins-solana-etf-race-amid-rising-investor-demand/">intensifying competition</a> among asset managers seeking to launch the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/21shares-becomes-second-major-firm-to-apply-for-a-spot-solana-etf-this-week/">first spot Solana ETF</a>.</p>
<p>Other players, including <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/21shares/">21Shares</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/canary-capital/">Canary Capital</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vaneck/">VanEck</a>, and Bitwise, have already submitted similar filings, signaling a race to secure regulatory approval. The growing interest reflects Solana&#8217;s rising prominence in the crypto space, fueled by its rapid adoption and innovative technology.</p>
<p>Over the past year, Solana has experienced a 275% surge in value, driven by its appeal as a scalable and cost-efficient alternative to Ethereum. Its current market capitalization exceeds $110 billion, making it one of the largest cryptocurrencies by market value.</p>
<p>This meteoric rise has increased demand for investment products tied to Solana, positioning ETFs as a convenient entry point for institutional and retail investors alike.</p>
<h2>Regulatory Uncertainty Lingers</h2>
<p>Despite the enthusiasm, the SEC has yet to approve any spot ETF linked to Solana or similar altcoins. The agency&#8217;s cautious approach to crypto ETFs, particularly spot products, stems from concerns about market manipulation, liquidity, and investor protection.</p>
<p>However, Grayscale and other issuers remain optimistic that the SEC will eventually greenlight these products, given the growing maturity of the crypto market and advancements in regulatory oversight, especially under the <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vanecks-matthew-sigel-confirms-solana-etf-is-a-bet-on-trump-victory/">incoming Trump administration</a>.</p>
<p>Grayscale has positioned its filing as part of a broader effort to expand access to digital assets through traditional financial products.</p>
<p>In a statement accompanying the filing, the company emphasized the potential of ETFs to bridge the gap between institutional-grade investment opportunities and individual investors seeking exposure to emerging technologies like blockchain.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-files-application-to-convert-solana-trust-into-spot-etf/">Grayscale files application to convert Solana trust into spot ETF</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/grayscale-files-application-to-convert-solana-trust-into-spot-etf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/grayscale-solana.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/grayscale-solana.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethereum and XRP soar with $270 million inflow as investors flock to altcoins</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitcoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethereum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Digital asset investment products experienced their second-lowest weekly inflows in the past eight weeks, totaling $270 million, according to CoinShares&#8216; latest fund flow report. This brings the total year-to-date inflow to $37.3 billion. James Butterfill, Head of Research at CoinShares, highlighted an unusual contrast in the flows across different assets within the class. He noted [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/">Ethereum and XRP soar with $270 million inflow as investors flock to altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Digital asset investment products experienced their second-lowest weekly inflows in the past eight weeks, totaling $270 million, according to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/coinshares/">CoinShares</a>&#8216; latest fund flow <a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-211-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-2b8c701cfe06">report</a>. This brings the total year-to-date inflow to $37.3 billion.</p>
<p>James Butterfill, Head of Research at CoinShares, highlighted an unusual contrast in the flows across different assets within the class. He noted that the minimal inflow was partly due to the impact of newly launched options on products.</p>
<p>Despite their high initial volumes, options on US ETFs have not driven a comparable rise in ETP volumes, which dropped from $34 billion the previous week to $22 billion.</p>
<h2>Ethereum, XRP outperforms Bitcoin.</h2>
<p>While <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> has been the market&#8217;s standout performer over the past year, large-cap alternative digital currencies like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">Ethereum</a> and XRP outperformed the flagship digital asset last week.</p>
<p>According to the CoinShares report, Bitcoin faced its first significant outflow since early September, with $457 million flowing out. This outflow likely reflects profit-taking amid <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitcoin-predicted-to-hit-100k-by-inauguration-day-amid-record-pre-market-equities-trading/">Bitcoin&#8217;s recent rally toward $100,000.</a></p>
<p>In contrast, Ethereum has experienced a strong turnaround, attracting $634 million in inflows. This boosted its year-to-date inflow to $2.2 billion, surpassing the $2 billion it received in 2021.</p>
<p>XRP also saw a record inflow of $95 million, driven by growing optimism around the asset and expectations of a potential <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/">XRP ETF launch in the US</a>. Notably, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">XRP&#8217;s price reached a seven-year high</a> after it surpassed $2, and its market capitalization hit a new peak of over $150 billion.</p>
<h2>US, Hong Kong lead flows.</h2>
<p>Regionally, the US led with $266 million in inflows, followed by Germany with $12.3 million. Switzerland and Canada experienced small outflows totaling $26 million and $10 million, respectively.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, crypto ETPs saw a notable $39 million in inflows, driven by the strong performance of Bitcoin ETFs.</p>
<p>According to SoSo Value <a href="https://sosovalue.com/assets/etf/hk-btc-spot">data</a>, the three Hong Kong Bitcoin spot ETFs are nearing $500 million in net assets. The ChinaAMC Bitcoin ETF leads with $277.48 million, followed by the Bosera Hashkey Bitcoin ETF with $153 million. The Harvest Bitcoin Spot ETF holds around $40 million in assets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/">Ethereum and XRP soar with $270 million inflow as investors flock to altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ethereum-and-xrp-soar-with-270-million-inflow-as-investors-flock-to-altcoins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ethereum-inflow.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/ethereum-inflow.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WisdomTree joins race for spot XRP ETF as 4th filing amid impending SEC leadership change</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 14:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Spot Bitcoin ETF issuer WisdomTree has filed a Form S-1 registration statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to launch a spot XRP exchange-traded fund (ETF). WisdomTree joins Bitwise, 21Shares, and Canary Capital in seeking SEC approval for spot XRP ETFs. As Eleanor Terrett of Fox Business reported, this collective move indicates growing institutional [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/">WisdomTree joins race for spot XRP ETF as 4th filing amid impending SEC leadership change</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Spot Bitcoin ETF issuer WisdomTree has filed a Form S-1 registration statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to launch a spot XRP exchange-traded fund (ETF).</p>
<p>WisdomTree joins Bitwise, 21Shares, and Canary Capital in seeking SEC approval for spot XRP ETFs. As Eleanor Terrett of Fox Business <a href="https://x.com/EleanorTerrett/status/1863559841341485547">reported</a>, this collective move indicates growing institutional interest in XRP as an investable asset class, especially given the impending <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-chair-gary-gensler-to-step-down-on-jan-20/">end</a> to Gary Gensler&#8217;s tenure at the SEC.</p>
<p>The proposed ETF would track the performance of XRP, with Bank of New York Mellon designated as the trust administrator. This initiative comes as XRP has demonstrated strong market <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/xrp-flips-solana-market-cap-soars-to-seven-year-high-fueled-by-south-korean-traders/">performance</a>, recently surpassing Tether&#8217;s USDT to become the third-largest digital asset by market capitalization.</p>
<p>Over the past week, XRP&#8217;s price surged to $2.42, representing a 68% gain and pushing its market capitalization beyond the $135 billion mark.</p>
<p>The timing of these ETF filings coincides with significant shifts in the regulatory and political landscape. President Donald Trump&#8217;s recent election victory suggests the possibility of more crypto-friendly policies under the new administration. Further, rumors <a href="https://www.foxbusiness.com/video/6364768291112">indicate</a> ongoing discussions between Ripple Labs, the company behind XRP, and the Republican administration.</p>
<p>However, the approval process remains uncertain for now due to the ongoing legal <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-resolute-as-sec-does-not-appeal-verdict-not-a-security-focuses-on-exchange-sales/">dispute</a> between Ripple Labs and the SEC. Though Gensler&#8217;s successor could well expedite approval, especially given Ripple&#8217;s US heritage, something Trump has been <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/no-capital-tax-on-us-crypto-bitcoin-reserve-asset-nation-state-adoption-the-biggest-trump-rumors/">vocal</a> in promoting.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/">WisdomTree joins race for spot XRP ETF as 4th filing amid impending SEC leadership change</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-joins-race-for-spot-xrp-etf-as-4th-filing-amid-impending-sec-leadership-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-etf.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/xrp-etf.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bloomberg analyst says altcoin ETFs will ignite a &#8216;wild&#8217; crypto market in 2025</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bloomberg-analyst-says-altcoin-etfs-will-ignite-a-wild-crypto-market-in-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bloomberg-analyst-says-altcoin-etfs-will-ignite-a-wild-crypto-market-in-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 18:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Bloomberg senior ETF analyst Eric Balchunas stated that unless a big collapse happens, the altcoin-related exchange-traded funds (ETF) awaiting approval will make crypto &#8220;pretty wild.&#8221; He shared that 14 altcoin-related ETFs await approval by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in the next 12 months, including funds giving exposure to Solana (SOL), XRP, Hedera [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bloomberg-analyst-says-altcoin-etfs-will-ignite-a-wild-crypto-market-in-2025/">Bloomberg analyst says altcoin ETFs will ignite a &#8216;wild&#8217; crypto market in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bloomberg senior ETF analyst <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/eric-balchunas/">Eric Balchunas</a> stated that unless a big collapse happens, the altcoin-related exchange-traded funds (ETF) awaiting approval will make crypto &#8220;pretty wild.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He</span> <strong><a href="https://x.com/EricBalchunas/status/1861802009021575237">shared</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that 14 altcoin-related ETFs await approval by the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in the next 12 months, including funds giving exposure to Solana (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">SOL</a>), <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a>, Hedera (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/hedera/">HBAR</a>), Litecoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/litecoin/">LTC</a>), baskets of assets, and Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) and Ethereum (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">ETH</a>) simultaneously.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, Balchunas expects the list of altcoin ETFs to triple in size in the next two months.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Favorable environment</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Following President <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/donald-trump/">Donald Trump</a> victory in the US elections, ETF Store CEO Nate Geraci predicted that several spot crypto ETFs</span> <strong><a href="https://x.com/NateGeraci/status/1855794053423452381">would be listed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">. He stated:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;Assume multiple issuers were highly prepared for election results. No downside to getting aggressive now.&#8221;</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Asset managers registered three new ETF listings since Geraci&#8217;s publication. On Nov. 12, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/canary-capital/">Canary Capital</a></span> filed for<span style="font-weight: 400;"> an <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/canary-capital-files-application-for-a-spot-hbar-etf/">HBAR ETF</a>, which surprised some market analysts, given the expectation that issuers would choose more prominent crypto among the 50 largest by market cap.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Moreover, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitwise/">Bitwise</a> registered a</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitwise-registers-solana-trust-signalling-future-sec-application-for-sol-spot-etf/">SOL trust</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> in Delaware on Nov. 21, and five days later, NYSE</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nyse-files-to-list-bitwises-bitcoin-and-ethereum-mixed-etp/">filed to list</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the asset manager&#8217;s mixed BTC and ETH ETF.</span></p>
<p><span style="box-sizing: border-box; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Bloomberg ETF analyst <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/james-seyffart/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">James Seyffart</a> believes that the SEC will likely approve Solana-related ETFs <a href="https://x.com/JSeyff/status/1861792629614059898">within two years</a>. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, he added that the current administration could &#8220;very easily&#8221; fail to acknowledge these ETFs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Seyffart highlighted that this had already happened in August when the Cboe removed the 19b-4 Form filing to list <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vaneck/">VanEck</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/21shares/">21Shares&#8217;</a> Solana ETFs registered in July.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, the Litecoin ETF filed by Canary in October has a higher chance of approval. Alex Thorn, head of research at <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/galaxy-digital/">Galaxy Digital</a>,</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/canary-capital-files-s-1-application-for-first-spot-litecoin-etf-in-the-us/">previously told</a></strong> <i><span style="font-weight: 400;">CryptoSlate</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> that the LTC launch is often considered fair, given the absence of a pre-mine or token sale.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Although the SEC&#8217;s position remains unclear, Thorn believes the regulator is unlikely to label LTC as a security.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bloomberg-analyst-says-altcoin-etfs-will-ignite-a-wild-crypto-market-in-2025/">Bloomberg analyst says altcoin ETFs will ignite a &#8216;wild&#8217; crypto market in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bloomberg-analyst-says-altcoin-etfs-will-ignite-a-wild-crypto-market-in-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/altcoins-etf-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/altcoins-etf-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple invests in Bitwise XRP fund amid new XRPL Foundation launch</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-invests-in-bitwise-xrp-fund-amid-new-xrpl-foundation-launch/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-invests-in-bitwise-xrp-fund-amid-new-xrpl-foundation-launch/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 15:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ripple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xrp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[XRPL]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain firm Ripple is among the four founding members of the newly incorporated XRP Ledger (XRPL) Foundation. Established on Nov. 26 in France, the organization aims to unify and govern the broader XRPL ecosystem. The foundation brings together Ripple, XRPL Labs, XRPL Commons, the former XRPL Foundation, and key members of the XRP community. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-invests-in-bitwise-xrp-fund-amid-new-xrpl-foundation-launch/">Ripple invests in Bitwise XRP fund amid new XRPL Foundation launch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blockchain firm <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ripple/">Ripple</a> is among the four founding members of the newly incorporated XRP Ledger (XRPL) Foundation.</p>
<p>Established on Nov. 26 in France, the <a href="https://xrpl.org/blog/2024/a-new-era-for-the-xrp-ledger">organization</a> aims to unify and govern the broader XRPL ecosystem. The foundation brings together Ripple, XRPL Labs, XRPL Commons, the former XRPL Foundation, and key members of the XRP community.</p>
<p>The foundation is committed to ensuring long-term growth, security, and decentralized contributions to the XRPL. Its primary mission is to foster a thriving, inclusive, and resilient XRPL community. Developers and users will have a trusted platform to create decentralized applications, financial tools, and blockchain infrastructure.</p>
<p>The group&#8217;s initial focus will be reclaiming assets from the previous XRPL Foundation. It also plans to implement a governance model representing developers, users, validators, academia, and infrastructure providers. Key contributors—including XRPL Commons, XRPL Labs, Ripple, and XAO DAO—will guide the foundation through board representation and decision-making roles.</p>
<p>The XRPL blockchain continues to gain traction for its scalability, low costs, and regulatory compliance. Notably, its growing <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-launches-first-tokenized-money-market-fund-on-xrp-ledger-through-uk-partnership/">role in tokenizing real-world assets (RWAs)</a> has attracted major institutional players like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/societe-generale-expands-its-stablecoin-to-ripples-xrp-ledger-to-drive-further-adoption/">SG-FORGE, the crypto division of Societe Generale.</a></p>
<h2>Support for Bitwise XRP Fund</h2>
<p>Meanwhile, Ripple is also ramping up support for <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a> through a strategic investment in <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitwise/">Bitwise&#8217;s</a> newly rebranded Physical XRP Exchange-Traded Product (ETP).</p>
<p>Formerly known as ETC Group Physical XRP, the product exposes European investors to XRP through a physically backed structure holding the token.</p>
<p>Bitwise CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/hunter-horsley/">Hunter Horsley</a> emphasized XRP&#8217;s reputation as one of the most recognized and reliable blockchain networks. He <a href="https://etc-group.com/newsroom/Press_Release_27_11_2024/">added</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;XRP and the XRP Ledger are among the most familiar and trusted blockchains in crypto. XRPL is unique with over 10 years of track record in reliability, while continuing to expand in capabilities.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Ripple CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/brad-garlinghouse/">Brad Garlinghouse</a> echoed this sentiment while noting a surge in global demand for crypto-backed investment products. He noted that recent regulatory clarity in the US will likely accelerate this trend, further boosting interest in offerings like the Bitwise Physical XRP ETP.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-invests-in-bitwise-xrp-fund-amid-new-xrpl-foundation-launch/">Ripple invests in Bitwise XRP fund amid new XRPL Foundation launch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ripple-invests-in-bitwise-xrp-fund-amid-new-xrpl-foundation-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitwise-xrp.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bitwise-xrp.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NYSE files to list Bitwise&#8217;s Bitcoin and Ethereum mixed ETP</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/nyse-files-to-list-bitwises-bitcoin-and-ethereum-mixed-etp/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/nyse-files-to-list-bitwises-bitcoin-and-ethereum-mixed-etp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 23:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454823</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NYSE Arca filed a 19b-4 Form to list a Bitwise exchange-traded product (ETP) offering direct spot exposure to Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH), weighted by their market capitalization. According to a Bitwise statement, the proposed Bitcoin-Ether ETP aims at simplifying portfolio allocation for investors seeking exposure to the crypto market’s most established assets. Its market-cap [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nyse-files-to-list-bitwises-bitcoin-and-ethereum-mixed-etp/">NYSE files to list Bitwise&#8217;s Bitcoin and Ethereum mixed ETP</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">NYSE Arca</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">filed</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> a 19b-4 Form to list a Bitwise exchange-traded product (ETP) offering direct spot exposure to Bitcoin (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">BTC</a>) and Ethereum (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/ethereum/">ETH</a>), weighted by their market capitalization.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to a Bitwise</span> <strong><a href="https://bitwiseinvestments.com/newsroom/nyse-arca-files-form-19b-4-for-bitwise-bitcoin-and-ethereum-etp">statement</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the proposed Bitcoin-Ether ETP aims at simplifying portfolio allocation for investors seeking exposure to the crypto market’s most established assets. Its market-cap weighting ensures that the fund dynamically adjusts to reflect these assets&#8217; evolving dominance.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitwise CIO Matt Hougan stated:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“Bitcoin and ether aren’t competitors any more than gold and tech stocks are competitors. So when investors ask us which is better to add to their portfolio, often our answer is ‘both.’ This fund aims to make that recommendation easy and actionable, providing balanced exposure to the world’s two largest crypto assets. I think it’s going to be a huge hit with investors.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bitwise&#8217;s spot Bitcoin and Ethereum ETPs have collectively amassed $4.2 billion in assets under management.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If approved, this dual-asset ETP would be a first-of-its-kind product in the US market, allowing investors simultaneous exposure to the two largest cryptocurrencies.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">However, other similar products are also waiting for approval. The US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/sec-delays-decision-on-franklin-templetons-crypto-index-etf-to-2025/">recently delayed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the approval of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/franklin-templeton/">Franklin Templeton&#8217;s</a> Crypto Index ETF, which tracks BTC and ETH, although it is not market cap-weighted.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Furthermore, Brazilian asset manager Hashdex filed to launch a similar product in June, as the Hashdex Nasdaq Crypto Index US ETF would track BTC and ETH. </span></p>
<h2><span style="font-weight: 400;">Different use cases</span></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">CryptoSlate</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> data, as of Nov. 26, BTC and ETH collectively had a market cap of over $2.1 trillion. Despite their dominance, investors usually perceive the two crypto use cases differently. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investors primarily regard Bitcoin as a digital store of value optimized for security and monetary use cases. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, ETH powers the Ethereum blockchain, the largest decentralized ecosystem for applications, boasting nearly $110 billion in total value locked (TVL) as per DefiLlama</span> <a href="https://defillama.com/chain/Ethereum"><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>data</strong>.</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Additionally, traditional finance giants like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/blackrock/">BlackRock</a>, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/visa/">Visa</a>, and Franklin Templeton chose the infrastructure to launch their products.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/nyse-files-to-list-bitwises-bitcoin-and-ethereum-mixed-etp/">NYSE files to list Bitwise&#8217;s Bitcoin and Ethereum mixed ETP</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/nyse-files-to-list-bitwises-bitcoin-and-ethereum-mixed-etp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/image_2022-04-07_142739543.png" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/image_2022-04-07_142739543.png" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dogecoin gains ground in Nordics with first-ever ETP introduction</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/dogecoin-gains-ground-in-nordics-with-first-ever-etp-introduction/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/dogecoin-gains-ground-in-nordics-with-first-ever-etp-introduction/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 15:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dogecoin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>DeFi Technologies, a publicly traded Canadian firm, has announced the launch of its subsidiary Valour Inc.&#8217;s new product—the Valour Dogecoin (DOGE) ETP—on the Sweden-based Spotlight Stock Market, according to a Nov. 26 statement. This marks the first Dogecoin ETP in the Nordics, giving investors a secure and simplified way to gain exposure to the popular [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dogecoin-gains-ground-in-nordics-with-first-ever-etp-introduction/">Dogecoin gains ground in Nordics with first-ever ETP introduction</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/defi-technologies-amplifies-bitcoin-holdings-adds-solana-to-treasury/">DeFi Technologies</a>, a publicly traded Canadian firm, has announced the launch of its subsidiary Valour Inc.&#8217;s new product—the Valour <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/dogecoin/">Dogecoin</a> (DOGE) ETP—on the Sweden-based Spotlight Stock Market, according to a Nov. 26 statement.</p>
<p>This marks the first Dogecoin ETP in the Nordics, giving investors a secure and simplified way to gain exposure to the popular digital asset.</p>
<p>The Valour Dogecoin (DOGE) SEK ETP is designed to eliminate the complexities of directly owning digital assets. The fund charges a management fee of 1.9% while providing a cost-effective and streamlined way for investors to participate in the growing crypto market.</p>
<p>Johanna Belitz, Head of Nordics at Valour, highlighted the launch&#8217;s importance, stating that the increasing demand for Dogecoin aligns with the company&#8217;s mission to provide timely access to high-demand digital assets. She added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The growing popularity of Dogecoin, bolstered by influential figures like Elon Musk, highlights our commitment to delivering innovative and diversified investment opportunities in the Nordics.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Meanwhile, the Dogecoin ETP reflects a more significant trend of institutional interest in making digital assets more accessible to investors. Since the introduction of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-etfs-drop-435-million-after-3-3-billion-inflow-streak/">Bitcoin and Ethereum ETFs</a> in the US, traditional financial institutions have diversified their offerings to include assets like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/solana/">Solana</a> and XRP.</p>
<p>Additionally, Dogecoin has <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dogecoin-soars-38-as-renewed-interest-propels-it-multi-year-high/">gained traction among institutions</a>, exemplified by Spirit Blockchain Capital&#8217;s acquisition of Dogecoin Holdings. This move indicates plans to develop new financial products to expand the meme coin&#8217;s utility and adoption.</p>
<h2>DOGE price</h2>
<p>This launch coincides with heightened activity in the crypto market.</p>
<p>Dogecoin recently surged to a three-year high<span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">, buoyed by Bitcoin&#8217;s rally near the $100,000 mark. </span><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">However, according to <em>CryptoSlate&#8217;s</em> data, DOGE has retraced by 11% to $0.3731 as of press time</span>.</p>
<p>Despite this dip, Dogecoin remains a focal point in the crypto ecosystem due to its unique cultural significance and consistent promotion by influential supporters like tech billionaire <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/elon-musk/">Elon Musk.</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/dogecoin-gains-ground-in-nordics-with-first-ever-etp-introduction/">Dogecoin gains ground in Nordics with first-ever ETP introduction</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/dogecoin-gains-ground-in-nordics-with-first-ever-etp-introduction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/dogecoin-nordic.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/dogecoin-nordic.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WisdomTree latest to eye spot XRP ETF amid heightened market optimism</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-latest-to-eye-spot-xrp-etf-amid-heightened-market-optimism/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-latest-to-eye-spot-xrp-etf-amid-heightened-market-optimism/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 18:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Price Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TradFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Asset manager WisdomTree has filed for a trust entity in Delaware, a preliminary step toward launching an exchange-traded fund (ETF) focused on XRP. If approved, the ETF would track XRP&#8217;s price, expanding institutional investors&#8217; access to digital assets. The filing aligns with a broader trend of crypto-focused ETFs reshaping investment opportunities. XRP reacted positively to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-latest-to-eye-spot-xrp-etf-amid-heightened-market-optimism/">WisdomTree latest to eye spot XRP ETF amid heightened market optimism</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Asset manager <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/wisdomtree/">WisdomTree</a> has <a href="https://icis.corp.delaware.gov/eCorp/EntitySearch/NameSearch.aspx">filed</a> for a trust entity in Delaware, a preliminary step toward launching an exchange-traded fund (ETF) focused on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/xrp/">XRP</a>.</p>
<p>If approved, the ETF would track XRP&#8217;s price, expanding institutional investors&#8217; access to digital assets. The filing aligns with a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/21shares-files-s-1-application-for-an-xrp-etf/">broader trend of crypto-focused ETFs</a> reshaping investment opportunities.</p>
<p>XRP reacted positively to the news and was up almost 7% over the past 24 hours to $1.47 as of press time. It has been one of the best-performing assets in the top 10 cryptocurrencies by market cap for the day, retaining almost all of its recent gains despite a wider market dip.</p>
<h2>Regulatory uncertainty</h2>
<p>XRP&#8217;s journey to becoming an ETF-backed asset faces significant legal and regulatory hurdles.</p>
<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/ripple/">Ripple Labs</a>, the issuer of XRP, remains embroiled in a legal dispute with the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), which alleges XRP was sold as an unregistered security.</p>
<p>While Ripple scored a partial legal victory in 2023 — securing a ruling that retail XRP sales did not violate securities laws — the SEC appealed, keeping regulatory uncertainty in play.</p>
<p>Ripple CEO <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/people/brad-garlinghouse/">Brad Garlinghouse</a> expressed optimism about XRP ETFs despite these challenges, pointing to strong demand. He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Since Bitcoin ETFs launched earlier this year, billions have flowed into these funds, highlighting institutional appetite.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The recent resignation of SEC chair Gary Gensler following President Donald Trump&#8217;s victory in the US elections has heightened optimism in the market that the new administration will likely end the constrictive regulatory uncertainty that has stifled the industry&#8217;s growth in the US.</p>
<h2>Expanding crypto ETF landscape</h2>
<p>WisdomTree, which oversees $113 billion in assets, joins firms like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bitwise/">Bitwise</a> and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/canary-capital/">Canary Capital</a> in seeking approval for XRP ETFs.</p>
<p>WisdomTree&#8217;s filing adds to a <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bitwise-registers-solana-trust-signalling-future-sec-application-for-sol-spot-etf/">growing list of crypto ETF proposals</a> as the market diversifies. Last week, Bitwise submitted an application for a Solana ETF, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/21shares/">21Shares</a> recently proposed the 21Shares Core XRP Trust for listing on the Cboe BZX Exchange.</p>
<p>Analysts believe these filings reflect a strategic push to meet institutional demand while awaiting clearer regulatory frameworks.</p>
<p>The ETF Store President Nate Geraci said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The move demonstrates foresight amid evolving crypto adoption.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>As crypto gains traction in mainstream finance, ETFs offer a bridge for institutional investors to access digital assets. The launch of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> ETFs earlier this year marked a pivotal moment, with <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/insights/bitcoin-etfs-record-1-billion-inflows-in-2-days-as-new-price-peak-boosts-investments/">significant inflows</a> highlighting the appeal of these products.</p>
<p>However, the approval of XRP ETFs remains contingent on resolving Ripple&#8217;s legal challenges. Until then, the broader market continues to navigate a complex regulatory environment, with firms like WisdomTree positioning themselves for future opportunities.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-latest-to-eye-spot-xrp-etf-amid-heightened-market-optimism/">WisdomTree latest to eye spot XRP ETF amid heightened market optimism</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/wisdomtree-latest-to-eye-spot-xrp-etf-amid-heightened-market-optimism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/ripple-amm.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/ripple-amm.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>VanEck extends zero-fee waiver for HODL Bitcoin ETF to $2.5 billion or 2026</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-extends-zero-fee-waiver-for-hodl-bitcoin-etf-to-2-5-billion-or-2026/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-extends-zero-fee-waiver-for-hodl-bitcoin-etf-to-2-5-billion-or-2026/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bitcoin ETF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VanEck]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>VanEck has extended the fee waiver for its HODL spot Bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) to the first $2.5 billion in assets or until Jan. 10, 2026, according to a Nov. 25 statement. Under the terms, investors will not pay any fees for HODL until the $2.5 billion threshold is reached or until Jan. 10, 2026—whichever [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-extends-zero-fee-waiver-for-hodl-bitcoin-etf-to-2-5-billion-or-2026/">VanEck extends zero-fee waiver for HODL Bitcoin ETF to $2.5 billion or 2026</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/vaneck/">VanEck</a> has extended the fee waiver for its <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/vaneck-bitcoin-trust/">HODL</a> spot <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a> exchange-traded fund (ETF) to the first $2.5 billion in assets or until Jan. 10, 2026, according to a Nov. 25 <a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241125981896/en/VanEck-Extends-Fee-Waiver-for-HODL-VanEck-Bitcoin-ETF-the-Only-Zero-Fee*-Option">statement</a>.</p>
<p>Under the terms, investors will not pay any fees for HODL until the $2.5 billion threshold is reached or until Jan. 10, 2026—whichever comes first. This marks a significant extension from the previous fee waiver deadline of March 31, 2025, based on the $1.5 billion asset cap. According to Farside&#8217;s data, HODL&#8217;s net asset value is approximately $1.33 billion, reflecting a 124% increase since its inception.</p>
<p>Once the $2.5 billion or January 2026 threshold is reached, investors will be subjected to a 0.20% sponsor fee. In the meantime, HODL remains the only zero-fee spot Bitcoin ETF available in the US.</p>
<p>Kyle USruz, VanEck&#8217;s Director of Digital Assets Product, said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;January 10 marks the anniversary of the SEC’s approval of the first US-listed spot bitcoin exchange-traded products—a watershed moment that we at VanEck had been working towards for close to a decade. It seems fitting to honor that milestone and extend the fee waiver on HODL with that date in mind.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h2>Record inflows</h2>
<p>VanEck&#8217;s move comes amid the continued strong investor interest in Bitcoin ETFs despite their launch over 11 months ago.</p>
<p><a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-210-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-1e294c6b2c70">Data</a> from CoinShares shows that spot Bitcoin ETFs saw record weekly inflows of $3.13 billion, pushing total inflows since mid-September to $15.2 billion. Year-to-date, inflows into crypto-related ETPs have reached $37 billion, primarily driven by inflows into Bitcoin.</p>
<p>According to CoinShares, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-climbs-to-top-1-in-record-breaking-211-days/">BlackRock&#8217;s iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT)</a> dominates the flow, with a year-to-date flow of $33.15 billion, followed by <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/fidelity-wise-origin-bitcoin-trust/">Fidelity&#8217;s Wise Origin Bitcoin Fund (FBTC)</a> with flows of $11.5 billion.</p>
<p>Conversely, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/products/grayscale-bitcoin-trust/">Grayscale&#8217;s Bitcoin Trust (GBTC)</a> experienced net outflows of more than $20 billion during the same period.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, these ETFs&#8217; cumulative performance far surpasses that of US Gold ETUS, which garnered just $309 million in their debut year.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-extends-zero-fee-waiver-for-hodl-bitcoin-etf-to-2-5-billion-or-2026/">VanEck extends zero-fee waiver for HODL Bitcoin ETF to $2.5 billion or 2026</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/vaneck-extends-zero-fee-waiver-for-hodl-bitcoin-etf-to-2-5-billion-or-2026/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/vaneck-bitcoin-etf.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/vaneck-bitcoin-etf.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
