<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>CBDCs News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<atom:link href="https://cryptoslate.com/cbdcs/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cbdcs/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News and Real-time Coin Data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/cropped-cryptoslate-transparent-icon-256x256-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>CBDCs News | CryptoSlate</title>
	<link>https://cryptoslate.com/cbdcs/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Missouri Senate introduces bill to disqualify CBDCs as legal tender</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Liam 'Akiba' Wright]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 12:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Legal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Missouri Senate introduced SB 194 on Dec. 1, proposing to ban central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) as legal tender within the state. The bill seeks to prohibit public entities from accepting or using CBDCs and modifies the definition of &#8220;money&#8221; under the Uniform Commercial Code to exclude these digital currencies. Sponsored by Senator Brattin, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/">Missouri Senate introduces bill to disqualify CBDCs as legal tender</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Missouri Senate <a href="https://trackbill.com/bill/missouri-senate-bill-194-creates-and-modifies-provisions-relating-to-legal-tender/2573895/">introduced</a> SB 194 on Dec. 1, proposing to ban central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) as legal tender within the state. The bill seeks to prohibit public entities from accepting or using CBDCs and modifies the definition of &#8220;money&#8221; under the Uniform Commercial Code to exclude these digital currencies.</p>
<p>Sponsored by Senator Brattin, SB 194 outlines several provisions affecting Missouri&#8217;s financial policies, including the requirement for the State Treasurer to hold gold and silver reserves equal to at least 1% of all state funds. Further, it also reduces tax liability for gold and silver as it</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;exempts from state income tax the portion of capital gain on the sale or exchange of gold and silver that are otherwise included in the taxpayer&#8217;s federal adjusted gross income.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In addition to addressing precious metals, the bill explicitly prohibits public entities from participating in any tests or pilot programs related to CBDCs conducted by the Federal Reserve or other federal agencies. This stance reflects growing concerns among some state legislators about the implications of CBDCs on financial privacy, monetary policy, and state sovereignty.</p>
<p>The modification of the Uniform Commercial Code&#8217;s definition of &#8220;money&#8221; to exclude CBDCs is a notable legal shift. This change could have significant implications for commercial transactions, contracts, and financial instruments within Missouri, effectively limiting the legal recognition and enforceability of CBDC-based transactions.</p>
<p>Earlier in 2024, Missouri&#8217;s legislature considered related <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-passes-crypto-mining-protection-law/">measures</a> regarding digital currencies. House Bill 2780, introduced in February, sought to prevent public entities from accepting or using CBDCs and passed the House in April with substantial support. The Senate also reviewed companion legislation, such as SB 1352, indicating a sustained legislative focus on regulating digital currencies at the state level.</p>
<p>Missouri&#8217;s legislative actions occur amid broader national and global discussions on the adoption and regulation of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-carolina-stands-firm-against-cbdcs-overrides-governors-veto/">CBDCs</a>. While some view CBDCs as an evolution in digital payment systems with the potential to enhance efficiency and financial inclusion, others express concerns over centralized control, privacy issues, and impacts on traditional banking systems.</p>
<p>By introducing SB 194, Missouri positions itself among states actively scrutinizing the role of government-issued digital currencies in their economies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/">Missouri Senate introduces bill to disqualify CBDCs as legal tender</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/missouri-senate-introduces-bill-to-disqualify-cbdcs-as-legal-tender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/missouri-cbdc.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/missouri-cbdc.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>ECB unveils second report on digital euro, announces prototype testing for 2025</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 22:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=455580</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The European Central Bank (ECB) has unveiled its second progress report on developing the digital euro central bank digital currency (CBDC), outlining advancements in the preparation phase and mentioning a prototype for 2025.  In the report, the ECB reaffirms its commitment to providing a secure and efficient digital payment solution that complements cash while safeguarding [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/">ECB unveils second report on digital euro, announces prototype testing for 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The European Central Bank (ECB) has unveiled its</span> <strong><a href="https://www.ecb.europa.eu/euro/digital_euro/progress/html/ecb.deprp202412.en.html">second progress report</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> on developing the digital euro central bank digital currency (CBDC), outlining advancements in the preparation phase and mentioning a prototype for 2025. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In the report, the ECB reaffirms its commitment to providing a secure and efficient digital payment solution that complements cash while safeguarding monetary stability. Additionally, the digital euro is seen as a way to ensure the future competitiveness of the Eurozone&#8217;s financial system.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The digital euro aims to support the European Union&#8217;s digital economy by providing a reliable digital payment method that could be widely accepted by consumers, businesses, and governments across the region.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Key findings on digital euro</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ECB&#8217;s progress report focused on two primary areas: technical and legal considerations, and the ongoing public consultation process. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Over the past year, the ECB has made significant strides in addressing the technical aspects of the digital euro, including improvements in infrastructure, security features, and integration with existing payment systems.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The ECB has also been working closely with stakeholders, including financial institutions, academics, and policymakers, to ensure that the digital euro can seamlessly incorporate into the current monetary and economic frameworks.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The report highlighted the importance of ensuring privacy protection and compliance with European Union regulations, such as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), in designing the digital euro.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Additionally, the document provides an update on the ongoing public consultation, which has garnered significant interest from citizens, businesses, and institutions. The ECB received feedback on a wide range of issues, including how the digital euro could improve payment efficiency, the potential risks to financial stability, and concerns around privacy and cybersecurity.</span></p>
<h2>Outlook</h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The consultation results are expected to play a crucial role in shaping the next phase of the digital euro project. The ECB emphasized that the public&#8217;s input will be vital in determining the final design and implementation of the digital euro.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Looking ahead, the ECB is focused on preparing for the next phase of the digital euro project, which will involve more detailed design work and pilot testing. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The central bank plans to begin testing prototypes of the digital euro in 2025. Depending on the outcome of the ongoing research and development phase, the currency could be launched in the following years.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">While the ECB has not set a definitive timeline for the launch, it remains committed to ensuring that the digital euro is introduced in a way that supports the stability and security of the European financial system.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/">ECB unveils second report on digital euro, announces prototype testing for 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/ecb-unveils-second-report-on-digital-euro-announces-prototype-testing-for-2025/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/ecb-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/ecb-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Irani central bank eyes CBDC, fintech progress to combat sanctions</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/irani-central-bank-eyes-cbdc-fintech-progress-to-combat-sanctions/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/irani-central-bank-eyes-cbdc-fintech-progress-to-combat-sanctions/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Iran&#8217;s Central Bank is preparing to launch its own central bank digital currency (CBDC), called the Digital Rial, to modernize its banking infrastructure and enhance financial operations, according to local media reports. Central Bank Governor Mohammad Reza Farzin revealed the plans on Nov. 25 at the 11th Annual Conference on Modern Banking and Payment Systems. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/irani-central-bank-eyes-cbdc-fintech-progress-to-combat-sanctions/">Irani central bank eyes CBDC, fintech progress to combat sanctions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Iran&#8217;s Central Bank is preparing to launch its own central bank digital currency (CBDC), called the Digital Rial, to modernize its banking infrastructure and enhance financial operations, according to local media <a href="https://www.tasnimnews.com/en/news/2024/11/25/3206932/iran-central-bank-governor-announces-imminent-launch-of-digital-rial">reports</a>.</p>
<p>Central Bank Governor Mohammad Reza Farzin revealed the plans on Nov. 25 at the 11th Annual Conference on Modern Banking and Payment Systems.</p>
<h2>Modernized banking vision</h2>
<p>The Digital Rial is set to leverage Iran&#8217;s advanced digital banking infrastructure, particularly the Shetab payment network, which processes transactions in under two seconds.</p>
<p>The currency aims to enhance the efficiency of domestic and international transactions, reducing operational delays and costs. It represents a key component of Iran&#8217;s broader push to digitize its financial systems, ensuring compatibility with the evolving global financial ecosystem.</p>
<p>Farzin described the Digital Rial as a key step toward positioning Iran as a leader in modern banking within the region. The currency&#8217;s introduction is part of a broader effort to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/russia-proposes-digital-asset-investment-platform-for-developing-markets/">integrate Iran&#8217;s financial systems</a> with international networks while strengthening its resilience against external pressures.</p>
<p>He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Our vision is to adapt, innovate, and collaborate globally, ensuring Iran’s banking system remains at the forefront of digital advancements.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The initiative also signals a commitment to bolstering the country&#8217;s economic resilience. With sanctions restricting access to conventional international banking platforms, such as SWIFT, the Digital Rial is seen as a strategic tool for securing financial autonomy while promoting innovation within Iran&#8217;s financial sector.</p>
<h2>Regional integration and international collaboration</h2>
<p>Farzin also highlighted that Iran’s Central Bank has implemented alternative solutions, such as the ACU-MIR platform, to address the impact of sanctions. Operational since October, the system facilitates regional trade by bypassing SWIFT, enabling transactions with key partners such as India and Pakistan.</p>
<p>These efforts are part of a broader strategy to <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bis-cuts-ties-with-controversial-cbdc-project-mbridge-citing-project-maturity/">deepen financial ties with BRICS economies</a>, which are expanding the use of local currencies to reduce dependence on traditional global financial networks.</p>
<p>Iran has also advanced regional connectivity by linking its Shetab network with Russia&#8217;s MIR payment system. This collaboration allows cross-border transactions and supports tourism, with Russian tourists expected to use Iran&#8217;s point-of-sale systems this winter. Iranian travelers will gain similar access in Russia by early 2025, showcasing the practical benefits of these integrations.</p>
<p>The rollout of the Digital Rial represents a pivotal moment for Iran&#8217;s banking sector. It highlights the nation&#8217;s efforts to foster innovation, strengthen economic resilience, and enhance its role in the regional and global financial landscape.</p>
<p>By prioritizing digital currency and alternative systems, Iran seeks to redefine its financial operations and adapt to ongoing global shifts in banking practices.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/irani-central-bank-eyes-cbdc-fintech-progress-to-combat-sanctions/">Irani central bank eyes CBDC, fintech progress to combat sanctions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/irani-central-bank-eyes-cbdc-fintech-progress-to-combat-sanctions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/iran-.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/iran-.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indian central bank in ‘no hurry&#8217; to rollout CBDC nationwide</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 21:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Banking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=454023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is adopting a cautious approach to the nationwide rollout of its Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC), the e-rupee, prioritizing financial stability and a thorough understanding of its potential impacts. Deputy Governor T. Rabi Sankar emphasized that the bank is &#8220;in no hurry to roll it out immediately,&#8221; indicating a [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/">Indian central bank in ‘no hurry&#8217; to rollout CBDC nationwide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) is adopting a cautious approach to the nationwide rollout of its Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC), the e-rupee, prioritizing financial stability and a thorough understanding of its potential impacts.</p>
<p>Deputy Governor T. Rabi Sankar emphasized that the bank is &#8220;in no hurry to roll it out immediately,&#8221; indicating a deliberate strategy to assess outcomes before broader implementation, Bloomberg News <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-20/india-expanding-payment-links-with-more-countries-rbi-says">reported</a> on Nov. 20.</p>
<h2>Evaluating long-term impact</h2>
<p>The e-rupee pilot, launched in December 2022, has made steady but modest progress, amassing over 5 million users and facilitating roughly 1 million retail transactions by mid-2024. Despite these numbers, Sankar highlighted the importance of e<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/csao-region-becomes-global-crypto-hub-with-india-singapore-and-indonesia-leading-the-charge-chainalysis/">valuating the long-term impac</a>t before scaling up.</p>
<p>He said during a conference in Cebu, Philippines:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Once we have clarity on the outcomes and potential effects, we will take the next steps.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The Reserve Bank&#8217;s deliberate approach reflects concerns about how CBDCs could disrupt traditional banking. Deputy Governor Michael Debabrata Patra previously noted that CBDCs might attract depositors during financial instability, posing risks to banks by encouraging mass withdrawals.</p>
<p>To mitigate such challenges, the central bank has limited its CBDC rollout to controlled experiments. Local banks participating in the pilot, such as ICICI Bank and State Bank of India, have introduced incentives like salary disbursements via e-rupee to encourage adoption.</p>
<p>Despite the reservations, regulators in the country have previously stated that <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/india-favors-cbdcs-over-crypto-like-bitcoin-despite-top-rank-in-global-adoption/">they prefer a nationwide CBDC</a> over private digital currencies like <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/bitcoin/">Bitcoin</a>.</p>
<h2>Evolving features</h2>
<p>India is also enhancing the e-rupee&#8217;s functionality, including developing offline transfer capabilities to boost accessibility. Governor Shaktikanta Das acknowledged, however, that adoption remains far from the levels achieved by the Unified Payments Interface (UPI), India&#8217;s leading digital payments platform.</p>
<p>The wholesale e-rupee program has focused on interbank transactions and government securities trading, with nine major financial institutions participating. These trials aim to refine the currency’s operational design and identify key use cases.</p>
<p>India’s approach mirrors the global trajectory of CBDC development. According to the Atlantic Council, over 130 nations are actively exploring digital currencies, with countries like China and Nigeria already advancing their CBDC programs.</p>
<p>As India observes international developments, its central bank remains committed to ensuring that the e-rupee strengthens the financial system without compromising stability.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/">Indian central bank in ‘no hurry&#8217; to rollout CBDC nationwide</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/indian-central-bank-in-no-hurry-to-rollout-cbdc-nationwide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/india-cbdc.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/india-cbdc.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brazil advances CBDC technology with new cross-chain pilot using Chainlink&#8217;s CCIP</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-advances-cbdc-technology-with-new-cross-chain-pilot-using-chainlinks-ccip/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-advances-cbdc-technology-with-new-cross-chain-pilot-using-chainlinks-ccip/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oluwapelumi Adejumo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 01:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CCIP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chainlink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DREX]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=453731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Central Bank of Brazil (BCB) is advancing its central bank digital currency (CBDC) framework initiative by collaborating with Banco Inter, Microsoft Brazil, 7COMm, and Chainlink, according to a Nov. 19 statement. The partnership aims to support trade finance solutions in the second phase of Brazil&#8217;s DREX pilot program. This phase will focus on automating [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-advances-cbdc-technology-with-new-cross-chain-pilot-using-chainlinks-ccip/">Brazil advances CBDC technology with new cross-chain pilot using Chainlink&#8217;s CCIP</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Central Bank of Brazil (BCB) is advancing its central bank digital currency (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/qatar-central-bank-launches-first-phase-of-cbdc/">CBDC</a>) framework initiative by collaborating with Banco Inter, <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/microsoft/">Microsoft</a> Brazil, 7COMm, and <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/coins/chainlink/">Chainlink</a>, according to a Nov. 19 statement.</p>
<p>The partnership aims to support trade finance solutions in the second phase of <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-to-launch-cbdc-drex-in-2024-said-to-improve-financial-accessibility-amid-centralization-concerns/">Brazil&#8217;s DREX</a> pilot program. This phase will focus on automating cross-border settlements for commodity transactions using blockchain technology and oracles.</p>
<h2>Chainlink&#8217;s role</h2>
<p>The test leverages Chainlink&#8217;s Cross-Chain Interoperability Protocol (<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/chainlink-ccip-powers-lidos-new-cross-chain-staking-on-arbitrum-base-and-optimism/">CCIP</a>) to enable seamless interactions between Brazil&#8217;s DREX platform and foreign central banks.</p>
<p>The initiative will tokenize an Electronic Bill of Lading (eBOL) and integrate supply chain data to automate payments. This data-driven approach will ensure that exporters are paid at various stages of the shipping process.</p>
<p>The pilot intends to showcase how blockchain-based trade finance enables Delivery versus Payment (DvP) and Payment versus Payment (PvP). These mechanisms aim to improve efficiency, security, and transparency in the global supply chain, particularly agricultural commodities.</p>
<p>Banco Inter is leading the implementation of the DREX platform in Brazil, while Microsoft Brazil and 7COMm will provide cloud services and technical support. Chainlink&#8217;s CCIP infrastructure will facilitate cross-chain transfers for DREX and other CBDCs.</p>
<h2>Improving market access</h2>
<p>Bruno Grossi, head of emerging technologies at Banco Inter, highlighted the project&#8217;s potential to expand market access and strengthen Brazil&#8217;s economic landscape.</p>
<p>Similarly, Microsoft Brazil said its role in DREX is to broaden access to intelligent financial services and play a key role in the development of the nation&#8217;s economy.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Angela Walker, the Global Head of Banking and Capital Markets at Chainlink Labs noted that the pilot would transform trade finance by showcasing how tokenized assets can unlock new CBDC applications in Brazil.</p>
<p>She added:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Chainlink CCIP is essential to enabling secure cross-border, cross-currency, and cross-chain transactions and will help showcase what tokenized assets can do at scale for this key CBDC use case in <span class="xn-location">Brazil</span>.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-advances-cbdc-technology-with-new-cross-chain-pilot-using-chainlinks-ccip/">Brazil advances CBDC technology with new cross-chain pilot using Chainlink&#8217;s CCIP</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/brazil-advances-cbdc-technology-with-new-cross-chain-pilot-using-chainlinks-ccip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/brazil-cbdc.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/brazil-cbdc.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fed Governor Waller questions CBDC utility for payments</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/fed-governor-waller-questions-cbdc-utility-for-payments/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/fed-governor-waller-questions-cbdc-utility-for-payments/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Gino Matos]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 21:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=452707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Federal Reserve Governor Christopher Waller recently expressed skepticism about the need for a central bank digital currency (CBDC) in the US payment system Waller made the comments during a speech at The Clearing House Annual Conference 2024 on Nov. 12, where he questioned whether the system has a problem that CBDCs could solve. He stated: [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fed-governor-waller-questions-cbdc-utility-for-payments/">Fed Governor Waller questions CBDC utility for payments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Federal Reserve Governor Christopher Waller recently</span> <strong><a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/newsevents/speech/waller20241112a.htm">expressed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> skepticism about the need for a central bank digital currency (CBDC) in the US payment system</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Waller made the comments during a speech at The Clearing House Annual Conference 2024 on Nov. 12, where he questioned whether the system has a problem that CBDCs could solve. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He stated:</span></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>“In a speech I gave in August 2021, I asked, what problem would a CBDC solve? In other words, what market failure or inefficiency demands this specific intervention? In more than three years, I have yet to hear a satisfactory answer as applied to CBDC.”</strong></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Waller advocated for market-driven solutions, highlighting the private sector&#8217;s benefits in fostering payment system innovation through competition. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He emphasized that the private sector, motivated by profit and competition, often makes better decisions when determining which technologies are worth investing in and which may fail to meet consumer needs. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">He further stated that until a clear need is identified that the private sector cannot meet, the government&#8217;s role should remain supportive rather than directly competitive with private innovation in payments.</span></p>
<h2><strong>Anti-CBDC efforts</strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">US lawmakers hold similar views as Waller and have generally opposed the idea of establishing a CBDC, primarily due to concerns around privacy and financial freedom.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The US House of Representatives</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/congress-passes-bill-banning-federal-reserve-from-creating-a-cbdc/">passed</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> the CBDC Anti-Surveillance State Act in May, preventing Federal Reserve banks from issuing digital currencies without Congress&#8217;s approval.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Patrick McHenry, the chairman of the House Financial Services Committee, supported the Act, officially known as H.R. 5403. He voiced his concerns about CBDCs being a tool for financial surveillance, mentioning China as an example.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The state of Louisiana has also pushed anti-CBDC legislation, with Governor Jeff Landry</span> <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/louisiana-signs-bill-to-ban-cbdcs-protect-right-to-self-custody-and-mine-crypto/">signing</a></strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> HB 488 in June to prohibit the creation of a state digital currency and prevent authorities from engaging with CBDC-related trials by the Fed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Meanwhile, North Carolina&#8217;s state lawmakers <strong><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/north-carolina-stands-firm-against-cbdcs-overrides-governors-veto/">overturned</a> </strong>Governor Roy Cooper&#8217;s veto of a bill preventing the state from implementing a CBDC in September.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/fed-governor-waller-questions-cbdc-utility-for-payments/">Fed Governor Waller questions CBDC utility for payments</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/fed-governor-waller-questions-cbdc-utility-for-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/feds-balance-sheet.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/feds-balance-sheet.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BIS cuts ties with controversial CBDC project mBridge, citing project maturity</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/bis-cuts-ties-with-controversial-cbdc-project-mbridge-citing-project-maturity/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/bis-cuts-ties-with-controversial-cbdc-project-mbridge-citing-project-maturity/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=451232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Bank for International Settlements (BIS) announced its departure from Project mBridge, a central bank digital currency (CBDC) initiative developed in partnership with the People&#8217;s Bank of China and the central banks of Hong Kong, Thailand, Saudi Arabia, and the UAE. The project, designed to simplify cross-border payments through CBDCs, has raised concerns over potential [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bis-cuts-ties-with-controversial-cbdc-project-mbridge-citing-project-maturity/">BIS cuts ties with controversial CBDC project mBridge, citing project maturity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://cryptoslate.com/companies/bank-for-international-settlements/">The Bank for International Settlements</a> (BIS) announced its departure from Project mBridge, a central bank digital currency (CBDC) initiative developed in partnership with the People&#8217;s Bank of China and the central banks of Hong Kong, Thailand, Saudi Arabia, and the UAE.</p>
<p>The project, designed to simplify cross-border payments through CBDCs, has raised concerns over potential misuse by certain nations to evade international sanctions, according to a recent Bloomberg News <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-31/bis-steps-back-from-cross-border-payment-project-touted-by-putin?leadSource=uverify%20wall">report</a>.</p>
<p>BIS General Manager Agustín Carstens confirmed the organization&#8217;s withdrawal in an Oct. 31 speech, emphasizing that the decision to leave was not politically driven.</p>
<p>Carstens characterized the exit as a &#8220;graduation&#8221; for the project, indicating that Project mBridge had r<a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-monetary-authority-announces-success-and-key-findings-from-cbdc-project-mbridge/">eached a level of maturity</a> where the BIS&#8217; involvement was no longer essential.</p>
<p>He said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We have contributed four years to this effort, and it has matured to the point where our partners can sustain it independently.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Carstens added that the BIS often steps back from initiatives once they achieve operational stability. However, recent political developments have added layers of complexity to the BIS&#8217;s departure.</p>
<h2>Concerns about sanctions</h2>
<p>In an address last month, Russian President Vladimir Putin mentioned Project mBridge&#8217;s underlying technology as a potential tool to circumvent Western financial sanctions, raising global concerns over the platform&#8217;s usage.</p>
<p>While Putin&#8217;s remarks didn&#8217;t specify intentions, they fueled speculation that mBridge could serve as a pathway for BRICS nations to bypass dollar-based restrictions in international trade.</p>
<p>The BIS, a global organization fostering international monetary and financial cooperation, remains dedicated to compliance with international standards and has sought to distance itself from any association with sanction violations.</p>
<p>Addressing the speculation, Carstens clarified that Project mBridge was not intended as a &#8220;BRICS bridge&#8221; or a tool to undermine global sanctions. He explained that the platform is still in its development stages and was built to streamline payment processes rather than to challenge existing financial structures.</p>
<p>He further stated that although mBridge has developed to a point where the BIS can step back, it remains &#8220;many years away&#8221; from operational readiness.</p>
<h2>&#8216;Finternet&#8217;</h2>
<p>Despite concluding its involvement in mBridge, the BIS continues to pursue broader digital finance initiatives, including its vision for a &#8220;Finternet.&#8221;  This conceptual framework seeks to create an interconnected global financial system with improved accessibility, reduced transaction costs, and increased regulatory alignment.</p>
<p>Carstens described the Finternet as resting on three main pillars: robust financial architecture, advanced technology, and solid regulatory foundations. The goal is to use tokenized assets and programmable money to automate and streamline transactions, providing a resilient infrastructure in an increasingly digital financial world.</p>
<p>The BIS is also advancing Project Agorá through its Innovation Hub. This initiative aims to integrate tokenized central bank and commercial bank money on unified ledgers, which could address inefficiencies in cross-border payments.</p>
<p>By focusing on interoperability and regulatory cohesion, Project Agorá highlights the BIS’ belief that while technology is critical, sustainable reform in global finance requires a foundational structure aligning public and private sector goals.</p>
<p>Carstens reiterated the BIS&#8217; commitment to fostering compliance and security in its projects. While the BIS continues to support innovative financial tools, Carstens noted that the true future of finance is about reshaping systems to meet the needs of a digital-first world where central and commercial banks collaborate to provide accessible and secure financial solutions.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/bis-cuts-ties-with-controversial-cbdc-project-mbridge-citing-project-maturity/">BIS cuts ties with controversial CBDC project mBridge, citing project maturity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/bis-cuts-ties-with-controversial-cbdc-project-mbridge-citing-project-maturity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bis.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bis.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HKMA partners up with Brazilian central bank to test cross-border tokenization</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/hkma-partners-up-with-brazilian-central-bank-to-test-cross-border-tokenization/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/hkma-partners-up-with-brazilian-central-bank-to-test-cross-border-tokenization/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 22:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=450453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) announced a new partnership with Banco Central do Brasil (BCB) to advance cross-border tokenization initiatives, joining their respective digital currency infrastructures to conduct experimental transactions under Project Ensemble and Brazil&#8217;s Drex pilot program. The HKMA and BCB are exploring cross-border settlement models, focusing on payment-versus-payment (PvP) and delivery-versus-payment (DvP) [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hkma-partners-up-with-brazilian-central-bank-to-test-cross-border-tokenization/">HKMA partners up with Brazilian central bank to test cross-border tokenization</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) announced a new partnership with Banco Central do Brasil (BCB) to advance cross-border tokenization initiatives, joining their respective digital currency infrastructures to conduct <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-targets-global-fintech-leadership-with-new-virtual-asset-strategies/">experimental transactions</a> under Project Ensemble and Brazil&#8217;s Drex pilot program.</p>
<p>The HKMA and BCB are exploring cross-border settlement models, focusing on payment-versus-payment (PvP) and delivery-versus-payment (DvP) systems applicable to trade finance and carbon credits. The partnership utilizes HKMA&#8217;s Ensemble Sandbox and BCB&#8217;s Drex platform to test these settlement scenarios across a range of financial use cases.</p>
<h2>Project Ensemble and Drex</h2>
<p>The HKMA launched Project Ensemble in 2023 to evaluate tokenized assets and their potential to improve various financial services. This Sandbox initiative, unveiled in August, builds on HKMA’s long-standing interest in distributed ledger technology (DLT) as a way to optimize payments and settlements.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kongs-project-ensemble-sandbox-explores-future-of-tokenized-finance/">Ensemble Sandbox</a> focuses on four primary areas: fixed income and investment funds, liquidity management, green finance, and trade and supply chain finance, each focused on reducing the costs and delays traditionally associated with cross-border payments.</p>
<p>Named Drex, the Brazilian CBDC aims to integrate seamlessly with financial services providers to offer real-time settlement solutions. Currently involving over 70 companies, Drex has moved through multiple phases, covering 13 key themes ranging from e-commerce payments to real estate transactions, all geared toward advancing Brazil’s financial ecosystem through tokenization.</p>
<p>BCB&#8217;s Drex pilot program, announced earlier this year, represents Brazil&#8217;s ambitions for digital currency. It creates the infrastructure for a tokenized financial market backed by a central bank digital currency (CBDC).</p>
<h2>Legacy of cooperation</h2>
<p>HKMA and BCB&#8217;s partnership builds on a 2018 agreement to foster innovation in financial services between their jurisdictions. Both institutions have consistently worked to shape the international regulatory landscape for digital currencies and tokenized assets.</p>
<p>HKMA&#8217;s active role in the Bank for International Settlements&#8217; (BIS) Project mBridge also highlights its commitment to cross-border CBDC projects. Project mBridge, which involves central banks from multiple regions, including the People&#8217;s Bank of China, has conducted trials for cross-border payments using a shared DLT platform, bringing promising results in reducing the friction often seen in foreign exchange settlements.</p>
<p>The HKMA and BCB’s collaboration reflects a global shift toward asset tokenization, with major economies exploring similar solutions to improve market transparency, regulatory compliance, and efficiency.</p>
<p>Many central banks see tokenization as a way to securely represent ownership rights in real assets—ranging from carbon credits to real estate—while reducing intermediaries in cross-border transactions.</p>
<p>The HKMA&#8217;s Sandbox and BCB&#8217;s Drex provide structured environments to evaluate these possibilities and solve common challenges, such as regulatory alignment and technical compatibility, which are essential for global adoption.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hkma-partners-up-with-brazilian-central-bank-to-test-cross-border-tokenization/">HKMA partners up with Brazilian central bank to test cross-border tokenization</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/hkma-partners-up-with-brazilian-central-bank-to-test-cross-border-tokenization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/hongkong-flag.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/hongkong-flag.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK central bank leader reassures cash&#8217;s place with rising Britcoin</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/uk-central-bank-leader-reassures-cashs-place-with-rising-britcoin/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/uk-central-bank-leader-reassures-cashs-place-with-rising-britcoin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Monika Ghosh]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 01:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=450255</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Amid growing fears that Britcoin, the UK&#8217;s central bank digital currency (CBDC), is going to supplant cash, Bank of England (BOE) governor Andrew Bailey said that the central bank will continue to supply cash &#8220;for as long as people want.&#8221; Bailey was speaking at the Group of Thirty’s 39th Annual International Banking Seminar. According to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/uk-central-bank-leader-reassures-cashs-place-with-rising-britcoin/">UK central bank leader reassures cash&#8217;s place with rising Britcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amid growing fears that Britcoin, the UK&#8217;s central bank digital currency (CBDC), is going to supplant cash, Bank of England (BOE) governor Andrew Bailey said that the central bank will continue to supply cash &#8220;for as long as people want.&#8221; Bailey was speaking at the Group of Thirty’s 39th Annual International Banking Seminar.</p>
<p>According to Bloomberg, Bailey <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-10-26/britcoin-will-not-replace-cash-boe-governor-bailey-says?srnd=phx-crypto">noted</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“The evidence is they do want it [cash], so we will continue to supply it.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Baileys words were a reiteration of what Sarah Breeden, a Bank of England veteran, said at a questioning by the Treasury Committee last year. She had said:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;We will ensure that cash is available as long as it is demanded. We will ensure that the cash infrastructure in the financial system is there as long as it is demanded – cash and digital money are choices.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Ever since the idea of the CBDC was first introduced years ago, lawmakers and citizens alike have been <a href="https://www.electronicpaymentsinternational.com/business/britcoin-uk-privacy-instability-2/">divided</a> over its benefits and pitfalls. Those who support Britcoin <a href="https://www.theregister.com/2023/09/18/digital_pound_treasury_committee/">believe</a> that it has the capacity to reduce costs and risks. Those opposed, however, are concerned that it could give the government the power to surveil people&#8217;s expenditures and replace cash.</p>
<p>The BOE <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-01-25/britain-starts-design-work-on-a-digital-version-of-the-pound">started</a> working on the design for a digital version of the pound in January this year. However, the BOE has still not decided whether it is actually going to launch it. Bailey said that he supports a wholesale CBDC for banks but is more cautious about releasing a retail CBDC.</p>
<p>He added that it was “harder to see an anchor role for central bank money” when it came to retail CBDC. However, a wholesale CBDC can play a “special role” for “central bank money in wholesale high value payments and in settlement of payment systems.”</p>
<p class="media-ui-Paragraph_text-SqIsdNjh0t0- paywall" data-component="paragraph">Bailey further added that the BOE is building a retail CBDC for innovation purposes. Bailey believes that the CBDC innovation should be available to the private sector and it will ensure that commercial banks modernize the digital payments system.</p>
<p data-component="paragraph">According to Bailey, banks lack the incentive to increase efficiency in certain fields, like cross-border payments, which &#8220;inhibits innovation.&#8221; Therefore, there is a need for better digital systems in the “area of cross-border payments, where progress on modernization continues to be slow,” Bailey said. “There is no good reason to be proprietorial on this.”</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/uk-central-bank-leader-reassures-cashs-place-with-rising-britcoin/">UK central bank leader reassures cash&#8217;s place with rising Britcoin</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/uk-central-bank-leader-reassures-cashs-place-with-rising-britcoin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andrew-bailey-england.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/andrew-bailey-england.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hong Kong targets global fintech leadership with new virtual asset strategies</title>
		<link>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-targets-global-fintech-leadership-with-new-virtual-asset-strategies/</link>
					<comments>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-targets-global-fintech-leadership-with-new-virtual-asset-strategies/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Assad Jafri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 19:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CBDCs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://cryptoslate.com/?p=449781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong is sharpening its focus on virtual asset trading and digital financial systems, local media reported on Oct. 23, citing Financial Secretary for Services and the Treasury Christopher Hui. Speaking at the Asia-Pacific Fintech Innovation Lab 2024, Hui emphasized that these areas are central to positioning Hong Kong as a global leader in virtual [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-targets-global-fintech-leadership-with-new-virtual-asset-strategies/">Hong Kong targets global fintech leadership with new virtual asset strategies</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hong Kong is sharpening its focus on virtual asset trading and digital financial systems, local media <a href="https://finance.mingpao.com/fin/instantf/20241023/1729661539076/%e8%a8%b1%e6%ad%a3%e5%ae%87-%e9%87%8d%e9%bb%9e%e9%97%9c%e6%b3%a8%e5%a4%ae%e8%a1%8c%e6%95%b8%e7%a2%bc%e8%b2%a8%e5%b9%a3-%e7%a7%bb%e5%8b%95%e6%94%af%e4%bb%98%e5%8f%8a%e8%99%9b%e6%93%ac%e8%b3%87%e7%94%a2%e4%ba%a4%e6%98%93%e7%ad%89%e9%a0%98%e5%9f%9f">reported</a> on Oct. 23, citing Financial Secretary for Services and the Treasury Christopher Hui.</p>
<p>Speaking at the Asia-Pacific Fintech Innovation Lab 2024, Hui emphasized that these areas are central to positioning Hong Kong as a global leader in virtual asset development.</p>
<p>As part of a broader push for digital finance, Hui emphasized the potential of central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) and virtual asset trading to reshape Hong Kong&#8217;s financial landscape. He said the government is accelerating efforts to integrate these technologies, providing secure and efficient payment systems that could enhance both local and regional markets.</p>
<p>Hui&#8217;s comments come as Hong Kong <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-set-to-expand-crypto-licensing-by-year-end-amid-push-to-become-digital-asset-hub/">ramps up</a> its licensing framework for crypto exchanges. The Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) has already <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hkvax-becomes-third-crypto-exchange-licensed-in-hong-kong/">granted its third</a> crypto trading platform license under new regulatory standards, following earlier approvals for OSL and HashKey.</p>
<p>Currently, 11 other platforms are undergoing the review process, aiming to secure licenses that would allow them to serve retail investors under the city&#8217;s updated crypto trading regime.</p>
<p>The licensing framework, first implemented in June 2023, is seen as a cornerstone of Hong Kong&#8217;s effort to become a hub for virtual assets. It offers exchanges a pathway to operate under stringent regulatory oversight, ensuring greater protection for retail investors.</p>
<p>Despite the progress, some local firms have criticized the regulatory environment as being overly stringent, leading several companies to withdraw their applications. The balance between regulatory rigor and innovation remains a challenge for Hong Kong, but its focus on licensing and compliance signals a long-term strategy to attract institutional and retail investors.</p>
<p>Hong Kong&#8217;s focus on regulatory innovation, coupled with its push to integrate digital assets into mainstream financial systems, positions the city as a leader in the global race for fintech dominance. Its continued efforts in virtual asset trading and crypto regulation are expected to solidify its role as a premier destination for fintech innovation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-targets-global-fintech-leadership-with-new-virtual-asset-strategies/">Hong Kong targets global fintech leadership with new virtual asset strategies</a> appeared first on <a href="https://cryptoslate.com">CryptoSlate</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://cryptoslate.com/hong-kong-targets-global-fintech-leadership-with-new-virtual-asset-strategies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/hongkong-flag.jpg" medium="image"/>
<enclosure url="https://cryptoslate.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/hongkong-flag.jpg" length="1200" type="image/jpg"/>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
